<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mental health on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mental health on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recovery Conversation Cafes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-conversation-cafes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-conversation-cafes/</guid>
      <description>INT: The Minister for Mental Wellbeing and Social Care, Kevin Stewart, officially launched a Recovery Conversation Café Toolkit for organisations and services. Developed by the Scottish Recovery Network, the toolkit provides a guide and resources to help people engage in meaningful discussions about what is important to them and their communities. We spoke to Ann Jones, Manager of the Mental Health Network at Greater Glasgow and Clyde about the Cafés; what they are, how they work, and what they achieve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care experience and mental health</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-experience-and-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-experience-and-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TB - Thomas Bartlett
CA - Casey Armstrong
MD The following conversation was recorded by Thomas Bartlett and Casey Armstrong, two care experienced young people who talk openly about the subject of mental health as part of a project titled, &amp;lsquo;Mental health and care experienced children and young people: a partnership for change&amp;rsquo;.
The project seeks to improve understanding and practice in relation to care experienced young people&amp;rsquo;s mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Michael Byrne: Lived Experience Trauma Support (LETS)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/michael-byrne-lived-experience-trauma-support-lets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 08:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/michael-byrne-lived-experience-trauma-support-lets/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
MB - Michael Byrne
MM On this podcast I&amp;rsquo;m going to be speaking to the founder and MD at Lived Experience Trauma Support for mental health, Michael Byrne. He is going to be speaking about his new venture and he is going to be speaking about his own experience about mental health.
A health warning. This episode describes scenes from traumatic events that listeners may find disturbing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write to Recovery - four years on</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery-four-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery-four-years-on/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
EC - Erin Crombie
JM - John McCormack
A - Audrey
D - Dorothea
MD - You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. &amp;ldquo;Write to Recovery&amp;rdquo; is celebrating four years this year. Erin Crombie, Group Work Facilitator, and John McCormack, Project Manager, from the Scottish Recovery Network give an update on the project four years on.
EC The project originally started out as a story-sharing tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jo McFarlane&#39;s journey to recovery</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/jo-mcfarlanes-journey-to-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/jo-mcfarlanes-journey-to-recovery/</guid>
      <description>JM - Jo McFarlane
Building the future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Workers, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See Me</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/see-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/see-me/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
NJ - Nick Jedrzejewski
MG - Maeve Grindall
MM I went into the See Me office, and See Me is a mental health charity, and on this podcast I interviewed the Communications Manager, Nick Jedrzejewski, and also I interviewed Maeve Grindall. Now Maeve Grindall is part of the Social Movement team at See Me Scotland. So tell me, what does your job involve?
NJ My job involves promoting See Me, promoting the message that we have of tackling stigma and discrimination and helping people to live fulfilled lives, and doing that in a variety of different mediums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scottish Mental Health Arts Festival</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-festival/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RW - Richard Warden
MM Ok, now at Iriss.fm we are going to be hearing about this year&amp;rsquo;s Scottish Mental Health Arts and Film festival and we are joined by Richard warden, who is in the film league and is going to tell us more about the whole festival. So, Richard, thanks for joining us.
RW My pleasure.
MM So, why is it important to have this festival?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alzheimer Scotland: Annual Conference and Dementia Awards</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-annual-conference-and-dementia-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-annual-conference-and-dementia-awards/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KW - Kirsty Wilson
Iriss.fm recently spoke to Kirsty Wilson from Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland about two upcoming events in 2017. Their annual conference and the Dementia awards. She also tells us about some of the exciting work being undertaken by Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland this year.
KW Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland&amp;rsquo;s main aim is to make sure that no one goes through dementia on their own, so that&amp;rsquo;s our main aim in everything that we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bipolar Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bipolar-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bipolar-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AK - Alison Kermes
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking to Alison Kermes, now Alison is the Chief Executive and the Company Secretary for a Scottish Mental Health charity called Bipolar Scotland so thanks Alison for giving up your time. Now the first question I really want to ask is what is bipolar?
AK Bipolar is a serious mental illness, it affects 2 to 3% of the population and the symptoms include mood swings&amp;hellip;extreme mood swings from, you know, serious depression to mania, psychosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From strength to strength</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/from-strength-to-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/from-strength-to-strength/</guid>
      <description>LP - Lisa Pattoni
JM - John Moody
DD - David Delaney
DR - Deborah Reid
In 2012, Iriss undertook a project focused on understanding how an assets based approach could improve mental health and wellbeing within East Dunbartonshire, focussing specifically on Kirkintilloch. East Dunbartonshire Association of Mental Health is now in the process of integrating personal asset mapping into WRAP - Wellness Recovery Action Plan. Iriss caught up with the team in East Dunbartonshire to discuss how the idea came about to integrate personal asset mapping into WRAP, what has happened, the feedback, learning outcomes and next steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Adventures with dementia - Neil Mapes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
NP - Neil Mapes
DM Well it&amp;rsquo;s now my pleasure to introduce Neil Mapes who&amp;rsquo;s the Chief Executive of Dementia Adventure. Now Neil is the founder and co-director of Dementia Adventure, which is an awarding winning community interest company and charity, which specialises in supporting people with dementia and their families, to have adventure experiences. Neil will share his own thoughts about how we traditionally respond to those diagnosed with dementia and the barriers we need to overcome if we are to help those with dementia and their family enjoy their lives to the full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Back in the driving seat - James McKillop</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-back-in-the-driving-seat-james-mckillop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-back-in-the-driving-seat-james-mckillop/</guid>
      <description>NM - Neil Mapes
JM - James McKillop
NM So we have got the great pleasure in introducing Dr James McKillop MBE. We have had the great pleasure in supporting James for the last 5 years or so and James is a man who likes photography and outdoor activities and is a strong family man as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you will hear but he is also a founding member of the Scottish Dementia Working Group and former Chair and since 1999 has had vascular dementia and has been part of an amazing array of initiatives and projects both Nationally and Internationally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acumen: giving mental health service users and carers a voice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/acumen-giving-mental-health-service-users-and-carers-a-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/acumen-giving-mental-health-service-users-and-carers-a-voice/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
PV - Pauline Vance
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we are joined by Pauline Vance. Pauline is a Development Worker for Acumen. Acumen is a Mental Health charity. Thanks Pauline for giving up your time and speaking to us. First of all, what can you tell us what is ACUMEN?
PV Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what it stands for first of all. It stands for Advancing Community Understanding of Mental and Emotional Needs, which is a very long thing to stand for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery Across Mental Health (RAMH)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-across-mental-health-ramh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-across-mental-health-ramh/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KM - Karen Milne
Recovery Across Mental Health (formerly Renfrewshire Association for Mental Health) is an independent voluntary sector organisation that aims to enable people to recover from mental ill health and to promote wellbeing. This year RAMH is celebrating 25 years of providing support. Michael McEwan speaks to Karen Milne who tells us more about the organisation and launch of the celebrations.
MM Okay, now we are joined by Karen Milne from RAMH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose Shoes?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/whose-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/whose-shoes/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GP - Gill Phillips
KH - Ken Howard
DH - Dorothy Hall
MB - Marion Brown
MD In this episode, Michelle Drumm from Iriss has a conversation with Gill Phillips, the creator of Whose Shoes? And Ken Howard, a media ambassador for people with dementia, who were up in Scotland from the 20th to the 24th of October to attend the European Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Conference and to also run Whose Shoes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Dementia Awareness Month 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
YS - Yvonne Stewart
AMMD - Anne Marie MacDonald
AL - Anne Love
RB - Rosalyn Barclay
AMMG - Ann-Marie McGregor
MD September is World Dementia Awareness Month, and to mark it, Iriss.fm met up with the directors of Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training and a group of carers and professionals in the area of dementia care. We firstly spoke to Yvonne Stewart and Anne Marie MacDonald about Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write to recovery</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LG - Linda Gillard
RR - Robin Ross
AC - Ashley Campbell
JC - Jim Campbell
SN - Sandy Nisbet
SB - Simon Bradstreet
JM - John McCormack
MD Write to Recovery, a website designed to support people affected by mental health problems on their journeys of recovery, was launched on the 11th of June 2014 at the Scottish Storytelling Centre in Edinburgh. The launch forms part of the Scottish Recovery Networks 10-year anniversary celebrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scottish Mental Health Arts and Film Festival 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-and-film-festival-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-and-film-festival-2013/</guid>
      <description>HT - Heidi Tweedie
KW - Keith Walker
LK - Lee Knifton
RW - Richard Warden
DS - Douglas T Stuart
CE - Chris Evans
RH - Roger Hutchison
CS - Chris Salt
CM - Carrie Marshall
JH - Jackie Hodges
HT Hello and welcome to the Highland Festival event roundup 2013, a programme exploring this years Scottish Mental Health Arts and Film Festival Highland contribution.
I am Heidi Tweedie, Highland Festival Publicity Coordinator and Producer of the National Festival Podcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Excellence in Dementia Education Conference</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/promoting-excellence-dementia-education-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/promoting-excellence-dementia-education-conference/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
HS - Henry Simmons
PM - Peter McLaughlin
MR - Mairead Rae
PM - Pamela Mackay
MD The Promoting Excellence in Dementia Education conference was held on the 18th of September 2013 at the Stirling Management Centre. Iriss.fm attended to capture some of the presentations and to get a flavour of the workshops. Henry Simmons, Chief Executive of Alzheimer Scotland, opened the conference and was subject to the Second Dementia Strategy for Scotland, he speaks about achievements in dementia care to date and some of the challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery 2020: A vision achieved? SRN 5th national gathering</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-2020-a-vision-achieved-srn-5th-national-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-2020-a-vision-achieved-srn-5th-national-gathering/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SB - Simon Bradstreet
RP - Rachel Perkins
JM - John McCormack
LC - Louise Christie
JG - Jenny Graydon
ED - Elinor Dowson
SS - Susan Scott
MD On 18th March 2013, Iriss.fm attended the 5th Scottish Recovery Network Gathering on the theme of &amp;lsquo;Recovery 2020: A Vision Achieved?&amp;rsquo; It featured a number of speakers from various mental health disciplines, each of who presented using the very upbeat and visual Pecha Kucha format comprising 20 images and 20 seconds per image to get the point across.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SASW MHO of the Year Award: Liz Snodgrass</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sasw-mho-of-the-year-award-liz-snodgrass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sasw-mho-of-the-year-award-liz-snodgrass/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LS - Liz Snodgrass
MD Liz Snodgrass from Renfrewshire Council became the first winner of the Scottish Association of Social Works&amp;rsquo; Mental Health Officer of the Year Award in memory of Wilma MacDonald, a highly respected Mental Health Officer from the east end of Glasgow who died in 2009.
On 2nd November 2012, Liz agreed to speak to Iriss.fm about the significance of winning the award and was also willing to answer some other questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring bipolar disorder through theatre</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/exploring-bipolar-disorder-through-theatre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/exploring-bipolar-disorder-through-theatre/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
VC - Vanessa Coffey
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services.
Introduction The 2012 Scottish Mental Health Arts &amp;amp; Film Festival is underway and Iriss went along to the Centre for Contemporary Arts in Glasgow to see a performance of &amp;lsquo;Piece of Mind&amp;rsquo;, a documentary dance theatre work that brings to live verbatim interviews with 15-25 year olds diagnosed with bipolar. After the performance, Ian Watson talked to Vanessa Coffey who devised the work and is one of the two performers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
