<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Davie Donaldson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/davie-donaldson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Davie Donaldson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/davie-donaldson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The relationship between social work and Gypsy/Traveller communities</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-relationship-between-social-work-and-gypsy-traveller-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-relationship-between-social-work-and-gypsy-traveller-communities/</guid>
      <description>Kerry: Today is about exploring positive engagement with Scotland’s gypsy travellers and the role rural social work has in challenging the othering of these communities. This session is going to be looking at terminology, historical understanding and the relationship between social work and gypsy traveller communities. We’re hoping it’s going to challenge some of the preconceptions around gypsy travellers that exist and it’s going to introduce solution focused approaches to positive engagement and bring in and reflect on the lived experience of the community and look at inclusive practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gypsy, Roma and Traveller history: Davie Donaldson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/gypsy-roma-and-traveller-history-davie-donaldson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 16:05:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/gypsy-roma-and-traveller-history-davie-donaldson/</guid>
      <description>KM - Kerry Musselbrook
DD - Davie Donaldson
KM Today I have with me Davie Donaldson, who identifies as a Scottish traveller from Perthshire. He&amp;rsquo;s a graduate of Aberdeen University, like myself, and is someone with a keen interest in culture and community relations. Davie is a social justice campaigner and is founder of Progress in Dialogue, a social enterprise that advocates dialogue between communities one conversation at a time. So today is a chance to have another one of those conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
