<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iriss on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/iriss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iriss on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/iriss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving community social work upstream</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/moving-community-social-work-upstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/moving-community-social-work-upstream/</guid>
      <description>Michelle: Hello and welcome to the Iriss.fm podcast. I&amp;rsquo;m Michelle, and in this episode we focus on community social work. It was a pleasure to get along to the Community Social Work conference on the 8 November 2022; an opportunity not only to meet people face to face, but also to hear about the new model of community social work in Fife. At the event we spoke to Colin Turbett, social work author and consultant alongside Kathy Henwood, the Chief social work officer of Fife Education and Children&amp;rsquo;s Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENRICH Scotland: supporting research in care homes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/enrich-scotland-supporting-research-in-care-homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/enrich-scotland-supporting-research-in-care-homes/</guid>
      <description>Michelle: Hello and welcome to the Iriss.fm podcast. I&amp;rsquo;m Michelle and in this episode I speak to Emma Law and Susan Shenkin about ENRICH Scotland, a programme of work that supports research in care homes, the results of which improve the lives of people who live in care homes, their families and care home staff. Emma and Susan are the Co-chairs of ENRICH. Emma has worked in the NHS for over 35 years and is the manager for the neuro progressive and dementia research network since June 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Community Teams</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/heart-community-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/heart-community-teams/</guid>
      <description>Michelle: Hi there, welcome to the Iriss.fm podcast. I’m Michelle and in this episode, I speak to Andrew Bryers about Heart Community Teams. Heart is a new wellbeing model of service delivery for children and their families in East Ayrshire. It is an approach in keeping with the principles of human rights based, inclusive service design and delivery.
Andrew has been a social worker since 2007, and has worked in Scotland, London and Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing how homecare is commissioned and delivered</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/changing-how-homecare-is-commissioned-and-delivered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/changing-how-homecare-is-commissioned-and-delivered/</guid>
      <description>Meylis: Hi, I’m Meylis from North Wales. I live here in Gwynedd and I’ve worked in Gwynedd for quite a few years. And currently I’m in a role across health and social care, leading a programme of change called the Community Transformation Programme. And one of the key things I’m working on and have been working on for a long time, is trying to change the way that we commission and deliver home care in Gwynedd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new model of support for independent living</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-new-model-of-support-for-independent-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-new-model-of-support-for-independent-living/</guid>
      <description>Kiana: My name is Kiana, Kiana Kalantar-Hormozi. I’m an artist, filmmaker and activist, and up until now I’m proud to have had many achievements. I’ve been nominated one of the 30, under-30, most inspirational women in Scotland in 2017 and MDUK Campaigner of the Year in 2018.
After graduating my short protest hip-hop film called ‘Tax On Me’ has been viewed by tens of thousands of people in Scotland, raising a parliamentary motion on the issue of Care Tax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Inspectorate: using digital devices in care homes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-inspectorate-using-digital-devices-in-care-homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-inspectorate-using-digital-devices-in-care-homes/</guid>
      <description>INT: Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care (TEC) Programme over Autumn/Winter 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services.
Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid Quality Improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work, and has developed a Learning Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Me in social services: keeping the QI conversation going</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-keeping-the-qi-conversation-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-keeping-the-qi-conversation-going/</guid>
      <description>INT: Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care (TEC) Programme. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services.
Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid Quality Improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work, and has developed a Learning Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrossReach: using Attend Anywhere to provide counselling support</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/crossreach-using-attend-anywhere-to-provide-counselling-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/crossreach-using-attend-anywhere-to-provide-counselling-support/</guid>
      <description>TA - Tanya Anderson
Near Me in social services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish government technology enabled care programme over the autumn winter of 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services. Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid quality improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work; and has developed a learning network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Me in social services: digital inclusion</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-social-services-digital-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-social-services-digital-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>AS - Aaron Slater
Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care Programme over autumn and winter 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services. Iriss has supported 5 services to participate in a rapid quality improvement cycle to start using Near Me, provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work and has also developed a learning network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
