<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transcripts on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transcripts on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Governance in Social Care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/research-governance-in-social-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/research-governance-in-social-care/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IM - Irina McLean
Irina McLean, Project Leader with NHS Research Scotland Management Team, is currently leading the development of a Research Governance Framework (RGF) which will meet the needs of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Care Services employers, staff and service users and their families. The Public Bodies (Joint Working) (Scotland) Act 2014 sets the context for the integration of adult health and social care in Scotland. Underpinning the introduction of the Act was a commitment to ensure the consistent provision of quality, sustainable care services for the increasing numbers of people in Scotland who need joined-up support and care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIDD 2019 Conference</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/iassidd-2019-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/iassidd-2019-conference/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM On this podcast we hear about a World Congress coming to Glasgow called the IASSSID Congress, from 6-9 August. So, I went to interview Linda Mitchell, Linda works for the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities and is on the local organising committee for the congress. So, Linda can you give us an overview of the whole event?
LM I can Michael. So, the IASSIDD World Congress happens every 3 years and IASSIDD stands for the International Association for the Scientific Study of Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed Jackie Irvine</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JI - Jackie Irvine
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Jackie Irvine. Jackie is currently Chief Social Work Officer and Head of Safer and Stronger Communities in the City of Edinburgh Council. Jackie was appointed as the president of Social Work Scotland in May of 2018 and her tenure as President comes to an end in May 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterbaby Arts</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/waterbaby-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/waterbaby-arts/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RF - Ruth Foster
MG - Maureen Graham
SG - Sandy Graham
MM On this episode on Iriss.fm we hear about an arts organisation called Waterbaby Arts and we&amp;rsquo;re going to be hearing from two of the dancers that take part. It&amp;rsquo;s Maureen Graham and Sandy Graham but first up we&amp;rsquo;re going to speak to Ruth Foster, Ruth Foster is the tutor of (&amp;hellip; unclear) Dance baby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: David Williams</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-david-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 12:00:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-david-williams/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DW - David Williams
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to David Williams. David qualified as a social worker in 1988 and worked for 2 years in Easterhouse and then for 7 years in Drumchapel as a social worker and senior social worker. He moved to the children&amp;rsquo;s charity NCH in 1997 as Service Manager to set up and bring in a range of integrated children and family services in the Moray Council area until 2004.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duty of Candour</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/duty-of-candour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/duty-of-candour/</guid>
      <description>SM - Stuart Muirhead
JW - Jackie Weston
AK - Alison Kirsty
LG - Lisa Greenan
LK - Linda Kemp
SM Hello and welcome to our discussion around the duty of candour, my name is Stuart Muirhead and I&amp;rsquo;m a project manager in Iriss. The thinking for this discussion came from being out about in the social services sector, over the last year and getting the feeling that the duty of candour provisions were something that were either well known, or known of and also something that was possibly causing some anxiety or confusion, either that or they weren&amp;rsquo;t on people&amp;rsquo;s radar at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving Miss Daisy</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/driving-miss-daisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/driving-miss-daisy/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AO - Ann Overdijking
CM - Christine McIntyre
MM On this podcast, we hear about a new service: a service called Driving Miss Daisy. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be hearing from Ann Overdijking and Christine McIntyre, who will tell us more. So, Ann can you tell us about Driving Miss Daisy?
AO Yes, I&amp;rsquo;d love to Michael, thank you. Well Driving Miss Daisy, it&amp;rsquo;s a driving and companion service and we offer a safe, very friendly and reliable driving service and people say, &amp;ldquo;What is it you actually do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Ben Farrugia</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ben-farrugia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ben-farrugia/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
BF - Ben Farrugia
Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Ben Farrugia, Director of Social Work Scotland. Ben grew up in London and Dorset and studied modern history and political science in Birmingham followed by a Masters in Political Sociology at the London School of Economics and Political Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Security Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-security-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-security-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RM - Rachael McKechnie
MM On this next podcast, I went to find out more about the all new Social Security Scotland where I was talking to Rachael McKechnie and first off, I asked her: what is Social Security Scotland?
RM Thank you Michael so, Social Security Scotland is the organisation that&amp;rsquo;s been established to deliver a subset of benefits that are being moved from the UK government up to the Scottish government so, those benefits are largely for people with disabilities so, the things like personal independence payment, disability living allowance, the carers, so, carers allowance is coming up and then another smaller number of benefits that are there to support people who are on a low income that need a bit of help to meet additional cost so, that&amp;rsquo;s things like the Sure Start Maternity Grant, DWP&amp;rsquo;s funeral payment and cold weather payments and winter fuel payments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support: a radical policy?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-a-radical-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-a-radical-policy/</guid>
      <description>SM - Stuart Muirhead
CP - Charlotte Pearson
NW - Nick Watson
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On the 21st of February 2019 Dr Charlotte Pearson and Professor Nick Watson spoke to Stuart Muirhead from Iriss about their research on Self-Directed Support in Scotland and whether it&amp;rsquo;s brought about the transformational change it set out to achieve.
SM Hello and welcome to our latest Iriss fm episode. My name is Stuart Muirhead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generations Working Together</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/generations-working-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/generations-working-together/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KS - Kate Samuels
KM - Keith Mitchell
NS - Natalie Stewart
CC - Charlotte Craig
On 8th February 2019 Michelle from Iriss had a conversation with Kate Samuels from Generations Working Together about the work it does to promote and support intergenerational practice. She also chatted to Keith Mitchell and Natalie Stewart from Glasgow&amp;rsquo;s Golden Generation and Charlotte Craig, from Impact Arts, about their intergenerational work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People-led Policy Panel</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-led-policy-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-led-policy-panel/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DH - Deirdre Henderson
DS - Denis Shovlin
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On 7th February 2019 Deirdre Henderson, People-led Policy Officer at Inclusion Scotland, and Denis Shovlin, a member of the People-led Policy Panel, spoke to Michelle from Iriss about the setup, aims and ambitions of the People-led Policy Panel, a group of people who are working together to reform adult social care in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week launch</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-launch/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LC = Libby Clement
MM On this episode of Iriss.fm I went to find out about this year&amp;rsquo;s Learning Disability Week, the launch of Learning Disability Week was held at Project Ability in Glasgow and the National Learning Disability Week takes place from Monday the 13th to Sunday the 19th of May 2019. On this podcast I spoke to the winner of the British Bake Off, James Morton and also one of the award nominees from the learning disability awards last year, Jonathon McKendry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disability Equality Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-equality-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-equality-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
IB - Ian Buchanan
Michael McEwan speaks to Ian Buchanan about Disability Equality Scotland, focusing more specifically on Disability Access Panels. As the umbrella body for Access Panels in Scotland, Disability Equality Scotland offers support and training opportunities to help Access Panels operate efficiently, link together as a network and learn from each other.
MM We are now joined by Ian Buchanan, who is the Access Engagement Officer at Disability Equality Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outspoken Arts</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outspoken-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outspoken-arts/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
ST - Steven Thomson
Michael McEwan speaks to Steven Thomson, Creative Director and CEO of Outspoken Arts, a professional and creative organisation interested in work which references cutting edge social issues such as creative learning for young and vulnerable people, stories of migration and asylum, issues affecting LGBT people, disability, ethnicity, creative ageing and social health and well-being. The organisation represents diverse communities and recognises that equality, equal and human rights are now very much the focus of mainstream society, civic and organisational culture and its shifting sense of identity plays an increasingly influential role in this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-production Week 2018</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/co-production-week-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/co-production-week-2018/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SJ - Sam Jordan
K - Kieran
A - Abbie
Co-production Week (#CoProWeekScot) was held from the 19-25 November 2018 and provided an opportunity to learn, discuss and celebrate how co-production puts people and communities at the heart of the support and services they&amp;rsquo;re part of. Michelle from Iriss.fm spoke to Sam Jordan from the Scottish Community Development Centre (SCDC) about what Co-production Week is and some of the activities that took place over the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Lynn Williams</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lynn-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lynn-williams/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LW - Lynn Williams
MD Hello welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influences in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Lynn Williams, an unpaid carer providing practical care and support to her husband Derek. Derek has a high-level spinal injury and other linked complex needs. Lynn is on the board of Engender a National Women&amp;rsquo;s organisation and on the board of her local carers centre, she also works on a part time basis in Health and Social Care policy with Glasgow Centre for Voluntary services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year of Young People</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/year-of-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/year-of-young-people/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KD - Kevin Ditcham
CS - Cameron Smith
MM On this episode of Iriss.fm we are going to hear about the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo;. 2018 is the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo; here in Scotland, and I went to speak to one of them, but an Ambassador for this campaign this year is Cameron Smith, but first of all I spoke to the Project Manager for the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo;, Kevin Ditcham, and first of all I asked Kevin to tell us why this year is the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Jennifer Davidson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jennifer-davidson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jennifer-davidson/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JD - Jennifer Davidson
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &amp;lsquo;squeeze&amp;rsquo; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Michelle Drumm interviews Professor Jennifer Davidson, Executive Director of Inspiring Children&amp;rsquo;s Futures at the University of Strathclyde, which incorporates the Centre for Excellence for Looked After Children in Scotland (CELCIS). Inspiring children&amp;rsquo;s futures has a vision of ensuring that children and young people facing aversity have what they need to reach their full potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Families as peer workers in early childhood intervention</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/families-as-peer-workers-in-early-childhood-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/families-as-peer-workers-in-early-childhood-intervention/</guid>
      <description>SM - Sylvana Mahmic
MH - Melanie Hayworth
SM Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Sylvana Mahmic the CEO of Plumtree. I&amp;rsquo;m also mother to Karim who&amp;rsquo;s twenty eight and has a disability and he&amp;rsquo;s been using self-manage funding for the last ten years or so.
MH And I&amp;rsquo;m Dr Melanie Hayworth. I&amp;rsquo;m a Peer Worker at Plumtree Children&amp;rsquo;s Services which is an early childhood intervention service in Australia and I have recently project managed a new project that we did with funding from the Australian Government around how peer work can be used in early childhood intervention, or ECI and the ways that families can be used to make peer work, work for ECI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in social work education</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/women-in-social-work-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/women-in-social-work-education/</guid>
      <description>VC - Viv Cree
MM - Mary Mitchell
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On the 24th of October, Iriss attended &amp;lsquo;Navigating Troubled Waters: Women in Social Work Education in Scotland&amp;rsquo; seminar where we heard from Emeritus Professor Viv Cree and Dr Mary Mitchell about a study funded by the Carnegie UK Trust which began with the realisation that women in the Academy fare less well than men across all disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Mairi O&#39;Keefe</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-mairi-okeefe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-mairi-okeefe/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MO - Mairi O&amp;rsquo;Keefe
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in Social Services in Scotland, today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Mairi O&amp;rsquo;Keefe. Mairi has been the Chief Executive of Leuchie House, national respite centre, based near North Berwick since 2003. The only facility of its kind in Scotland, Leuchie has specialised in providing short respite breaks for people and their families living with MS, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s and other long-term conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared Lives</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/shared-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/shared-lives/</guid>
      <description>LS - Lesley Stevenson
SE - Shona Elvin
AK - Asif Khan
BB - Bill Black
ES - Elaine Stockdale
BH - Ben Hall
LS Today&amp;rsquo;s discussion on Shared Lives in Scotland, we have with us Shona Elvin who is family placement assessor for Cornerstone, we have Asif Khan, who is a Shared Life service user with Quarriers, we have Bill Black, who is a Shared Lives carer for Cornerstone, Elaine Stockdale who is a Shared Lives carer with Shared Lives Moray, Ben Hall, who is Scotland Development Manager for Shared Lives Plus and I&amp;rsquo;m Lesley Stevenson, Scotland Development Officer for Shared Lives Plus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social pedagogy in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MS - Mark Smith
LH - Lotte Harbo
GE - Gabriel Eichsteller
GC - Gemma Campbell
GM - Graham McPheat
MD You&amp;rsquo;re professor of Social Work isn&amp;rsquo;t it up at University of Dundee?
MS Yeah.
MD And from a social work perspective then, what is the significance of social pedagogy really?
MS For me some of the significance is it&amp;rsquo;s link back to some of the earlier ideas of Scottish social work, in particular Kilbrandon&amp;rsquo;s idea of social education and Cole Brandon thought of social education as education in it&amp;rsquo;s widest sense to work with individuals families and communities and if you think of the idea of social pedagogy then that is described as education in it&amp;rsquo;s broadest sense as well so, there are obvious sort of linkages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to Politics</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-to-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-to-politics/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
EY - Ethan Young
MM On this podcast on Iriss.fm I went to hear about a new project called Access to Politics. It is a fund to help people with a disability into the mainstream politics and on this series I spoke to Ethan Young from Inclusion Scotland. Now Ethan is a Civic Participation Officer and I spoke to him about access to politics. So, what is Access to Politics Ethan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Emma Scott</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-emma-scott/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-emma-scott/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
ES - Emma Scott
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I am speaking to Emma Scott. In June of this year Emma won the Bright Spark award at the Scottish Social Services Awards. This award aims to recognise a young person who is excelling in the work they do in the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outside the Box</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outside-the-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outside-the-box/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JK - Jill Keegan
MM On this episode I went to hear about an organisation called Outside the Box, where I was talking to Jill Keegan, who is the Community Development Adviser. The first question I asked her was, tell us a bit about Outside the Box.
JK Outside the Box is a community development support organisation. So, we are an equalities charity and we are based in Glasgow, but we work right across Scotland and now have also some links with England and Wales, with one of the really big projects we run called Rural Wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Social Work: Claire Ferrier</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-claire-ferrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-claire-ferrier/</guid>
      <description>CF - Claire Ferrier
Talking Social Work was an event held on the 13th September 2018 to mark the 50th Anniversary of the Social Work Scotland Act 1968, to celebrate, reflect on the journey so far and look to the future. There were a number of guest speakers. Claire Ferrier newly qualified social worker graduated from the University of Dundee with an MSc in Social Work and has just started her first post as a registered social worker with Perth and Kinross Council working within an adult care team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Social Work: Colin Turbett</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-colin-turbett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-colin-turbett/</guid>
      <description>CT - Colin Turbett
CT Thanks very much folks and it&amp;rsquo;s a privilege to be here at the first of these talking social work sessions and I certainly hope it&amp;rsquo;s something that will continue, it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to see such large numbers interested in something like this. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m here tonight is because a result of a commission from Iriss, I&amp;rsquo;ve written this, now it was a collaborative effort and in a sense the story of this publication which only came off the press yesterday is a bit like the history of community social work which is what I want to talk about tonight and that history over the last fifty years since the 68 Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Social Work: Jane Martin</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-jane-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-jane-martin/</guid>
      <description>JM - Jane Martin
Jane So it&amp;rsquo;s really good to be here and excellent turn out I think we are going to rival the opening for the V &amp;amp; A and I actually didn&amp;rsquo;t realise there was quite so many social workers. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that in Dundee we have a very strong belief in the value of practitioner forum, that&amp;rsquo;s particularly important given the disperse nature of our workforce and when Alan was here as Director of social work, he worked hard to introduce support and embed the approach, but in truth I think like other areas we have struggled to retain the concept, we&amp;rsquo;ve found that our meetings were becoming poorly attended and actually there was a bit of a sense that they were turning into a meeting and greeting session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Hope</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-hope/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KB - Katherine Baxter
EB - Eileen Bray
LS - Liam Slaven
NC - Natalie Connell
MD - You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On the 28th of August 2018 we held a roundtable discussion on &amp;ldquo;Talking Hope&amp;rdquo;, a project exploring to what extent to creating safe conversational spaces amongst diverse stakeholders helps cultivate hope in a context of young people considered to be at high risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write to Recovery - four years on</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery-four-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery-four-years-on/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
EC - Erin Crombie
JM - John McCormack
A - Audrey
D - Dorothea
MD - You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. &amp;ldquo;Write to Recovery&amp;rdquo; is celebrating four years this year. Erin Crombie, Group Work Facilitator, and John McCormack, Project Manager, from the Scottish Recovery Network give an update on the project four years on.
EC The project originally started out as a story-sharing tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Ian Welsh</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ian-welsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ian-welsh/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IW - Ian Welsh
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;ldquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rdquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to professor Ian Welsh OBE. Ian was previously Director of UK Services for the Rehab Group, leading charities working in care, supported employment, rehabilitation and training. In his time as Chief Executive and Board Member of Kilmarnock Football Club he led the club through business and footballing success building a number of innovative community programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Trisha Hall</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-trisha-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-trisha-hall/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TH - Trisha Hall
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencer in social services in Scotland. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Trisha Hall, Trisha was born in the Netherlands and has worked with and for Children and Families for over 40 years. Since coming to Britain from the Netherlands in 1987, Trisha has worked in residential child care in West Yorkshire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Points in East Renfrewshire</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-points-in-east-renfrewshire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-points-in-east-renfrewshire/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GT - Gerry Tougher
MM So, on this next episode for Iriss.fm I went along to East Renfrewshire to hear about a new piece of work called Talking Points and I spoke to Gerry Tougher. Now, Gerry Tougher is a public Engagement Officer of East Renfrewshire. So, can you tell us what is Talking Points?
GT Talking Points really is a new approach that we&amp;rsquo;re taking in East Renfrewshire, essentially Talking Points are places in your community where you can the advice and support you need to help you to do the things you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Donald Macaskill</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-donald-macaskill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-donald-macaskill/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DM - Dr Donald Macaskill
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss Podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Dr Donald Macaskill, Donald has worked for many years in the health and social care sectors across the UK specialising in learning disability and older people&amp;rsquo;s work. A particular professional focus has been issues related to bereavement, palliative care and individual rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Viv Cree</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
VC - Viv Cree
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Viv Cree who is professor of Social work studies at the University of Edinburgh. Viv worked for 16 years as a professional social worker and community worker in both the statutory and voluntary sectors and is an accredited practice teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welfare advisers in health and social care services</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-advisers-in-health-and-social-care-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-advisers-in-health-and-social-care-services/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
KB - Kate Burton
RS - Roddy Samson
KC - Karen Carrick
WA roundtable discussion on the embedding of welfare advisers in health and social care services, as an effective response to the impact of welfare reform. The discussion involved Kate Burton, Public Health Practitioner at Scottish Public Health Network; Roddy Samson, Welfare Advice Service Facilitator at the Improvement Service; and Karen Carrick, Project Manager at the Improvement Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Tommy Whitelaw</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-tommy-whitelaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-tommy-whitelaw/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TW - Tommy Whitelaw
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &amp;lsquo;squeeze&amp;rsquo; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland.
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Services podcast.
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed and Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social service in Scotland, today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Tommy Whitelaw. For 5 years Tommy was a full-time carer for his late mother Joan who had vascular dementia, in 2011 he embarked on a walk around Scotland&amp;rsquo;s towns and cities to collect hundreds of life story letters detailing the experiences of individuals caring for a loved one living with dementia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at Learning Disability Week</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looking-back-at-learning-disability-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looking-back-at-learning-disability-week/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KM - Katie Morris
PO - Paul O&amp;rsquo;Kane
Michael McEwan, our roving reporter on disability issues attended a number of events over Learning Disability Week 2018 (14-20 May) and spoke to the organisers. We hear about &amp;lsquo;Be the Change&amp;rsquo; campaign created by Enable Scotland, Project Ability and Mind the Gap theatre performance organised by the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability (SCLD).
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Services podcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Iona Colvin</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-iona-colvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-iona-colvin/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IC - Iona Colvin
Welcome to the first episode in a new series, Freshly Squeezed, which aims to &amp;lsquo;squeeze&amp;rsquo; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. We hear how and why they are working in social services, what motivates them, and the people, books and music that inspire them. They also offer some golden nuggets of advice. To kick the series off, Michelle Drumm spoke to Iona Colvin, Chief Social Work Adviser for Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the future; shaping our social work identity</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/building-the-future-shaping-our-social-work-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/building-the-future-shaping-our-social-work-identity/</guid>
      <description>MK - Martin Kettle
Building the future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Work, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jo McFarlane&#39;s journey to recovery</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/jo-mcfarlanes-journey-to-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/jo-mcfarlanes-journey-to-recovery/</guid>
      <description>JM - Jo McFarlane
Building the future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Workers, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership and professional identity</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-and-professional-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-and-professional-identity/</guid>
      <description>ST - Susan Taylor
Building the Future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Work, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions of social work education and practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/perceptions-of-social-work-education-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/perceptions-of-social-work-education-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>MK - Martin Kettle
Building the future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Work, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The grand challenge(s) for social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-grand-challenges-for-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-grand-challenges-for-social-work/</guid>
      <description>JD - John Devaney
At the Social Work Scotland AGM 2018, John Devaney, Centenary Chair of Social Work, spoke about social work in Scotland today. He focused on three key themes:
The nature of modern social work and contribution of social workers to civil society
The role of leadership in social work
How to raise or sustain profile of what social work does and its value to wider society.
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2018</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2018/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM On this podcast we hear about this year&amp;rsquo;s Learning Disability week. Learning Disability week takes place between the 14th to the 20th of May and the theme for this years Learning Disability week is My Generation. We went along to the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities to find out more where we spoke to Linda Mitchell. Linda is a partnership and development manager of the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Am Me</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/i-am-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/i-am-me/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DC - Debbie Campbell
Megan - Megan Milligan
MM Now on Iriss.fm I went to I Am Me Scotland to find more about the charity, now I Am Me Scotland is a community partnership charity who is developing in Renfrewshire to raise awareness of a disability hate crime and on this podcast, you&amp;rsquo;ll hear me speaking to Debbie Campbell. Debbie Campbell is the project officer and committee member of I Am Me Scotland, but first up let&amp;rsquo;s hear from Megan Milligan who is the project assistant and she is the secretary from I Am Me Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>See Me</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/see-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/see-me/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
NJ - Nick Jedrzejewski
MG - Maeve Grindall
MM I went into the See Me office, and See Me is a mental health charity, and on this podcast I interviewed the Communications Manager, Nick Jedrzejewski, and also I interviewed Maeve Grindall. Now Maeve Grindall is part of the Social Movement team at See Me Scotland. So tell me, what does your job involve?
NJ My job involves promoting See Me, promoting the message that we have of tackling stigma and discrimination and helping people to live fulfilled lives, and doing that in a variety of different mediums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geetha Marcus</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/geetha-marcus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/geetha-marcus/</guid>
      <description>GM - Geetha Marcus
GM I&amp;rsquo;m Geetha Marcus and I did a study around the experiences of Gypsy Traveller girls in Scottish schools some time ago, and before I started I thought - oh, by the way, Isaac, I hope I fulfil your strong women thing because that&amp;rsquo;s, you know, you can tell me later if I fit the bill! So just a little bit about my journey, who I am and how I ended up here and how I ended up talking about Gypsies and Travellers when I&amp;rsquo;m not myself a Gypsy or a Traveller, although I think there&amp;rsquo;s some sort of a connection through the Indian connection, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d start with myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paisley Disability Resource Centre:2</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre2/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JT - Jim Thompson
DT - Duncan Tomlinson
MM Now on part two of our special series called &amp;ldquo;Inside The Resource Centre&amp;rdquo;, I went along to speak to one of the participants of the group, Duncan Tomlinson, and he takes part in the movie makers group, but first up, we spoke to Jim Thompson. Now Jim Thompson is the co-ordinator for the movie makers and the music group, and he told us more about what happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paisley Disability Resource Centre:1</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre1/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KC - Kevin Cantwell
BN - Billy Neil
B - Brenda
BW - Billy White
MM Okay, now on Iriss.fm we&amp;rsquo;re going to do a series about &amp;ldquo;Inside The Resource Centre&amp;rdquo;. A lot of people have got a stigma about people with a disability going to the Resource Centre. What can they do? What are they capable of? Well, in this series we&amp;rsquo;ll prove you wrong. This is part one of two of &amp;ldquo;Inside The Resource Centre&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation with Evan Rae, a support worker</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/conversation-with-evan-rae-a-support-worker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/conversation-with-evan-rae-a-support-worker/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
ER - Evan Rae
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we&amp;rsquo;re going to be continuing our series on support workers and we are going to be talking to Evan Rae about his work as a support worker. So first off Evan why did you want to get into this kind of work?
ER I think initially it&amp;rsquo;s always something that&amp;rsquo;s been a kind of an interest for me, working with folk who have a learning disability or extra support needs or something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversation with Greg Campbell, a support worker</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/conversation-with-greg-campbell-a-support-worker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/conversation-with-greg-campbell-a-support-worker/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GC - Greg Campbell
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm we are going to be talking to Greg Campbell. Greg Campbell is a support worker. So, Greg, why did you want to get into this kind of work?
GC Well, I have always felt that I have been a very helpful and supportive person. I think that comes a lot from my family and the way I have been brought up, just a very caring and nurtured, supporting environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAssport to Independent Living</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passport-to-independent-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passport-to-independent-living/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LS - Lilian Smith
SL - Sharon Ledger
M - Mandy
L - Lizzie
S - Susan
Y - Yvonne
A - Alison
MD 31st of October 2017 marked the launch of PAssport to Independent Living, a published collection of stories written by Personal Assistants about their experiences of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to work as a Personal Assistant in Scotland, and to raise awareness of self-directed support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Film Club</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-film-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-film-club/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JW - Jodie Wilkinson
MM Now on Iriss.fm we&amp;rsquo;re going to hear about a new project called Access Film Club, and we&amp;rsquo;re joined on Iriss fm by Jodie Wilkinson, the Public Engagement Officer, so thanks for joining us. So, can you tell us a bit about the Access Film Club?
JW Yeah, of course. Access Film Club is a monthly Autism-friendly screening that happens at Glasgow Film Theatre, and we began the journey in November 2014, and at the time we were working with a fantastic organisation called Scottish Autism, who helped us develop the film club into what we see today, and then last year we said goodbye to Scottish Autism and we continued working with the National Autistic Society Scotland, which has enabled us to continue running the monthly screenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scottish Mental Health Arts Festival</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-festival/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RW - Richard Warden
MM Ok, now at Iriss.fm we are going to be hearing about this year&amp;rsquo;s Scottish Mental Health Arts and Film festival and we are joined by Richard warden, who is in the film league and is going to tell us more about the whole festival. So, Richard, thanks for joining us.
RW My pleasure.
MM So, why is it important to have this festival?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restorative justice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/restorative-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/restorative-justice/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
CW - Ciara Webb
Int. Restorative justice is a process of dialogue between two parties. In the context of criminal justice social work this will be a victim or person harmed and an offender, one who has caused harm. Statutory criminal justice social work in Edinburgh is a service aimed to reducing reoffending and protecting the public through evidence based interventions. The development of a restorative justice service for those on statutory orders is a new and progressive approach to tackling reoffending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Care Collective</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-care-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-care-collective/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RG - Ruth Gallagher
LW - Lynn Wardle
CW - Colette Walker
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm we are going to hear about a new project called the Care Collective and we are joined by Ruth Gallagher, from Voluntary Action and we are joined by a carer and someone who has a disability as well, Colette Walker, and we are joined by Lynn Wardle from Thrive. So, we are going to hear about this exciting project, but I wanted to ask as well, first of all, if Ruth can give us a wee overview of what Voluntary Action is and what they provide?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dundee Early Intervention Team</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-dundee-early-intervention-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-dundee-early-intervention-team/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
F - Natalie, Harriet, Jade, Bianca
M - Brian
The Dundee Early Intervention Team (DEIT) provides early intervention support to families.
The team is a partnership of the four leading children&amp;rsquo;s charities in Dundee - Aberlour, Children 1st, Action for Children and Barnardo&amp;rsquo;s Scotland - the team works together with Dundee City Council, NHS Tayside and Dundee Voluntary Action.
Practicing a social pedagogy model, the team work alongside families to build their capacity to tackle challenges and make sustainable change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden disabilities: Joseph Delaney</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-joseph-delaney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-joseph-delaney/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JD - Joseph Delaney
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm on this series of Hidden Disabilities, we are going to be talking to Joseph Delaney. Joseph is on the autistic spectrum and Joseph is going to speak about his ups and downs of his journey. So, thanks Joseph for joining us. The first question, when did you become aware that you might be different?
JD Well when I went to mainstream primary school it was discovered I had a moderate learning disability, but even long before that, when I was in nursery school I had a short concentration span so I could only focus on something for a couple of minutes, then I would be away to something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden disabilities: Ryan Fleming</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-ryan-fleming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-ryan-fleming/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RF - Ryan Fleming
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm, and this series of hidden disabilities, we are going to speak to Ryan Fleming about the barriers and challenges that he faces day to day. First of all, Ryan, going back to when you were younger, what obstacles did you face?
RF Well I faced quite a number of obstacles when I was young, my big one I would say, was when I actually started nursery school because I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it, it was far too much for me, the playing and all that, with other children, just simply did not happen and I don&amp;rsquo;t really think you got much help back then when I started, I mean you are talking the late 1990s here, you didn&amp;rsquo;t really get much support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Between a rock and a hard place</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</guid>
      <description>KM - Kristina Moodie
DN - Debbie Nolan
DA - David
S - Sheila
DU - Duncan
KM Welcome to this special podcast, the Centre for Youth &amp;amp; Criminal Justice are hosting to celebrate the CELCIS 2017 Festival of Residential Childcare. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about how residential childcare workers respond to offending in children&amp;rsquo;s houses. Everyone here, aside from myself and Debbie, works with young people who are looked after, so we really appreciate you all travelling and giving your time to meet with us for this conversation in Glasgow today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure care in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/secure-care-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/secure-care-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>DN - Debbie Nolan
AG - Alison Gough
S - Sharon
D - Deborah
L - Lesley
DN Thanks a lot to everyone for joining us today. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the perceptions and experiences of secure care with myself. My name is Debbie Nolan, I&amp;rsquo;m Practice Development Advisor at the Centre for Youth &amp;amp; Criminal Justice.
AG Alison Gough, I&amp;rsquo;m the Secure Care National Advisor and I&amp;rsquo;m also based at CYCJ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme (AILIP)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/active-and-independent-living-improvement-programme-ailip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/active-and-independent-living-improvement-programme-ailip/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
SM - Sarah Mitchell
SK - Susan Kelso
Sarah Mitchell, programme director for the Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme, and Susan Kelso, AHP Lead for Early Intervention with Scottish Government, spoke to Iriss.fm about the programme and the current Life Curve survey, which they would like AHP&amp;rsquo;s to complete. The Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme, or AILIP, was officially launched on April 26th by Shona Robison, MSP Cabinet Secretary for Health and Sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents with learning disabilities</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/parents-with-learning-disabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/parents-with-learning-disabilities/</guid>
      <description>AMi - Andy Miller
AMu - Amanda Muir
BW - Bianca Wood
DB - David Barr
GM - Gillian McIntrye
KM - Kerry Musselbrook
KM Morning everyone it&amp;rsquo;s Learning Disability Week this week and today we are here to focus ton parents with learning disabilities. Today we are joined by a range of people, so welcome. We have Bianca Wood, People First Scotland, an organisation that works to support people with learning disabilities, to have more choice and control and Bianca is Chairperson of the People First Scotland Parents Group, a self-advocacy group that has been meeting for over ten years now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hate crime: causes, motivations and effective interventions</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hate-crime-causes-motivations-and-effective-interventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hate-crime-causes-motivations-and-effective-interventions/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
RH - Rania Hamad - City of Edinburgh Council
RH First of all, the Scottish Government allotted money for Criminal Justice Social Work to sort of strengthen their community interventions, and Criminal Justice Social Work in Edinburgh decided to use that funding to undertake research into hate crime and the Criminal Justice Social Work response to that and how do we strengthen our interventions when working with offenders and perpetrators - I&amp;rsquo;ll use those terms, they are sometimes a bit value laden but just for ease of reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2017</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2017/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CC - Chris Creegan (Chief Executive - Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities)
MM We are going by Chris Creegan, now Chris Creegan is the Chief Executive of the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities. Thanks for talking to us. First off, what is happening this year? What&amp;rsquo;s the theme?
CC Okay so, just a little bit about the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability, and I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what our role is and then talk to you about the theme for this year, yeah?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/unity-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/unity-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LG - Loretta Galloway
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm we are joined by Loretta Galloway, the Service Manager for the Learning Disability Service here at Unity Enterprise. Now, she has come to tell us a bit about what her own service does, the Learning Disability Services, but first of all can you tell us an overview of what Unity Enterprise is?
LG Unity Enterprise is a social (&amp;hellip;unclear) Scotland down in Ayrshire and Inverclyde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alzheimer Scotland: Annual Conference and Dementia Awards</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-annual-conference-and-dementia-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-annual-conference-and-dementia-awards/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
KW - Kirsty Wilson
Iriss.fm recently spoke to Kirsty Wilson from Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland about two upcoming events in 2017. Their annual conference and the Dementia awards. She also tells us about some of the exciting work being undertaken by Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland this year.
KW Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland&amp;rsquo;s main aim is to make sure that no one goes through dementia on their own, so that&amp;rsquo;s our main aim in everything that we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support survey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-survey/</guid>
      <description>Int. = Interviewer
CM - Cathy McGregor
LG - Lorraine Gillies
On the 21st of February 2017, Iriss.fm spoke to Cathy McGregor and Lorraine Gillies from Audit Scotland about the National Self-Directed Support survey that has recently been circulated. Audit Scotland are keen to get as many responses as possible before the 27th of February; stories positive or negative of people&amp;rsquo;s experiences of Self-Directed Support or experiences of supporting someone to use Self-Directed Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bipolar Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bipolar-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bipolar-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AK - Alison Kermes
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking to Alison Kermes, now Alison is the Chief Executive and the Company Secretary for a Scottish Mental Health charity called Bipolar Scotland so thanks Alison for giving up your time. Now the first question I really want to ask is what is bipolar?
AK Bipolar is a serious mental illness, it affects 2 to 3% of the population and the symptoms include mood swings&amp;hellip;extreme mood swings from, you know, serious depression to mania, psychosis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A watershed for social work in Scotland?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-watershed-for-social-work-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-watershed-for-social-work-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JL - Dr John Lincoln
AB - Audrey Burt
LW - Lynn Williams
SL - Sue Lavery
AB - Alan Baird
On 30th November 2016 the Health and Social Care Alliance, in Partnership with a number of Sector Organisations, including Iriss, posted a seminar entitled A Watershed for Social Work in Scotland. The event brought together people to explore the implications of the Audit Scotland Report on Social Work in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child abuse scandals and online discourse</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-abuse-scandals-and-online-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-abuse-scandals-and-online-discourse/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
DF - Danielle Farrell
On the 15th November 2016 we recorded a discussion for Iriss.fm with Danielle Farrell about her PHD research. Danielle shared with us an overview of the main points of her thesis which was an examination of the 2012 Child Abuse Scandals in the UK. The research focused on the multi-functional nature of on-line discourse surrounding the issue.
DF I carried out my PHD over 4 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glasgow Disability Alliance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/glasgow-disability-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/glasgow-disability-alliance/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
BS - Brian Scott
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm, I&amp;rsquo;m here in the Glasgow Disability Alliance office and I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Brian Scott. Now Brian Scott is the Development Manager for the Alliance so thanks Brian&amp;hellip;
BS - Hi.
Male voice - &amp;hellip;for taking the time out to speak to us. So first of all give us a quick over view and a quick insight into what is Glasgow Disability Alliance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From strength to strength</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/from-strength-to-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/from-strength-to-strength/</guid>
      <description>LP - Lisa Patonni
JM - John Moody
DD - David Delaney
DR - Deborah Reid
In 2012, Iriss undertook a project focused on understanding how an assets based approach could improve mental health and wellbeing within East Dunbartonshire, focussing specifically on Kirkintilloch. East Dunbartonshire Association of Mental Health is now in the process of integrating personal asset mapping into WRAP - Wellness Recovery Action Plan. Iriss caught up with the team in East Dunbartonshire to discuss how the idea came about to integrate personal asset mapping into WRAP, what has happened, the feedback, learning outcomes and next steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you find real lack and real passion?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-do-you-find-real-lack-and-real-passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-do-you-find-real-lack-and-real-passion/</guid>
      <description>RF - Dr Robert French
On 24th October 2016 at the University of Strathclyde in Glasgow, Dr Robert French lead an Iriss workshop exploring how to negotiate a way through the complexities of our managed world, in order to do some of the worthwhile things we feel passionate about. In this talk he includes examples from his own experience of the school education system in England, the Poet John Keats and the text &amp;lsquo;Symposium&amp;rsquo; by the Classical Greek philosopher, Plato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Control Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/in-control-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/in-control-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM Michael McEwan
KE Keith Etherington
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm we are in the In Control Scotland office and we are speaking to Keith Etherington, who is the director of In Control Scotland. So, first of all Keith, can you tell us more information about what is In Control Scotland?
KE Yeh, In Control Scotland is a small independent charity that&amp;rsquo;s been going, been running as an organisation since 2009, been around since 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters/</guid>
      <description>HM - Helen Minnis
DW - David Woodier
In the following interview between Professor Helen Minnis, from University of Glasgow, and David Woodier, a teacher, adoptive parent and blogger for Scottish Attachment in Action, Helen speaks about why attachment matters to her. Themes emerging from the interview may well resonate with those living and working with children and young people who have had an adverse start in life.
DW My name is David Woodier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Unlocking the potential in our communities - George Thomson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-unlocking-the-potential-in-our-communities-george-thomson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-unlocking-the-potential-in-our-communities-george-thomson/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
GT - George Thomson
DM It is my pleasure to tell you that today is about unlocking the potential in our communities. Are we making the most effective use of all that our communities can offer? How might new partnerships improve the choice and availability of short breaks? Where is the potential for developing new opportunities? Our aim today is to consider opportunities to develop alternative approaches to short break provision but tap into the wider community resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limelight Music</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/limelight-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/limelight-music/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GG - Gordon Goodall
MM Okay now at Iriss.fm we&amp;rsquo;re joined by Gordon Goodall the Director of Limelight and Gordon the first question would be what is Limelight?
GG Well basically Limelight&amp;rsquo;s an organisation that supports disabled musicians and provides professional training and employment with the largest employer of disabled musicians in Scotland and within that remit we also roll out a youth&amp;rsquo;s programme to primary schools and to primary schools with Autism units, vision impairment units and hearing impairment units to encourage children to look at ways of developing skills in music and also drama but mainly music, and the reason for this is so that they can get transferrable skills that can lead to employment in other stratospheres of the, of the world basically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Getting there - Roy McConkey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-getting-there-roy-mcconkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-getting-there-roy-mcconkey/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
RM - Roy McConkey
DM Well it is now my pleasure to introduce Professor Roy McConkey, who is the Emeritus Professor from Ulster University in Ireland. Roy is going to provide a personal, retrospective look at the progress of policy and practice around short breaks and respite care. We all know that progress can feel frustratingly slow at times and it&amp;rsquo;s not always even, as Steve was just reminding us, it can be up and down and up and down a bit and sometimes we lose sight of what the long-term pattern has been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: No limits - Jamie Andrew</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-no-limits-jamie-andrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-no-limits-jamie-andrew/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
JA - Jamie Andrew
DM We keep climbing up. So, we&amp;rsquo;re delighted to be able to welcome Jamie Andrew. He&amp;rsquo;s going to inspire us I&amp;rsquo;m sure, and challenge us to look at the barriers that get in the way of progress and to believe in the influence we can exert individually and collectively to achieve our goal. So, as I said earlier, you&amp;rsquo;re joy-givers, you&amp;rsquo;re hope-givers, you&amp;rsquo;re the people who make a huge difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Reframing respite - Maureen Flynn</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-reframing-respite-maureen-flynn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-reframing-respite-maureen-flynn/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
MF - Maureen Flynn
DM It is now my pleasure to introduce Maureen Flynn, who is Project Officer and Transition Support Co-ordinator with Interchange Illawarra Incorporated in New South Wales, Australia. Maureen will talk to us about the transformational changes taking place throughout Australia with a move to individualised funding packages of support for people with disability, their families and carers. It&amp;rsquo;s known as consumer directed care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: The 10th International Short Break Association conference - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
DW - Don Williamson
DW What is ISBA? Right ISBA stands for the International Short Break Association and it&amp;rsquo;s a worldwide initiative made up of a whole variety of different agencies and organisations who are all providing healthcare and respite services for families who are concerned or affected by disability. It began back in 1995 with a Conference in a place called Thunder Bay in Canada and the event was entitled Rendezvous for Respite and then we managed to bring together 300 people from 13 different countries, possibly the very first time that that&amp;rsquo;s ever happened that we&amp;rsquo;ve had such a large gathering of people with that shared sort of common interest in respite and then from there it evolved into a whole series of Conferences which happen every two years and they are hosted by different countries and Scotland this year is hosting the 10th event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: The shifting sector - Amy MacFarlane</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-shifting-sector-amy-macfarlane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-shifting-sector-amy-macfarlane/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
AM - Amy McFarlane
DM My pleasure it is now to introduce Amy MacFarlane, who is the Chief Executive and founder of Recreation Respite Canada. As a provider of creative and flexible respite services, Amy will tell us about the latest developments in policy and practice in Canada and how this is changing people&amp;rsquo;s expectations of where, when and how respite services are delivered. Amy will share her views on the need for traditional services to become more entrepreneurial and collaborative in their approach to service development and what this means in terms of new business skills and tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Adventures with dementia - Neil Mapes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
NP - Neil Mapes
DM Well it&amp;rsquo;s now my pleasure to introduce Neil Mapes who&amp;rsquo;s the Chief Executive of Dementia Adventure. Now Neil is the founder and co-director of Dementia Adventure, which is an awarding winning community interest company and charity, which specialises in supporting people with dementia and their families, to have adventure experiences. Neil will share his own thoughts about how we traditionally respond to those diagnosed with dementia and the barriers we need to overcome if we are to help those with dementia and their family enjoy their lives to the full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Anything to declare? - Jaynie Mitchell</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-anything-to-declare-jaynie-mitchell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-anything-to-declare-jaynie-mitchell/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
JM - Janie Mitchell
DM The theme of today is to look at ways in which we can enable people to develop policies and practices to maximise opportunities for people to experience real choice and control over their short breaks. Today we are looking at unlocking the potential of family and friends. What are the different ways we can support people to achieve the breaks they want?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Back in the driving seat - James McKillop</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-back-in-the-driving-seat-james-mckillop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-back-in-the-driving-seat-james-mckillop/</guid>
      <description>NM - Neil Mapes
JM - James McKillop
NM So we have got the great pleasure in introducing Dr James McKillop MBE. We have had the great pleasure in supporting James for the last 5 years or so and James is a man who likes photography and outdoor activities and is a strong family man as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you will hear but he is also a founding member of the Scottish Dementia Working Group and former Chair and since 1999 has had vascular dementia and has been part of an amazing array of initiatives and projects both Nationally and Internationally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Caring in Scotland - Aileen Campbell</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-caring-in-scotland-aileen-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-caring-in-scotland-aileen-campbell/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
AC - Aileen Campbell
DM Now if we are to make progress then it is absolutely critical that our sector has a positive relationship with our Government. Good legislation and policy is key to creating the conditions that are needed that will help us to develop the best provision that we can. I think in Scotland we are really fortunate in that we have a Government and we have a Parliament that goes to great lengths to be as open and as accessible as it can so that people really feel that they have the opportunity to engage directly with the key decisions that will affect their lives and there is a lot happening in Scotland at the moment concerning new Laws that will help to strengthen the support available to unpaid carers and to people that they care for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: ISBA values and themes - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
DN - Don Williamson
DM Well it&amp;rsquo;s my pleasure to introduce Don Williamson who is the President of the International Short Breaks Association. There must be something about 10. It&amp;rsquo;s the 10th ISBA and I noticed that Don has been the Shared Care of Scotland for 10 years and he&amp;rsquo;s done a fantastic job in spearheading the team and many, many hands have been involved in bringing all this together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Welcome - Donald Macleod</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-welcome-donald-macleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-welcome-donald-macleod/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macloud
DM Ceud Mle Filte, a hundred thousand welcomes as we say in Gaelic. To those of you who have come from 17 other nations. Failte gu na h-Alba, welcome to Scotland and to you all Failte gu Dun Eideann, welcome to Edinburgh. Maidin mhaith, good morning. My name is Domhnall Eoin ma&amp;rsquo;klaud, Donald Ian Macleod and it&amp;rsquo;s a pleasure to stand here today to welcome you to the 10th International Short Breaks Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C-Change</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/c-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/c-change/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan (Interviewer)
CW - Cheryl Walker
MM OK and we&amp;rsquo;re at the C-Change office in Glasgow and we&amp;rsquo;re joined by Cheryl Walker. Now Cheryl Walker is a PR in Marketing, Development Officer at C-Change. So Cheryl, can you tell us first of all what is C-Change?
CW C-Change is a supported living organisation. We&amp;rsquo;ve been in existence for about 15 years now. We&amp;rsquo;re actually celebrating our 15 year anniversary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social pedagogy in practice at Camphill Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice-at-camphill-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice-at-camphill-scotland/</guid>
      <description>K - Kirsten
A - Alec
I - Ishtvan
R - Robina
S - Sandra
K Social Pedagogy is an approach to working with people which focusses on relationships. It encourages staff to think about how they can strengthen their relationships through spending quality time with somebody and jointly taking part in activities. It encourages them to reflect on their practise, to acknowledge where things didn&amp;rsquo;t work and to use that information not to blame themselves, but to try something different next time and to focus on how they can use their relationships with someone to help that person to learn and develop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbourhood Networks</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/neighbourhood-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/neighbourhood-networks/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Lauren May
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we are in the Neighbourhood Networks office in Glasgow and we&amp;rsquo;re speaking to Lauren May who is the Network Manager for Glasgow. So, first of all, Lauren, can you tell us what is Neighbourhood Networks?
LM So, Neighbourhood Networks facilitates networks of peer support in communities for adults who have a learning disability, mental health problems, people who have physical disabilities as well or just generally anybody who is isolated in their community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging child protection: new directions in safeguarding children</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenging-child-protection-new-directions-in-safeguarding-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenging-child-protection-new-directions-in-safeguarding-children/</guid>
      <description>JM - Janice McGhee
JM What I&amp;rsquo;ll be partly doing is drawing on a recently edited book that Lorraine and I have been involved in and are the editors of that is, has this title New Directions in Safeguarding Children and I&amp;rsquo;ll also be drawing on some of my work as the Social Work lead for the Administrative Data Research Centre. It&amp;rsquo;s a Centre that is funded by the ESRC. There is one in each of the four parts of the UK and it&amp;rsquo;s really intended to support and promote the use of data that is already routinely collected by Government, by Public Agencies, by the third sector and use that for research purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social workers&#39; communication with children involved in child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-workers-communication-with-children-involved-in-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-workers-communication-with-children-involved-in-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>Viv - Viv Cree
Fiona - Fiona Morrison
Viv So, hello everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m Viv Cree, I&amp;rsquo;m a Professor of social work studies at the University of Edinburgh. I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to meet with you today and really pleased at the response we&amp;rsquo;ve had to our project. This is the second of three seminars within Scottish Government and in our project, which has a website. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be sharing all the materials that have come from the project we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about today and the project we&amp;rsquo;re involved in now because what we&amp;rsquo;re doing right now is very much what&amp;rsquo;s called an impact project, which is about taking forward the findings from our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reforming child protection insights from Australasia</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-child-protection-insights-from-australasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-child-protection-insights-from-australasia/</guid>
      <description>MC - Professor Marie Connolly
MC (unclear 00:07) Greetings to you. Greetings to you and greetings to you all. Thank you for inviting me and thank you to Viv, the University of Edinburgh, for making this possible. I was chief social worker in New Zealand at a time when reform was very much in the mind of the New Zealand Government, and so I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you today some of the insights from that period of time because we did quite an integrated set of reforms between 2005 and 2010, and then I moved into my current role at the University of Melbourne and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been a part of a number of ministerial committees that are advancing reform processes in child welfare both in Melbourne and in New South Wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acumen: giving mental health service users and carers a voice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/acumen-giving-mental-health-service-users-and-carers-a-voice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/acumen-giving-mental-health-service-users-and-carers-a-voice/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
PV - Pauline Vance
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we are joined by Pauline Vance. Pauline is a Development Worker for Acumen. Acumen is a Mental Health charity. Thanks Pauline for giving up your time and speaking to us. First of all, what can you tell us what is ACUMEN?
PV Okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what it stands for first of all. It stands for Advancing Community Understanding of Mental and Emotional Needs, which is a very long thing to stand for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2016</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2016/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we are here at the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability with Linda Mitchell. Linda is the Learning and Development Manager for the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability and we&amp;rsquo;re here to speak to her about the 2016 Learning Disability Week that&amp;rsquo;s coming up in May. So first of all, Linda, why do we have Learning Disability Week?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action on Hearing Loss Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/action-on-hearing-loss-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/action-on-hearing-loss-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DH - Delia Henry
This is Iriss.fm Internet radio for Scotland Social Services.
MM Now on Iriss.fm we are here at Action on Hearing Loss Scotland and I&amp;rsquo;m joined by the Director of the Scottish branch, Delia Henry. Delia thanks for giving us your time. First question would be what is Action on Hearing Loss?
DH Action on Hearing Loss is the biggest Charity in the UK who support deaf or hard of hearing people or importantly people with tenasis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabled Access Day 2016</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disabled-access-day-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disabled-access-day-2016/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KM - Kiki McDonald
MM Now on Iriss.fm I&amp;rsquo;m joined via Skype by the cofounder of Disabled Access Day Kiki McDonald and she&amp;rsquo;s going to tell us about what is Disability Access Day. So basically, welcome. The first question I would like to ask is, what is Disabled Access Day?
KM So Disabled Access Day is a day where venues are putting on events and incentives to encourage disabled people to come and try them out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Wesley Greer</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-wesley-greer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-wesley-greer/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
WG - Wes Greer
M Wes Greer talks to Michael McEwan about his life, from school through the highs and lows of breaking into the performing arts, currently Wes is working in a voluntary post at Common Knowledge UK, he is also a member of East Kilbride Rec Theatre where he recently played the dormouse in their pantomime adaptation of Alice in Wonderland. Wes has steadfastly refused to let his learning disability limit his ambitions and he explains how his self-confidence increased through attending college and being a host city volunteer at the Common Wealth Games in Glasgow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Lynn Murdoch</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-lynn-murdoch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-lynn-murdoch/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Lynn Murdoch
In our continuing series, My Life My Way, Lynn Murdoch talks candidly to Michael McEwan about life with Cerebral Palsy. Lynn attended mainstream schools and tried office work for a while, now living in her own home and working as an activities co-ordinator in a care home, Lynn offers advice to others with disability.
MM Lynn stays in Nelson and she&amp;rsquo;s got Cerebral Palsy and she works in a care home and she is going to be speaking about her journey from school to working life to getting a house of her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: George Gordon</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-george-gordon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-george-gordon/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GG - George Gordon
Michael McEwan talks to George Gordon, a part time receptionist with the Scottish Consortium for Learning Disability, who has previously worked with Common Knowledge as an interviewer on the Special Olympics and as a support worker. He has also worked on the SCLD, Citizen Leadership Programme. In this episode, he talks about the challenge of attending college while working as a school traffic patroller and his advice on how to deal with bullying and verbal abuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violent and aggressive children: caring for those who care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/violent-and-aggressive-children-caring-for-those-who-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/violent-and-aggressive-children-caring-for-those-who-care/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
CG - Christine Gordon
KW - Karen Wallace
Adoptive or foster parents often believe they have failed and blame themselves for their children&amp;rsquo;s violent or aggressive behaviour. It is important that professionals are &amp;lsquo;trauma aware&amp;rsquo; and dot reinforce these feelings. In this episode, Edwina Grant, Chair of Scottish Attachment in Action talks to Christine Gordon and Karen Wallace of Adapt Scotland about caring for those who care for children who exhibit violent or aggressive behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bobath Scotland and World Cerebral Palsy Day</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bobath-scotland-and-world-cerebral-palsy-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bobath-scotland-and-world-cerebral-palsy-day/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
SF - Stephanie Fraser
Bobath Scotland is the only charity in Scotland dedicated to helping people with cerebral palsy, the most common cause of physical disability. With Cerebral Palsy Month coming up in October and World Cerebral Palsy Day on 7th October, Bobath Scotland Chief Executive Stephanie Fraser, talks to Michael McEwan about Bobath Therapy, the economics of running a charity, fundraising and training programmes for families, classroom assistants and young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sense Scotland: supporting disabled people and their families</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sense-scotland-supporting-disabled-people-and-their-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sense-scotland-supporting-disabled-people-and-their-families/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GT - Graeme Thomson
GH - Grant Hendry
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland Social Services. In this episode for Iriss.fm, I went out to Sense Scotland at TouchBase in Glasgow where I interviewed a Grant Hendry, one of the support workers at Sense Scotland, but first up let&amp;rsquo;s hear the interview that I did with their Communications Officer at Sense Scotland, Graeme Thomson.
MM First of all, what is Sense Scotland?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Values into Action Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/values-into-action-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/values-into-action-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DR - David Ross
CH - Catherine Hurrell
Values into Action Scotland promotes rights and equality for people with learning disabilities and individuals on the autistic spectrum. In this episode Michael McEwan first talks to David Ross about how his work as a Quality Checker helps people get more choice and control in their lives. Then Catherine Hurrell talks about a project to develop modern apprenticeships for young people on the autistic spectrum or with learning disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2015</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2015/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
MM Learning Disability Week is running from 15th to 21st June. Now why do we have Learning Disability and why is it important? Well it&amp;rsquo;s important to raise the issues of people with learning disabilities, raise issues and make people aware that there are issues, and give them a stronger voice in their community and society, at the end of the day, and hopefully we will break down barriers and give people an even bigger chance with a learning disability or mental health issues for that matter, to try and get into employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversations about alcohol: making a difference to alcohol-related harm</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/conversations-about-alcohol-making-a-difference-to-alcohol-related-harm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/conversations-about-alcohol-making-a-difference-to-alcohol-related-harm/</guid>
      <description>NF - Naimh Fitzgerald
The Evidence Exchange programme, an Alliance for Useful Evidence initiative, seeks to encourage the sharing and use of social policy evidence across the UK. One of the programme&amp;rsquo;s themes is the role of evidence in developing policy and interventions that reduce people&amp;rsquo;s risk of alcohol related harm, such as ABIs - Alcohol Brief Interventions. In this episode, Dr Naimh Fitzgerald discusses what is known about ABIs, how and where they work; her recent research on delivery of ABIs outside of primary healthcare, and pointers for practitioners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reversing the trend: supporting people to reduce harmful drinking</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reversing-the-trend-supporting-people-to-reduce-harmful-drinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reversing-the-trend-supporting-people-to-reduce-harmful-drinking/</guid>
      <description>EW - Elaine Wilson
Reversing the Trend is a resource developed by Partnership Drugs Initiative and Evaluation Support Scotland with practioners that helps to demonstrate the impact of preventative approaches for young people at risk of developing alcohol issues. In this episode we hear from Elaine Wilson, Programme Manager for Partnership Drugs Initiative, a funding programme within Lloyds TSB Foundation for Scotland. Elaine tells us more about the projects funded and the approaches taken:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery Across Mental Health (RAMH)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-across-mental-health-ramh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-across-mental-health-ramh/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KM - Karen Milne
Recovery Across Mental Health (formerly Renfrewshire Association for Mental Health) is an independent voluntary sector organisation that aims to enable people to recover from mental ill health and to promote wellbeing. This year RAMH is celebrating 25 years of providing support. Michael McEwan speaks to Karen Milne who tells us more about the organisation and launch of the celebrations.
MM Okay, now we are joined by Karen Milne from RAMH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trauma and looked after children</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-and-looked-after-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-and-looked-after-children/</guid>
      <description>FL - Fiona Lettice
CG - Christine Gordon
KW - Karen Wallace
How do we deal with trauma? Most of us have a reference point for what is &amp;lsquo;safe&amp;rsquo; which allows us to make sense of traumatic events (for example a car crash) and provides a framework to deal with it. Looked after or adoptive children often have no such reference point which makes it difficult for them and their parents to deal with trauma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Chose to Climb!</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/we-chose-to-climb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/we-chose-to-climb/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CB - Charlie Barker
MD We Chose to Climb was a three-day event or &amp;lsquo;climb&amp;rsquo; that was held over 16-18th March at the Arches in Glasgow. It was an event that brought together those interested in discussing and exploring the principles of self-directed support. Iriss.fm spoke to Charlie Barker of Social Care Ideas Factory - she tells us more about it.
MD Charlie, just tell me, you are the brain behind this event - what&amp;rsquo;s it all about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PASDA. Supporting families of adults with autism</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pasda-supporting-families-of-adults-with-autism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pasda-supporting-families-of-adults-with-autism/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DN - Donna Nelson
CP - Cath Purdie
In Edinburgh and the Lothians there are over 7,000 families supporting adults with an autistic spectrum condition. Pasda is a charity that offers support to parents, partners and siblings of adults with ASC. Executive Manager, Donna Nelson, and Cath Purdie, a carer, join Michael McEwan in a Glasgow cafe to explain how Pasda works in partnership with a whole range of organisations to help improve the health and wellbeing of families affected by ASC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dates-n-Mates</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LI - Liz Irvine
Dates &amp;lsquo;n Mates is a friendship and dating agency for people with learning disabilities. Michael McEwan talked to PR and Marketing Manager, Liz Irvine, just before Valentines Day 2015.
MM For my latest episode of Iriss.fm, I interviewed PR and Marketing Manager for Dates &amp;lsquo;n Mates, Liz Irvine.
MM First of all, Liz, can you tell us about Dates &amp;lsquo;n Mates?
LI Yes, Dates n Mates has been going 8 years now, it&amp;rsquo;s a friendship and dating agency that covers the whole of Scotland, and it&amp;rsquo;s run by and it&amp;rsquo;s for people with learning disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Scotland&#39;s Got Talent</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/young-scotlands-got-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/young-scotlands-got-talent/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
ML - Maura Lynch
Young Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Got Talent is an employment campaign for young people with learning difficulties, as well as young people with autism. Campaign organiser, Maura Lynch, explains to Michael McEwan why the campaign is as much about fun as information.
MM First off Moira, what is Young Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Got Talent?
ML Young Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Got Talent is a campaign that has been set up recognising that the number of young people with a learning disability and autism are not getting jobs and are not getting into the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East Project: supported employment</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-east-project-supported-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-east-project-supported-employment/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
EH - Emma Hill
MM We are here in the East Project in East Renfrewshire with the Project Coordinator, Emma Hill. So Emma, first tell us a bit about the project.
EH Yes, absolutely - the project is called the East Project - we have just began in East Renfrewshire in about September of this year. It&amp;rsquo;s a supported employment project, so we help individuals with learning disabilities and learning difficulties between the ages of 18-30 to look for employment opportunities - and that can be work experience, right up to paid employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go4IT digital inclusion service</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/go4it-digital-inclusion-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/go4it-digital-inclusion-service/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DW - Diane Webb
RM - Ross McNicol
DP - Dee Piggott
PH - Pamela Hewison
MD Iriss.fm visited the Glasgow Centre for Inclusive Living which hosts &amp;lsquo;Go4IT&amp;rsquo;, a digital inclusion service for adults with disabilities who are supported by Quarriers. We spoke to Diane Webb, Digital Inclusion Lead at Quarriers about how the Go4IT programme began and the type of courses it provides. Diane received a TalkTalk Digital Hero Award in 2014 for her work with Go4IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters: in play, SAIA Conference 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-in-play-saia-conference-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-in-play-saia-conference-2014/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
Theraplay is a child and family therapy aimed at enhancing and building attachment, self-esteem and trust in others. In this keynote address to the Scottish Attachment in Action Conference in December 2014, Edwina Grant explains the importance of play - the building block of human development, and explains the relationship between Dyadic Development Psychotherapy and Theraplay.
EG A little bit about me and Dyadic Developmental Practice, because DDP and Theraplay have a great deal in common I think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit for the Future in Argyll and Bute</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future-in-argyll-and-bute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future-in-argyll-and-bute/</guid>
      <description>RM - Rhiann McLean
JR - Jim Robb
JC - Jackie Connelly AA - Ann Austin
RM In 2014, the Fit for the Future project worked with Argyll &amp;amp; Bute Council and local independent sector providers to explore new approaches to the commissioning of care at home. Fit for the Future is a joint Scottish Care and Iriss project which aims to inspire better outcomes for older people by working with independent sector providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose Shoes?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/whose-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/whose-shoes/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GP - Gill Phillips
KH - Ken Howard
DH - Dorothy Hall
MB - Marion Brown
MD In this episode, Michelle Drumm from Iriss has a conversation with Gill Phillips, the creator of Whose Shoes? And Ken Howard, a media ambassador for people with dementia, who were up in Scotland from the 20th to the 24th of October to attend the European Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Conference and to also run Whose Shoes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCanDoIT, digital literacy training</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ucandoit-digital-literacy-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ucandoit-digital-literacy-training/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JJ - Joyce Jordan
MM I am joined by Joyce Jordan. Joyce is one of the tutors for UCanDoIT. Now first off Joyce, what is UCanDoIT?
JJ Well UCanDoIT is a charity which provides computer and internet training for people in their own homes, and we teach them on a one to one basis. The charity was founded in 1998 and we have a network of tutors around the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be a radical?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-radical/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-radical/</guid>
      <description>AM - Angela Morgan
On the 30th of October 2014, Iriss held its annual AGM, which featured guest speaker, Angela Morgan, Chief Executive at Includem. Includem is an organisation that provides intensive support services for Scotland&amp;rsquo;s most vulnerable young people. Her presentation was on the question, &amp;lsquo;what does it mean to be a radical?&amp;rsquo;
AM Good evening everybody, I am very pleased to be here and I appreciate the invitation from Iriss to address you and I would want to say that in terms of our relationship with Iriss, both in terms of the support that Includem receive through Alison being a member of our board and indeed our connection with your projects, we find it incredibly helpful in terms of our commitment to improvement, so you really do play a unique and very important role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover Care Opinion</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discover-care-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discover-care-opinion/</guid>
      <description>Int. - Interviewer
JM - James Munro
IO - Irene Oldfather
GA - Gina Alexander
GD - Grant Douglas
RL - Richard Lyall
On the 13th of November, Iriss.fm attended Discover Care Opinion, an event to launch, as well as discussing explore Care Opinion, the sister site to patient Opinion in Scotland. James Munro, Chief Executive of Patient Opinion, gave us the background on the initiative and its aims.
We started in 2005, we are a social enterprise, not for profit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reforming narratives: is there life after punishment?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-narratives-is-there-life-after-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-narratives-is-there-life-after-punishment/</guid>
      <description>FM - Fergus McNeill
LA - Louis Abbott
This episode features a recording of a Sutherland Trust Lecture, Reforming Narratives, is there Life after Punishment? Presented by Fergus McNeill, professor of Criminology and Social Work at the University of Glasgow. It was held on the 29th of October 2014, and features songs created by Vox Luminous, which are sung by Louis Abbott.
FM So tonight&amp;rsquo;s lecture is a little bit different, the middle is fairly conventional, in that I will talk to you for about 35 minutes about the subject of Reforming Narratives or Narratives of Reform, I suppose we could call them the narrative reconstruction that people experience as they move away from offending and into different kinds of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving permanence for disabled children</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/achieving-permanence-for-disabled-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/achieving-permanence-for-disabled-children/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LB - Liz Brabender
TB - Tam Baillie
MD On the 10th of October 2014, Iriss.fm attended an event, &amp;lsquo;Achieving permanence for disabled children&amp;rsquo; which was held at the Teacher Building in Glasgow. The event was held to discuss a new piece of research, - achieving permanence for disabled children and young people in foster care and adoption. The research was produced by Vicki Welch, Senior Research Fellow at CELCIS, Kirsten Stalker, Professor of Disability Studies at the University of Strathclyde and Chris Jones, Lecturer at the Child Protection Centre at the University of Edinburgh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we effectively engage with harder to reach older people?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-effectively-engage-with-harder-to-reach-older-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-effectively-engage-with-harder-to-reach-older-people/</guid>
      <description>VM - Vivien Moffat
SC - Sarah Currie
BM -Betty Milton
AT - Audrey Taylor
GP - Gerry Power
AM - Agnes McGroarty
Plan P: New approaches to prevention with older people is an Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter the advisory group records a group discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the fourth discussion - How can we effectively engage with hard to reach older people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASSET (Age Specialist Services Emergency Team)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/asset-age-specialist-services-emergency-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/asset-age-specialist-services-emergency-team/</guid>
      <description>TM - Trudi Marshall
ASSET, Age Specialist Services Emergency Team, was set up in February 2012 and is based in Coathill Hospital in Coatbridge. The team is running at Hospital at Home service for people aged over 65. Hospital at Home is for people who require secondary care but who are cared for at their home or the place in which they normally live, rather than having to be admitted to a hospital ward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Chris White</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-chris-white/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-chris-white/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CW - Chris White
You are listening to My Life My Way on Iriss.fm and we are joined by Chris White today. Now basically Chris was in his 20s, he was doing okay, he was married, he had a good job and a decent social life. Then he started feeling worried and anxious about most things and quickly developed into feeling as though he couldn&amp;rsquo;t cope. He attended a kind of a day centre from 1995 to 1999, and in about 2002, Chris made the decision not to use the day centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Dementia Awareness Month 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
YS - Yvonne Stewart
AMMD - Anne Marie MacDonald
AL - Anne Love
RB - Rosalyn Barclay
AMMG - Ann-Marie McGregor
MD September is World Dementia Awareness Month, and to mark it, Iriss.fm met up with the directors of Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training and a group of carers and professionals in the area of dementia care. We firstly spoke to Yvonne Stewart and Anne Marie MacDonald about Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby IN the bathwater, why attachment matters for all</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/putting-the-baby-in-the-bathwater-why-attachment-matters-for-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/putting-the-baby-in-the-bathwater-why-attachment-matters-for-all/</guid>
      <description>JS - Jonathan Sher
JS I came here from the States, specifically from North Carolina, and I can talk like this all the live long day if it would amuse and please you, but it&amp;rsquo;s not actually how I talk, so I will just sort of go with what I know and lapse into it every once in a while if it would please you. But in North Carolina, I had the pleasure of being Chief Executive of an organisation which was called the North Carolina Child Advocacy Institute, and part of what we did was to create a coalition of organisations called, &amp;lsquo;the Covenant with North Carolina&amp;rsquo;s Children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships Matter</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/relationships-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/relationships-matter/</guid>
      <description>GR - Gayle Rice
GR Relationships Matter is a project run by Iriss, and we wanted to look specifically at difficulties that workers from a range of different services experience in terms of keeping in contact with young people who are leaving care.
We have read in the literature and we have spoken to workers and young people have brought it up, time and time again, that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of difficulties maintaining relationships that they would like to continue as they transition and become inter-dependent and are moving in and out of different communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Gordon Roy</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-gordon-roy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-gordon-roy/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GR - Gordon Roy
MM When Gordon Roy left school at 17 in the 1980&amp;rsquo;s, he first attended a day centre. He was told he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to work or have a family. He left the day centre and went to college and has held down a steady job for many years. He also has a family. In the first of our new series, My Life My Way, Gordon talks to Michael McEwan about day centres, college and working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking towards better health</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/walking-towards-better-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/walking-towards-better-health/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
EG - Emma Goodlad
So we are here today with Emma Goodlad from the Walking Towards Better Health project from the ALLIANCE Scotland. Now, Emma, can you first tell us what is this project all about?
EG Well, Walking Towards Better Health was set up to really, it&amp;rsquo;s a partnership programme between Paths For All and Health and Social Care ALLIANCE Scotland, and it&amp;rsquo;s really all about trying to encourage people who are living with long term conditions to become more active through walking, because it&amp;rsquo;s the most accessible form of physical activity and it&amp;rsquo;s got so many benefits come from it, so that was really, the whole premise of it was really just to think of a really simple way to try and encourage people living with any long term condition to become more active.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge into practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-into-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-into-practice/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AW - Dr Ann Wales
In this episode, Michael McEwan talks to Dr Ann Wales about translating knowledge into practice. Ann is Programme Director for Knowledge Management with NHS Education Scotland. She explains the relationship between Social Services Knowledge Scotland, known as SSKS, and the Knowledge Network, going on to talk about the Strategy and Action Plan for embedding Knowledge in Practice in Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Services. She highlights three strands of knowledge management: skills for sourcing and sharing evidence, producing actionable knowledge, such as decision aids, and the social use of knowledge, that is tools and techniques for connecting people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospital to Home</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hospital-to-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hospital-to-home/</guid>
      <description>FM - Fiona Munro
PM - Peter McLeod
Hospital to Home is a project to design a pathway to support the transition from hospital to home for older people. Fiona Munro, the project lead, gives us an overview of Hospital to Home, progress to date and the final outcomes of the project.
FM Currently I am leading a 20 month project entitled Hospital to Home which ends in March 2015. The overall aim of this project is to design a pathway to support the transition from hospital to home for older people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do we mean by prevention?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-do-we-mean-by-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-do-we-mean-by-prevention/</guid>
      <description>VM - Viviene Moffat
GW - Glenda Watt
BM - Betty Milton
IR - Irene Reid
DY - Derek Young
GP - Gerry Power
AM - Agnes McGroarty
Plan P, New Approaches to Prevention with older People, is an Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter, the Advisory Group records a group discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the third discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPAEN and self directed support</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/spaen-and-self-directed-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/spaen-and-self-directed-support/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CM - Colin Millar
MM We are joined by Colin Millar, now Colin Millar is the Chief Executive of the Scottish Personal Assistant Employment Network, wow, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a mouthful. Colin and his team deal with Self Directed Support. So first off, can you tell us a bit about Self Directed Support?
CM Sure, Self Directed Support is the name that&amp;rsquo;s been given to a national strategy, so in November 2010, the Scottish Government started talking about folk having more choice and control and freedom over how their support needs are met, and the Self Directed Support strategy, aims to encourage folk to take a lot more control and have a lot more say over how they meet those needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write to recovery</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LG - Linda Gillard
RR - Robin Ross
AC - Ashley Campbell
JC - Jim Campbell
SN - Sandy Nisbet
SB - Simon Bradstreet
JM - John McCormack
Michelle Drumm: Write to Recovery, a website designed to support people affected by mental health problems on their journeys of recovery, was launched on the 11th of June 2014 at the Scottish Storytelling Centre in Edinburgh. The launch forms part of the Scottish Recovery Networks 10-year anniversary celebrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The arts in social care: overview of the evidence base</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-arts-in-social-care-overview-of-the-evidence-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-arts-in-social-care-overview-of-the-evidence-base/</guid>
      <description>JT - Jim Thomas
Jim Thomas: Hi, my name is Jim Thomas, and I am the Programme Head for Workforce Innovation at Skills for Care. I am going to talk to you today about the arts in social care and a presentation I made at the end of January, to a workshop for professional artists and people from social care, in partnership with the Institute for Research and Innovation into Social Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining the Future: public debate part one</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-one/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LR - Lesley Riddoc
AM - Alastair McIntosh
GM - Gehan Macleod
MD As part of the Iriss, Imagining The Future of Social Services project, led by Robert Rae, a series of creative events were held in Govan over May 2014, to explore aspirations for the future from a locality perspective and to think about the changes that need to be made now and in the coming years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining the Future: public debate part three</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-three/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
HB - Harry Burns
LR - Lesley Riddoch
MD As part of the Iriss, Imagining The Future of Social Services project, led by Robert Rae, a series of creative events were held in Govan over May 2014, to explore aspirations for the future from a locality perspective and to think about the changes that need to be made now and in the coming years. One of the events was a public debate on the subject of Social Justice, Chaired by the Journalist, Lesley Riddoch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining the Future: public debate part two</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-two/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LR - Lesley Riddoch
JM - Jackie McLeod
AU - Alison Urie
BH - Bob Hamilton
MD As part of the Iriss, Imagining The Future of Social Services project, led by Robert Rae, a series of creative events were held in Govan over May 2014, to explore aspirations for the future from a locality perspective and to think about the changes that need to be made now and in the coming years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2014/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JM - Jan Murdoch
MM You are listening to Iriss.fm and we are here with Jan Murdoch, Head of Corporate Affairs at the Scottish Consortium for Learning Disabilities, and Jan is going to be speaking to us about Learning Disability Week. Now before we speak about Learning Disability Week, can you tell us what is Learning Disability Week all about?
JM It&amp;rsquo;s a week to bring attention to the issues that are facing people with disabilities and their families, so it&amp;rsquo;s a change to think about what is happening locally or nationally and make a bit of a noise about it and to hopefully get some attention from people right across Scotland around the issues that are affecting people and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative care and support: Pitlochry</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/creative-care-and-support-pitlochry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/creative-care-and-support-pitlochry/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
FJ - Fiona Johnstone
RI - Rikke Iversholt
MD On the 29th of April, Iriss.fm spoke to Fiona and Rikke, the project leads on the Creative Care and Support project in Pitlochry, which has been underway since the autumn of 2013. They tell us where the idea for the project originated and what it aimed to do.
FJ I am Fiona Johnstone, I am the Community Engagement Worker for Highland and Perthshire and I am funded through the Reshaping Care for Older People in Polgreen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Advocacy Project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-advocacy-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-advocacy-project/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CR - Catriona Rowley
MM Now on Iriss.fm we are joined by Catriona Rowley from The Advocacy Project. Can you tell us what is advocacy if people don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is?
CR Yes, so advocacy in one sentence - it&amp;rsquo;s really just about helping people to speak up for themselves and say what they want. We don&amp;rsquo;t tell them what they should say or what they should choose, it&amp;rsquo;s all about helping them to say exactly what they think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welfare reform. Impact on third sector social and housing care providers in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-reform-impact-on-third-sector-social-and-housing-care-providers-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-reform-impact-on-third-sector-social-and-housing-care-providers-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
GW - Gregory White
SD - Shaheena Din
KM - Kirsty McKechnie
IW Iriss and CCPS - the Coalition of Care and Support Providers in Scotland, collaborated on an ESRC funded research project to investigate the impact of welfare reform on third sector social and housing care providers in Scotland. The results of this project were shared at a workshop on the 23rd of April 2014. First, Lead Researcher Gregory White, describes the project and its findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status change: will the marriage of health and social care lead to better partnership working?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/status-change-will-the-marriage-of-health-and-social-care-lead-to-better-partnership-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/status-change-will-the-marriage-of-health-and-social-care-lead-to-better-partnership-working/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
AP - Alison Petch
MD The Public Bodies (Joint Working) (Scotland) Bill that has passed through Scottish Parliament is aimed at ensuring closer integration of health and social care services across Scotland. Given a growing older population on the one hand and a past history of sometimes difficult working relationship between health and social work services on the other, any measure which will result in more joined-up services with less people falling through the gaps is to be welcomed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we ensure that older people are equal partners in developing preventative approaches?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-ensure-that-older-people-are-equal-partners-in-developing-preventative-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-ensure-that-older-people-are-equal-partners-in-developing-preventative-approaches/</guid>
      <description>VM - Vivien Moffat
IW - Irene Weeden
SC - Sarah Currie
GP - Gerry Power
AM - Agnes McGroarty
GW - Glenda Watt
BM - Betty Milton
VM Plan P - new approaches to prevention with older people is an Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter, the Project Advisory Group records a discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the second discussion and the topic is &amp;ldquo;How can we ensure that older people are equal partners in developing preventative approaches?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dates-n-Mates nightclub for people with learning disabilities</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates-nightclub-for-people-with-learning-disabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates-nightclub-for-people-with-learning-disabilities/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JP - John Paul
MM We are at the Arches in Glasgow for the &amp;lsquo;Late&amp;rsquo; event, it&amp;rsquo;s Scotland&amp;rsquo;s first fully inclusive club night for people with learning disabilities and one of the Directors is here from Dates-n-Mates, John Paul. Now, John Paul, before you tell us a bit about the campaign, can you first of all tell us a bit about what is Dates-n-Mates?
JP Yes, no bother, Michael.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit for the Future</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
RM - Rhiann McLean
MD Rhiann McLean, Project Lead on the Fit for the Future project, was happy to speak to Iriss.fm about the project and progress to date. She firstly gives an overview of Fit for the Future and explains the main objectives.
RM Fit for the Future is a partnership project between Iriss and Scottish Care that is aiming to support the independent sector to embrace the challenges and opportunities in transforming support for older people, as laid out by the Reshaping Care for Older People Agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Peckham Experiment. Henrietta Trotter in conversation with Lisa Curtice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-peckham-experiment-henrietta-trotter-in-conversation-with-lisa-curtice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-peckham-experiment-henrietta-trotter-in-conversation-with-lisa-curtice/</guid>
      <description>LC - Dr Lisa Curtice
HT - Henrietta Trotter
Henrietta Trotter was closely involved with the Pioneer Health Centre, popularly known as the Peckham Experiment. The centre was set up in 1926 as a public health research study and become something of an icon for people interested in self-organising communities. Dr Lisa Curtice, has long been interested in the Peckham Experiment, collaborating with founder, Dr Alex Scott-Samuel and others, to write its history, and subsequently becoming a trustee of the Pioneer Health Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Sony Playstation Portable (PsP) for context based learning</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/using-the-sony-playstation-portable-psp-for-context-based-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/using-the-sony-playstation-portable-psp-for-context-based-learning/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
AW - Alistair Welsh
SM - Sandy Marshall
IW First of all, Alistair, we had a plan to create some support materials for people who were preparing to go along to committee meetings.
AW &amp;hellip; we have 2 members of TAG who are part of the committee for Key, and as part of assisting the guys in preparing for and contributing to committee meetings, one of the themes that we had looked at the use of the PSP for, was whether that through the short video segment it can offer, might that be a helpful way of the two members preparing for and contributing on the day of the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disability sports in Scotland and the Commonwealth Games 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-sports-in-scotland-and-the-commonwealth-games-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-sports-in-scotland-and-the-commonwealth-games-2014/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GM - Gavin MacLeod
MM We are here on Iriss.fm, with the Chief Executive of Scottish Disability Sports, Gavin MacLeod. Gavin, so just tell us a bit about Scottish Disability Sports and the work that you do.
GM Thanks Michael, our job is really to create opportunities for people with a disability to participate in sport and then once we have got them involved in sport, is to develop their performance so that they can meet their full potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters beyond early years. SAIA Conference 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-beyond-early-years-saia-conference-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-beyond-early-years-saia-conference-2013/</guid>
      <description>TB - Tam Baillie
JF - Judy Furnivall
SW - Sally Wassell
HM - Helen Minnis
ZD - Zachary Duncalf
IR - Ian Reid
Scottish Attachment In Action, (SAIA) annual conference was held in Glasgow on 6th December 2013, on the theme of &amp;lsquo;why attachment matters beyond early years&amp;rsquo;. Tam Baillie, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Commissioner for Children and Young People, opened the conference by setting attachment in the context of the United Nations Convention on the rights of the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of ethics in social care research and six principles for ethical research</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/importance-ethics-social-care-research-six-principles-ethical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/importance-ethics-social-care-research-six-principles-ethical-research/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
AP - Alison Petch
MD An event entitled &amp;lsquo;Navigating ethical approval and access in social care research&amp;rsquo;, was held on the 28th of January 2014. It provided an opportunity to discuss the routes for gaining ethical approval for social care research and to provide a platform for the launch of the guidance document developed by a working group led by Scottish Government. In this episode, Alison Petch, Director at Iriss, speaks about the importance of ethics in social care research and the six key principles for ethical research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting practitioners through the ethical research journey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-practitioners-through-ethical-research-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-practitioners-through-ethical-research-journey/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CR - Catherine-Rose Stocks Rankin
MD An event entitled &amp;lsquo;Navigating ethical approval and access in social care research&amp;rsquo; was held on the 28th of January 2014. It provided an opportunity to discuss the routes for gaining ethical approval for social care research and to provide a platform for the launch of the guidance document developed by a working group led by Scottish government. In this episode, Catherine-Rose Stocks Ranking, Iriss Associate, speaks about supporting practitioners through the ethical research journey taken on the PROP (Practitioner Research and Older People) project .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trend Spotter network</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trend-spotter-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trend-spotter-network/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
SC - Susan Campbell
MM Today we are joined by Susan Campbell, from the Social Care Ideas Factory. First of all before Susan tells us about the project, she is going to tell us a bit about herself.
SC Hi Michael, yes, my name is Susan Campbell and I am a self employed life coach and community worker, but I have been doing bits and pieces of work for the Social Care Ideas Factory on an off for the last 5 years now and this piece of work I am working on just now is called &amp;lsquo;Trendspotters&amp;rsquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s a really exciting piece of work that I am wanting to tell Michael all about today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mindfulness-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mindfulness-practice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SG - Sandra Gyalsten
JK - Jane Kellock
MD In this episode, Iriss.fm hears from Sandra Gyalsten, Learning and Development officer at Dumfries and Galloway Council and Jane Kellock, Senior Manager of Children and Early Intervention at West Lothian Council on the subject of mindfulness and its application to Social Services practice. Firstly they gave us some background on their interest in the subject and define what mindfulness is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does prevention mean in an ageing population?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-prevention-mean-ageing-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-prevention-mean-ageing-population/</guid>
      <description>AT - Audrey Taylor
JR - Jackie Reid
JP - Jerry Power
IW - Irene Wheaton
EC - Emma Collins
DY - Derek Young
Plan P: New Approaches to prevention with older people, is a new Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter the project advisory group records a group discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the first discussion - &amp;lsquo;What does prevention mean in an ageing population?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Able Radio presents... December 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-december-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-december-2013/</guid>
      <description>MM = Michael McEwan
In this episode, guest presenter, Michael McEwan from Able Radio, gives us the latest roundup of news and events for people with disabilities.
Hello and welcome to another programme on Iriss.fm. My name is Michael McEwan. Coming up this month we will tell you about an international day of persons with a disability. We will also tell you a bit about a new initiative run by the Scottish Government, facilitated by the Social Ideas Factory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk assessment and risk management in youth justice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/risk-assessment-and-risk-management-youth-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/risk-assessment-and-risk-management-youth-justice/</guid>
      <description>LJ - Lorraine Johnstone
DO - David Orr
SA - Stuart Allardyce
NV - Nina Vaswan
MM - Mark McSherry
On 9th December 2013, Mark McSherry, Head of Development with the Risk Management Authority, hosted a discussion at the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice about risk assessment and risk management in Youth Justice. Taking part, Lorraine Johnstone, Consultant, Clinical and Forensic Psychologist, David Orr, a Social Worker with Edinburgh Youth Offending Service, currently seconded to the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice, Stuart Allardyce, also a Social Worker and seconded from Barnardo&amp;rsquo;s to the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice, and Nina Vaswani, Research Fellow at the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little engine that could - ideas into practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/little-engine-could-ideas-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/little-engine-could-ideas-practice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KD - Katharine Dill
MD Dr Katharine Dill, lecturer at Queens University Belfast and founding executive director of PART (Practice and Research Together), spoke at Iriss&amp;rsquo;s 6th annual AGM on the 27th of November 2013. Her presentation was entitled &amp;lsquo;The Little Engine That Could&amp;rsquo;, creating, building and sustaining a Canadian based knowledge exchange programme. In this programme, Dr Katharine Dill speaks about putting ideas into practice and gives an example of implementing system-wide change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little engine that could - implementation science and art</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/little-engine-could-implementation-science-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/little-engine-could-implementation-science-art/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KD - Katharine Dill
MD Dr Katharine Dill, lecturer at Queens University Belfast and founding executive director of PART (Practice and Research Together), spoke at Iriss&amp;rsquo;s 6th annual AGM on the 27th of November 2013. Her presentation was entitled &amp;lsquo;The Little Engine That Could&amp;rsquo;, creating, building and sustaining a Canadian based knowledge exchange programme. In this programme, Dr Katharine Dill, talks about the science and the art of implementing evidence informed practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little engine that could - introduction</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/little-engine-that-could-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/little-engine-that-could-introduction/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KD - Katharine Dill
MD Dr Katharine Dill, Lecturer at Queen&amp;rsquo;s University Belfast and founding Executive Director of PART, (Practice and Research Together) spoke at Iriss&amp;rsquo;s sixth annual AGM on the 27th of November 2013. Her presentation was entitled, &amp;lsquo;The Little Engine That Could&amp;rsquo;, creating, building and sustaining a Canadian based knowledge exchange programme. This programme is known as PART (Practice and Research together). In this introductory episode, she tells us how PART came about, grew and made an impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scottish Mental Health Arts and Film Festival 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-and-film-festival-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/scottish-mental-health-arts-and-film-festival-2013/</guid>
      <description>HT - Heidi Tweedie
KW - Keith Walker
LK - Lee Knifton
RW - Richard Warden
DS - Douglas T Stuart
CE - Chris Evans
RH - Roger Hutchison
CS - Chris Salt
CM - Carrie Marshall
JH - Jackie Hodges
HT Hello and welcome to the Highland Festival event roundup 2013, a programme exploring this years Scottish Mental Health Arts and Film Festival Highland contribution.
I am Heidi Tweedie, Highland Festival Publicity Coordinator and Producer of the National Festival Podcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. Reflections on the project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-reflections-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-reflections-project/</guid>
      <description>BD - Bridget Daniel
The Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential child care. Bridget Daniel is Professor of Social Work at the University of Stirling, she pooled together the main messages from the original Food Practices research as well as the Food for Thought project. She highlighted the value in combining practice based evidence with academic research adding a sprinkling of the day to day experiences of children and young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. The experience of partnership and co-production</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-experience-partnership-coproduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-experience-partnership-coproduction/</guid>
      <description>JA - Jane Alcorn
LS - Laura Steckley
Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling, into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential child care. Jane Alcorn, of Foster Care Associates, explains her experience in being part of the project, in particular working with academics. She mentions the difference between an evidence based practice and practice based evidence. Jane is followed by Laura Steckley of the University of Strathclyde who reflects on the pros and cons of co-production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. The food and care study</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-food-care-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-food-care-study/</guid>
      <description>SP - Samantha Punch
Professor Samantha Punch of the University of Stirling summarised the original research project, the use of food and food practices in residential child care in Scotland. This project gave rise to the Food for Thought project. She describes the research questions, the findings and how they set about putting the findings into practice.
SP &amp;hellip; on a very broad thing, we weren&amp;rsquo;t interested in nutrition and healthy eating or eating disorders and whilst these things are important and they may have emerged as important, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t our key focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. What it means in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-what-it-means-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-what-it-means-practice/</guid>
      <description>RE - Ruth Edmond
RG - Robbie Gilligan
The routines and the rituals that surround food, shopping, preparing, cooking, serving, clearing up, are important parts of our lives, yet often we fail to recognise as symbolic or hidden meanings. The Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential childcare. The project has created a variety of tools and training materials which encourage reflection and strengthen the use of knowledge about food and looked after children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought: the contexts of care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-contexts-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-thought-contexts-care/</guid>
      <description>RE - Ruth Edmond
RG - Robbie Gilligan
The routines and the rituals that surround food, shopping, preparing, cooking, serving, clearing up, are important parts of our lives, yet often we fail to recognise as symbolic or hidden meanings. The Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential childcare. The project has created a variety of tools and training materials which encourage reflection and strengthen the use of knowledge about food and looked after children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilotlight: self-directed support for those with mental health problems</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pilotlight-self-directed-support-those-mental-health-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pilotlight-self-directed-support-those-mental-health-problems/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KD - Kate Dowling
JM - Judith Midgeley
JL - Joyce Lorimer AI - Ailsa Innes
CW - Catriona Watson
TG - Tracey Grant
MD In this episode we hear more about the first Pilotlight Pathway in Moray Council. Kate Dowling and Judith Midgeley, Iriss associates in Pilotlight, give us an overview of the Pilotlight project and the first Pilotlight Pathway in Moray.
KD Social Care Self Directed Support Scotland Act 2013 will be enacted on the 1st of April 2014 and preparations for implementation are well underway across Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working together to safeguard and protect children and young people in sport</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/working-together-safeguard-and-protect-children-and-young-people-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/working-together-safeguard-and-protect-children-and-young-people-sport/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SR - Shona Robison
BS - Beth Smith
CB - Campbell Bell
DF - Deborah Fry
Working Together to Safeguard and Protect Children and Young People in Sport conference was held on the 29th of October 2013 at Celtic Park. It was a partnership event of WithScotland and Children 1st. Shona Robison, Minister for Commonwealth Games and Sport was keynote speaker. Michelle Drum from Iriss.fm spoke to her before the event began.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Able Radio presents- October 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MM - Michael McEwan
MD In this episode, guest presenter, Michael McEwan from Able Radio, gives us the latest roundup of news and events for people with disabilities.
MM Hello, welcome to Iriss.fm and welcome to this podcast. Coming up on this months podcast we will tell you a bit about a few AGM&amp;rsquo;s taking place - Enable Scotland, Downs Syndrome Scotland, and we will tell you a bit about the SCLD, the Scottish Consortium for Learning Disabilities we have news of events taking place later in November.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Poverty Week: effects of welfare reform on practice and practitioners</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenge-poverty-week-effects-welfare-reform-practice-and-practitioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenge-poverty-week-effects-welfare-reform-practice-and-practitioners/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
FM - Fiona McHardy
JB - Jackie Barton
CW - Chris White
LM - Lorraine McGrath
AM - Andrew MacDonald
LS - Lesley Sharkey
IK - Isobel Kelly
BL - Barry Levine
MD It&amp;rsquo;s Challenge Poverty Week 2013, and to mark it Iriss recently hosted a round-table discussion on the subject of welfare reform. The topic was &amp;lsquo;The effects of welfare reform on practice and practitioners - how can we continue to deliver positive services?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Able Radio presents - September 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
In this episode, we are pleased to introduce guest presenter, Michael McEwan, who is a regular broadcaster on Able Radio.
My name is Michael McEwan and you are listening to Iriss.fm. My background is I work on a disability radio station called Able Radio and I do numerous of disability issues in the media. For the next couple of Iriss broadcasts I will be here with news or events coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Excellence in Dementia Education Conference</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/promoting-excellence-dementia-education-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/promoting-excellence-dementia-education-conference/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
HS - Henry Simmons
PM - Peter McLaughlin
MR - Mairead Rae
PM - Pamela Mackay
Michelle Drumm: The Promoting Excellence in Dementia Education conference was held on the 18th of September 2013 at the Stirling Management Centre. Iriss.fm attended to capture some of the presentations and to get a flavour of the workshops. Henry Simmons, Chief Executive of Alzheimer Scotland, opened the conference and was subject to the Second Dementia Strategy for Scotland, he speaks about achievements in dementia care to date and some of the challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public debate on welfare reform, Learning Disability Week 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/public-debate-welfare-reform-learning-disability-week-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/public-debate-welfare-reform-learning-disability-week-2013/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PS - Peter Scott
AJ - Alex Johnston
BS - Bill Scott
AM - Andrew McKie
MM - Michael McEwan
MD An Iriss public debate on the subject of welfare reform to mark Learning Disability Week 2013 was held on the 20th of August in Glasgow. Over 50 people attended on the day. The motion for the debate was: Welfare reform will mean that people with learning disabilities are pushed further into poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential child care in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/residential-child-care-bangladesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/residential-child-care-bangladesh/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
TI - Tuhinul Islam
IW Tuhinul Islam is from Bangladesh. Currently he is a Consultant with Action Aid and a part time academic, also working with an NGO for Child Protection. As an under-graduate in Bangladesh studying forestry, he did voluntary work with slum dwellers and street children often using recreational singing and dancing techniques to help inspire the desire to learn. Seeing the harsh world of these children growing up in brothels shocked him and he decided this was where he wanted to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support is just the same as an outcomes focused approach?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-just-same-outcomes-focused-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-just-same-outcomes-focused-approach/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
NB - Nikki Bruce
AC - Anne Connor
JM - Judith Midgley
YW - Yvonne Stewart
CM - Colin Millar
CS - Caroline Sturgeon
JF = June Findlater
MD The first in a series of planned Iriss discussions took place on 20th June 2013 on the topic self-directed support. We had seven people from various organisations involved including Nikki Bruce, Head of Personalisation at Enable Scotland, Anne Connor, Chief Executive at Outside the Box, Judith Midgley, Iriss Associate on the Pilotlight project, Yvonne Stewart, SDS Project Manager at Alzheimer Scotland, Colin Millar, Chief Executive at Scottish Personal Assistant Employers&amp;rsquo; Network (SPAEN), Caroline Sturgeon, Workforce Development Advisor at SSSC and finally June Findlater, Fieldwork Manager, Adult and Older People Services at South Lanarkshire Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A collaborative consultation on the draft statutory guidance for self-directed support in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/collaborative-consultation-draft-statutory-guidance-self-directed-support-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/collaborative-consultation-draft-statutory-guidance-self-directed-support-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KF - Kate Fearnley
DM - Donald McAskill
RC - Roy Campbell
SR - Scott Reid DMD - Donna McDowell MH - Mark Paul Howard
KD - Kate Dowling
YM - Yvonne McLees
LM - Lesley McLaren
MD A consultation event on the draft statutory guidance for Self-Directed Support in Scotland was held on 6th June 2013 at the Carnegie Conference Centre in Dunfermline. It brought together providers of services and users and carers to discuss the various parts of the guidance and give their views on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Lives, Real Difference: service user and carer involvement in professional education</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/real-lives-real-difference-service-user-and-carer-involvement-professional-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/real-lives-real-difference-service-user-and-carer-involvement-professional-education/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PB - Peter Beresford
JM - James McKillop
TF - Tom Friel SS - Surinder Kaur Saroya
MM - Mo McPhail
MD The Real Lives, Real Difference conference was held at the University of Stirling on the 4th of June 2013. It focused on service user and care involvement in professional education. The keynote speaker, Peter Beresford from Brunel University and Chair of Shaping our Lives, argues that user and care involvement in professional education is of unprecedented importance and makes possible a transformed approach to occupational roles, education and practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Accolades 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2013/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
AB - Alan Baird
AF - Anna Fowlie
SM - Susan McGregor
MR - Margaret Richmond
MM - Marlene Murray
DW - Diane Wright
CT - Caroline Tumath
AW - Alex Wallace
DM - David McKay
DB - David Bleasdale
MD The Care Accolades is a wonderful opportunity to celebrate the achievements of those involved in Social Care Services across Scotland. The 2013 awards was held on a very sunny, 31st of May at Perth Concert Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why volunteer?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-volunteer/</guid>
      <description>CL - Claire Lightowler
CL This recording was made on 8th May 2013 in Stirling. We were joined at Volunteer Development Scotland&amp;rsquo;s office by a number of volunteers to talk about what motivates them to volunteer and what their experience of volunteering has been.
Welcome, I am Claire Lightowler from Iriss. It&amp;rsquo;s 8th May and we are in Volunteer Development Scotland&amp;rsquo;s offices in Stirling, and I am joined today by 9 volunteers who very kindly offered to talk about their experiences of volunteering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The politics of social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/politics-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/politics-social-work/</guid>
      <description>IF - Iain Ferguson
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland Social Services. Ian Ferguson is Professor of Social Work and Social Policy at the University of the West of Scotland. He&amp;rsquo;s widely published and a founder member of SWAN, Social Work Action Network. In this lecture at Glasgow School of Social Work on 18th April 2013 he argues that an understanding of Social Work&amp;rsquo;s political dimension is essential and that failure to recognise this has been harmful both to the Social Work profession and to service users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording and measuring outcomes: Carr Gomm</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recording-and-measuring-outcomes-carr-gomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recording-and-measuring-outcomes-carr-gomm/</guid>
      <description>AT - Andrew Thomson
J - Jill
L - Louise
Recent policy and practice shifts towards personal outcomes present a number of opportunities and challenges for those who provide human services in Scotland. Carr Gomm, which describes itself as a person centred organisation that supports people to lead their lives safely and to do the things they want to do, has developed its own conversation based outcome measurement tool. Their system is designed to capture and track the personal outcomes of the people they support and link these to the wider local and national outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bed for the night? Austerity, social work and resistance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bed-night-austerity-social-work-and-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bed-night-austerity-social-work-and-resistance/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IF = Professor Iain Ferguson
MD On 27th March 2013, Iain Ferguson, Professor of Social Work and Social Policy at the University of the West of Scotland, gave an inaugural lecture entitled &amp;lsquo;A bed for the night? Austerity, social work and resistance&amp;rsquo;, which challenges the myth of welfare dependency used to justify attacks on some of the poorest sections of the community. He examines the impact of cuts on services on people&amp;rsquo;s lives, including the working poor, and argues that the crisis calls for a different kind of social work, drawing on the radical tradition and rooted in the collective experience of service users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery 2020: A vision achieved? SRN 5th national gathering</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-2020-vision-achieved-srn-5th-national-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-2020-vision-achieved-srn-5th-national-gathering/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SB - Simon Bradstreet
RP - Rachel Perkins
JM - John McCormack
LC - Louise Christie
JG - Jenny Graydon
ED - Elinor Dowson
SS - Susan Scott
MD On 18th March 2013, Iriss.fm attended the 5th Scottish Recovery Network Gathering on the theme of &amp;lsquo;Recovery 2020: A Vision Achieved?&amp;rsquo; It featured a number of speakers from various mental health disciplines, each of who presented using the very upbeat and visual Pecha Kucha format comprising 20 images and 20 seconds per image to get the point across.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New technologies and child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/new-technologies-and-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/new-technologies-and-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CM - Colin McKerracher
BS - Beth Smith
BW - Bill White
KS - Kelly Stone
IW - Ian Watson
PR - Pauline Rattray
KL - Katrina Laing
SK - Stewart Kerr
MD On the 1st of March 2013, Iriss.fm attended the New Technologies and Child Protection Conference, which was held at the Scottish Police College in Tulliallan. It was hosted by WithScotland in partnership with the Criminal Justice Social Work Development Centre and the Youth Justice National Development Team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looked after young people and home supervision requirements</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looked-after-young-people-and-home-supervision-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looked-after-young-people-and-home-supervision-requirements/</guid>
      <description>JF - John Paul Fitzpatrick
Young people who are looked after at home or are under a Home Supervision requirement make up the largest proportion of young people who are looked after. They have the poorest educational outcomes compared to other groups, yet have been largely neglected by research. John Paul Fitzpatrick of CELCIS, the Centre for Excellence for Looked After Children in Scotland, has studied this group as part of his PhD research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the first steps with self-directed support</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/taking-the-first-steps-wth-self-directed-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/taking-the-first-steps-wth-self-directed-support/</guid>
      <description>KE - Keith Etherington
BA - Bill Alexander
KE Taking The First Steps started from the idea that there had been relatively little work done in Scotland with children, young people and families, as well as with local authorities and provider organisations, so we were trying to work out ways that people could be involved in directing their own support. And Taking the First Steps was designed to help people go through the process of Self Direct Support in a way that was safe and not risky for anyone, for people themselves, for families and for local authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Widening access to higher education for looked after young people</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/widening-access-to-higher-education-for-looked-after-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/widening-access-to-higher-education-for-looked-after-young-people/</guid>
      <description>NM - Neil Maclennan
JG - Jonathan Gray
SM - Susan Mueller
GC - Graham Connolly
Learning Enhancement and Academic Development in supporting students from a looked after background, hosted by Neil Maclennan, Jonathan Gray, Susan Mueller and Graham Connolly
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland Social Services.
On 25th January 2013, the Centre for Learning Enhancement and Academic Development at Glasgow Caledonian University, and CELCIS, the Centre for Excellent for Looked After Children in Scotland, joined forces to review progress in relation to supporting students from a looked after background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educating looked after young people: Aspire Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/educating-looked-after-young-people-aspire-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/educating-looked-after-young-people-aspire-scotland/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
FS - Francis Scott
PN - Paul Neilson
IW Aspire provides high quality residential care and education for children and young people aged between 8 and 17. Aspire Education is based in Kilbirnie, Ayrshire, in a converted cinema which is also home to a number of community facilities including a cafe, gym and games hall to which the school has access. In fact these facilities play an important part in the education programme - helping the young people integrate with the local community and learning about trust and respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Home Abroad exhibition</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/at-home-abroad-exhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/at-home-abroad-exhibition/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DS = Daniele Sime
DS This exhibition is one of a series of events that we are organising for practitioners and general public policymakers, through a knowledge exchange programme of activities funded by the Economic and Social Research Council. The exhibition is an interactive, very visual child centred model of thinking about a topic which is often quite controversial and a lot of people will have different opinions on, bringing together people who are migrants, non-migrants, people who have positive or less positive views on migration, perhaps challenging stereo types that people might have about what migrants are like and what experiences of migration are, what are peoples reasons for migrating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping an eye on the child</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/keeping-an-eye-on-the-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/keeping-an-eye-on-the-child/</guid>
      <description>BD - Brigid Daniel
It is really nice to see so many familiar faces, to see colleagues, people who work with us on the courses, previous students, and obviously this is a really rich group of folk and you really enjoy getting together. I did say at one point - why bring people in from the foyer, you are obviously having such a good time just talking to each other. So, but anyway I am just going to cover just a few small topics - leadership, multidisciplinary practice, practice learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SASW MHO of the Year Award: Liz Snodgrass</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sasw-mho-year-award-liz-snodgrass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sasw-mho-year-award-liz-snodgrass/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LS - Liz Snodgrass
MD Liz Snodgrass from Renfrewshire Council became the first winner of the Scottish Association of Social Works&amp;rsquo; Mental Health Officer of the Year Award in memory of Wilma MacDonald, a highly respected Mental Health Officer from the east end of Glasgow who died in 2009.
On 2nd November 2012, Liz agreed to speak to Iriss.fm about the significance of winning the award and was also willing to answer some other questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media and the criminal courts in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/media-and-criminal-courts-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/media-and-criminal-courts-scotland/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
JD - James Doleman
James Doleman started blogging during the Tommy Sheridan trial in 2006. At a seminar organised by Strathclyde University&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Law, Crime and Justice, James talked about why social media and criminal courts should be seen as an opportunity rather than a problem. The vast majority of court proceedings are not reported at all, and a great many are under-reported. Social media offers us a new set of media tools that can open up justice and enable citizens to take an active role in the world, going to court rooms or local Council meetings and telling people what is happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting people through partnerships: WithScotland Conference 2012</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/protecting-people-through-partnerships-withscotland-conference-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/protecting-people-through-partnerships-withscotland-conference-2012/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TW - Tom Wood
BS - Beth Smith
JB - Joy Barlow
BD - Brigid Daniel
Iriss.fm had the pleasure of attending the first WithScotland conference which was held at Stirling Management Centre on 25th October. Formerly the Scottish Childcare and Protection Network and the Multi-Agency Resource Service, respectively known as SCCPN and MARS - both organisations joined forces to become WithScotland in the summer of 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video enhanced reflective practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/video-enhanced-reflective-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/video-enhanced-reflective-practice/</guid>
      <description>RS - Robin Sen
RS - What we did was Video Enhanced Reflective Practice and I just want to kind of locate that within the wider method of Video Interaction Guidance, which is a method used with parents to improve interaction with children, particularly young children. I want to focus on the process of what we did and how we set up the training and what we did in the training and give you a few examples of what we did, and then we are going to come onto the evaluation of the training and how effective it was, which is my shakiest point - still looking at the data at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assets-based approaches to intervention</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/assets-based-approaches-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/assets-based-approaches-intervention/</guid>
      <description>LP - Lisa Pattoni
PM - Paul Morin
FG - Fiona Garven
JM - Jennifer McLean
I&amp;rsquo;m Lisa Pattoni, a Project Manager with the Iriss Innovation and Improvement Team. In this episode I will be looking at asset based approaches. An asset based approach means shifting the balance away from doing things to people in favour of doing things with people. Assets, or social assets, are things like personal skills, inner strength, knowledge and lived experiences - so things that people already possess that can be harnessed to help them deal with crisis, trauma or problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring bipolar disorder through theatre</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/exploring-bipolar-disorder-through-theatre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/exploring-bipolar-disorder-through-theatre/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
VC - Vanessa Coffey
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services.
Introduction The 2012 Scottish Mental Health Arts &amp;amp; Film Festival is underway and Iriss went along to the Centre for Contemporary Arts in Glasgow to see a performance of &amp;lsquo;Piece of Mind&amp;rsquo;, a documentary dance theatre work that brings to live verbatim interviews with 15-25 year olds diagnosed with bipolar. After the performance, Ian Watson talked to Vanessa Coffey who devised the work and is one of the two performers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Choose Life North Lanarkshire awareness programme</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/evaluating-choose-life-north-lanarkshire-awareness-programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/evaluating-choose-life-north-lanarkshire-awareness-programme/</guid>
      <description>GB - Greg Burgess
MR - Dr Mark Robinson
GB I am Greg Burgess, I am the Choose Life Coordinator for North Lanarkshire which means I am the suicide prevention guy for North Lanarkshire Council. Choose Life started in 2002, it&amp;rsquo;s the national strategy to reduce suicide in Scotland by 20% before 2013, so a 10 year plan. Each local authority was given a pot of money to spend on suicide prevention activity, that was the decision back then, so every local authority would receive a pot of money, pro rata looking at their general budgets and population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attachment focused therapy for children and young people</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/attachment-focused-therapy-children-and-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/attachment-focused-therapy-children-and-young-people/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
DH - Dan Hughes
Introduction: Dan Hughes is an specialist in dyadic developmental psychotherapy, an approach that is gaining momentum in Scotland as an effective intervention for children and young people in residential care, as well as children who are adopted or are in foster care and children have experienced abuse, neglect or trauma in their early years.
Dan is a regular visitor to Scotland and we caught up with him in September 2012 in Glasgow during a four day workshop organised by Scottish Attachment in Action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social media and social work practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-media-and-social-work-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-media-and-social-work-practice/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
DG - Deborah Goodman
KD - Katharine Dill
IW In April 2012 a team from Iriss took part in an international workshop on evidence informed practice in County Cavan, Ireland. Following the workshop I was invited to spend a couple of weeks in Toronto working with PART (Practice and Research Together). PART&amp;rsquo;s mission is to link research to child welfare practice which they do by promoting practice, organisational and systemic change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Accolades 2012</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2012/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GC - Gary Coutts
LC - Lisa Curtis
TL - Trisha Lowe
DF - Doug Fairweather
MO - Maureen O&amp;rsquo;Neill
MM - Maria McKay
MB - Mhairi Buttle
AR - Ashleigh Ryan
KM - Kenneth McGowan
KMA - Karen Maley
KS - Kirsty Soutar
GM - Grace McVeigh
H - Heather
DJ - David Jarrold
NH - Nigel Henderson
JC - Jane Cumming
LF - Leah Ford</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth family contact. Continuity or contamination?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/birth-family-contact-continuity-or-contamination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/birth-family-contact-continuity-or-contamination/</guid>
      <description>MM - Mary McKenna
BG - Barbara Godden
Conversation between Mary McKenna and Barbara Godden about contact with birth parents. Recorded at a meeting of Scottish Attachment in Action in March 2012.
MM Barbara has given permission to share some information about her family in relation to contact, so I am going to do a conversation, a Michael Parkinson conversation [laughter]. Barbara, you and your husband adopted 2 girls?
BG That&amp;rsquo;s right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotions in social work practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/emotions-social-work-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/emotions-social-work-practice/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
RI - Richard Ingram
Telephone interview with Ian Watson 11 June 2012
Richard Ingram - a lecturer in Social Work at the University of Dundee - is completing a PhD on &amp;ldquo;Emotions in Social Work Practice&amp;rdquo;. He has recently published a paper in the British Journal of Social Work looking at the role of emotional intelligence in social work. Iriss&amp;rsquo;s Ian Watson talked to Richard, via Skype, about his research and its implications for social work practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed methods research and design: their development and use</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mixed-methods-research-and-design-their-development-and-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mixed-methods-research-and-design-their-development-and-use/</guid>
      <description>JB - Julia Brannen
Introduction: Julia Brannen, Professor of the Sociology of the Family at the University of London, Institute of Education, is a leading international scholar in the fields of family life, work life and intergenerational issues. In this lecture at the Glasgow School of Social Work on 7th June 2012, Professor Brannen explores what we mean by mixed methods - that is mixed qualitative and quantitative research methodologies. She outlines the history of this approach to research and describes some recent examples of its use, in particular in studies of food practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering desistance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discovering-desistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discovering-desistance/</guid>
      <description>CL - Claire Lightowler
EW - Ewan
B - Beth
A - Archie
EL - Elizabeth
Claire Lightowler (Iriss) hosts a discussion at the second of two workshops held in Glasgow on 16 May 2012 as part of the Desistance Knowledge Exchange
CL Shall we start just going around the table and introduce yourselves a little bit?
EW I am Ewan
B I am Beth
A I am Archie
EL I am Elizabeth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy and emotional intelligence</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/empathy-and-emotional-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/empathy-and-emotional-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>DH - David Howe
David Howe - Emeritus Professor in the school of Social Work and Psychology at the University of East Anglia - one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading social work academics specialising in adoption, emotional intelligence, empathy attachment theory and child abuse and neglect. On 10th May 2012, he addressed a packed audience of academics, students and practitioners at a meeting of the resiliency, risk and vulnerability research network in the school of education, social work and community education at the University of Dundee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self directed support: North Lanarkshire demonstrator project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-north-lanarkshire-demonstrator-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-north-lanarkshire-demonstrator-project/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
CO - Carron O&amp;rsquo;Byrne
MD - Morag Dendy
GK Gerry Kelly
Interviewees: Carron O&amp;rsquo;Byrne and Morag Dendy, North Lanarkshire Council and Gerry Kelly, In Control
MD We&amp;rsquo;ve really tried to put families at the centre and give people much more choice and control over the lives they want to live and the supports that they put around them, not necessarily traditional services within that, and helping people understand the individual budget that&amp;rsquo;s available to them makes such a big difference, but we are also clear that what works in adults in working out what budget is right, isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily the same as what works for children and families, so the opportunity to test something out specifically around children and families is really exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Involving young people: messages from research</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/involving-young-people-messages-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/involving-young-people-messages-research/</guid>
      <description>HW - Helen Whincup
Helen Whincup, teaching fellow at the University of Stirling, reflects on a qualitative study entitled &amp;lsquo;Involving Young People Messages from Research&amp;rsquo; which examines how young people feel involved or not in assessment and decision making. It was recorded at a Scottish Childcare Protection meeting on the 30th of April 2012.
HW This morning is thinking about some of the messages from research about what children have said about their feelings about being involved and I will also be drawing on the research that I have been doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How prevalent is child abuse and neglect?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-prevalent-child-abuse-and-neglect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-prevalent-child-abuse-and-neglect/</guid>
      <description>LR - Lorraine Radford
Are children&amp;rsquo;s lives getting worse? Is there any evidence that our child protection efforts over the last 30 or 40 years have been making a difference? Lorraine Radford, an independent researcher and former head of research at the National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, reflected on these and other questions about child protection and abuse at a meeting of the Scottish Child Care and Protection Network on 27 April 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Worker of the Year, Sandy Watt</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-worker-year-sandy-watt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-worker-year-sandy-watt/</guid>
      <description>RI - Rikke Iversholt
SW - Sandy Watt
RI Thank you Sandy for talking to me today and congratulation on being Social Worker of the Year in Scotland.
SW Thanks very much.
RI What does it mean for you to receive this award?
SW Well I suppose I am still probably trying to come to terms with it - it was a bit of a shock at the time, but as I say, I feel quite comfortable with it now, I feel quite happy because I realise it&amp;rsquo;s more than just a personal award, it is a reflection on social work in general and my colleagues and everybody I have had contact with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding children of adults in receipt of palliative care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/safeguarding-children-adults-receipt-palliative-care-carole-comben/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/safeguarding-children-adults-receipt-palliative-care-carole-comben/</guid>
      <description>CC - Carol Comben
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Carol Comben recorded 17 March 2012
My name is Carol Comben. The focus of the study is the role of the palliative care social worker in safeguarding and promoting the welfare of children of adults who are receiving specialist palliative care. The background to this is that whilst there is a stress on the importance of the family in palliative care, reference in the literature generally refers to partners, adult relatives and carers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aberlour Glasgow Bridges service</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/aberlour-glasgow-bridges-service-cheryl-burges-sandra-sweeten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/aberlour-glasgow-bridges-service-cheryl-burges-sandra-sweeten/</guid>
      <description>CB - Cheryl Burgess
SS - Sandra Sweeten
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Cheryl Burgess and Sandra Sweeten, recorded 6th March 2012
CB Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Cheryl Burgess, I am a Research Fellow in the School of Applied Social Science at Stirling University and I am going to talk to you today about the Aberlour Glasgow Bridges Service. I will also be joined by Sandra Sweeten who is the Service Manager for the service and she will also contribute to the talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care and permanence planning for looked after children in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-and-permanence-planning-looked-after-children-scotland-gillian-henderson-malcolm-schaffer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-and-permanence-planning-looked-after-children-scotland-gillian-henderson-malcolm-schaffer/</guid>
      <description>Int. -Interviewer
GH - Gillian Henderson
MS - Michael Schaffer
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Gillian Henderson and Michael Schaffer, recorded on 16th January 2012
MS I&amp;rsquo;m Michael Schaffer and I am Head of Practice &amp;amp; Policy within SCRA.
GH I&amp;rsquo;m Gillian Henderson and I am the Information Research Manager within SCRA and I did this research with my colleagues Lucy Hanson and India Whitehead.
Int. Okay, so what research is it you have come to talk to us about today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and food practices in residential care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-and-food-practices-residential-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-and-food-practices-residential-care/</guid>
      <description>RE - Ruth Emond
SP - Sam Punch
RE My background is as a residential social workers and I had went on to do my PhD looking at young people in residential care and how they formed friends and peer relationships. And as part of that I lived in a residential unit for a year to undertake the research - and one of the things that became very apparent as a kind of pseudo resident was the significance of food and how much of a part food played in the day to day life of both the children and of the adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permanence panel: part one</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-one/</guid>
      <description>C - Chair
D - Dave
M - Margaret
A - Anne
J - Jean
H - Helen
C OK, good morning, everyone. Thanks for attending this meeting of the Permanence Panel. First item on the agenda this morning is Douglas Jones, a nine-month-old child, and we have Jean, Douglas&amp;rsquo;s social worker, attending. I think it might be useful first just to do a quick roundtable of introductions. I think, Jean, you&amp;rsquo;ve been before, but there might be one or two people who weren&amp;rsquo;t on the previous panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permanence panel: part two</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-two/</guid>
      <description>C - Chair
J - Jean
AB - Anne Brown
DC - Dave Campbell
MF - Margaret Fortes
HG - Helen Green
YS - Yvonne Smith
C Moving on to Mum&amp;rsquo;s view in terms of the permanent plan, Jean. What is Lauren currently saying about the plans for permanence for Douglas?
J Lauren&amp;rsquo;s got a foot in two camps, really, is the only way to say it. She is currently very clear that she would contest adoption for Douglas on one hand, but then on the other, she is supporting and preparing information for his future reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing up in Scotland (GUS)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/growing-scotland-gus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/growing-scotland-gus/</guid>
      <description>PB - Paul Bradshaw
Okay, so the study that I worked on is called &amp;lsquo;Growing Up In Scotland&amp;rsquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s a longitudinal study &amp;hellip; a longitudinal birth and child cohort study. So we are basically covering or tracking several groups of children from their early childhood, into sort of middle childhood, hopefully into adolescence and maybe beyond. It&amp;rsquo;s a study that is funded by Scottish government, funded by the Education Directorate, so a lot of what we do in the study is directed at producing evidence that can be used to inform policy making directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revealing lives: children and young people&#39;s experiences of parental alcohol problems</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/revealing-lives-children-and-young-peoples-experiences-parental-alcohol-problems-louise-hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/revealing-lives-children-and-young-peoples-experiences-parental-alcohol-problems-louise-hill/</guid>
      <description>LH - Dr Louise Hill
LH The research study that I would like to tell you about is called &amp;lsquo;Revealing Lives&amp;rsquo; - a qualitative study with children and young people affected by parental alcohol problems. This was a PhD study that I completed at the University of Edinburgh with Barnardo&amp;rsquo;s Childcare organisation, and I used to work for Barnardo&amp;rsquo;s as a researcher and this was a piece of work that was kind of developed along the way and in discussion with services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a scoping study on disabled children and child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/lessons-scoping-study-disabled-children-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/lessons-scoping-study-disabled-children-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>KS - Professor Kirsten Stalker
KS I am very pleased to have a chance to tell you about the scoping study that we did around disabled children and child protection. This was the research that I carried out with Dr Pam Green-Lister at Strathclyde University, it was funded by the Sir Harry Stewart Trust and we are really keen that practitioners find out about the research and the findings. The research was an 8 month scoping study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding child trafficking and the challenges for practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/understanding-child-trafficking-and-challenges-practice-paul-rigby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/understanding-child-trafficking-and-challenges-practice-paul-rigby/</guid>
      <description>PR - Paul Rigby
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Paul Rigby, recorded on 15th January 2012
PR My name is Paul Rigby. I am a researcher in the Child Protection Team at Glasgow Social Work and I am also working presently on a secondment at the Criminal Justice Development Centre at the University of Edinburgh - and I plan to talk today for about 10 minutes about the research we have been doing in Glasgow around the issue of child trafficking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A RIGHT blether with Scotland&#39;s Commissioner for Children and Young People (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/right-blether-scotlands-commissioner-children-and-young-people-part-1-katie-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/right-blether-scotlands-commissioner-children-and-young-people-part-1-katie-brown/</guid>
      <description>KB - Katie Brown
Part 1 of a talk by Katie Brown, recorded on 6th January 2012.
Welcome to the Iriss podcast. You are listening to a talk as part of the Childcare and Protection Research Collection, a partnership of Iriss and the Scottish Childcare and Protection Network. This talk was recorded on 6th January 2012. Katie Brown speaks about &amp;lsquo;A RIGHT Blether&amp;rsquo;.
KB My name is Katie Brown - I am Head of Participation and Education at the Office of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Commissioner for Children and Young People - the post is currently held by Tam Baillie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A RIGHT blether with Scotland&#39;s Commissioner for Children and Young People (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/right-blether-scotlands-commissioner-children-and-young-people-part-2-katie-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/right-blether-scotlands-commissioner-children-and-young-people-part-2-katie-brown/</guid>
      <description>KB - Katie Brown
Part 2 of a talk by Katie Brown, recorded on 6th January 2012
KB So we had the &amp;lsquo;Tell Tam Tour&amp;rsquo;. So very exciting, very successful - there&amp;rsquo;s the man himself and there&amp;rsquo;s access to him.
Then we rolled out the next part of the journey which was called &amp;lsquo;Right Brilliant Things&amp;rsquo;, and this was focused on ensuring that we were asking children and young people not only about what they think should improve in the lives of children and young people, but actually what they themselves perceived as really important parts of their lives to celebrate - what they thought was happening really well for children and young people in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rights and status of children of prisoners in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rights-and-status-children-prisoners-scotland-nico-juetten/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rights-and-status-children-prisoners-scotland-nico-juetten/</guid>
      <description>NJ - Nico Juetten
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Nico Juetten, recorded 6th January 2012
NJ The role of the (&amp;hellip; unclear) Office is to promote and safeguard the rights of children and young people, with particular regard to the United Nation&amp;rsquo;s Convention on Rights of the Child or UNCRC for short. The UK ratified the UNCRC in 1991 and so committed itself to bring in all laws, policies and practices in line with the Convention, and the Office&amp;rsquo;s remit covers children up to the age of 18 or 21 if they have been in the care system at any point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An inspector&#39;s view: quantifying intervention and outcomes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/inspectors-view-quantifying-intervention-and-outcomes-emma-mcwilliam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/inspectors-view-quantifying-intervention-and-outcomes-emma-mcwilliam/</guid>
      <description>EM - Emma McWilliam
SCCPN Seminar 20th and 21st April 2011. Thursday 21st April, 11.15am - 11.45am
Longitudinal research: measuring child well-being, outcomes and interventions from multi-disciplinary perspectives.
Introduction
EM For the past four and a half years, I have been working as an inspector in the multi-disciplinary Services for Children team based in HMIE which from the 1.4.11 transferred to SCSWIS. The main focus of my work has been joint inspections of services to protect children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child protection and disabled children: lessons from a scoping study</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-protection-and-disabled-children-lessons-scoping-study-kirsten-stalker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-protection-and-disabled-children-lessons-scoping-study-kirsten-stalker/</guid>
      <description>KS - Kirsten Stalker
Recorded in February 2012
KS I am very pleased to have a chance to tell you about the scoping study that we did around disabled children and child protection. This was the research that I carried out with Dr Pam Greenlister at Strathclyde University, it was funded by the Sir Harry Stewart Trust and we are really keen that practitioners find out about the research and the findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to encourage innovation in the regulated environment</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-encourage-innovation-regulated-environment-carole-wilkinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-encourage-innovation-regulated-environment-carole-wilkinson/</guid>
      <description>CW - Carole Wilkinson
CW Good morning everybody. It&amp;rsquo;s very nice to see some familiar faces and some old friends here this morning. I was reflecting as I was coming here that this is probably quite a good piece of timing in terms of thinking about risk and regulation in the light of what has been happening in the airline and aviation industry in the last few days (Icelandic volcano eruption) and we might want to see what we can learn from that as we go through this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the concept of Next Practice offer to people using social services?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-concept-next-practice-offer-people-using-social-services-geoff-mulgan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-concept-next-practice-offer-people-using-social-services-geoff-mulgan/</guid>
      <description>GM - Geoff Mulgan
GM What I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about two things which I suspect are, if they&amp;rsquo;re not already, will be quite live in your sort of day jobs. One is about productivity and how do you cope with pressures on money and outputs and outcomes and so on, and the other is tools of innovation to help you get to better productivity.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to take you through some methods and frameworks and then apply it to one or two specific topics that at least some of you will have far more knowledge than me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Caf</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-cafe-david-gurteen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-cafe-david-gurteen/</guid>
      <description>DG - David Gurteen
DG Good morning. We&amp;rsquo;re not only going to talk about Knowledge Cafe, we are actually going to run one and get some experience of what it is all about. But let me start by telling you the story of how I started to run Knowledge Cafes, because Knowledge Cafes have been around for quite a while, probably since back to the early 90&amp;rsquo;s and have taken various sorts of forms and formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective user involvement</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/effective-user-involvement-peter-beresford/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/effective-user-involvement-peter-beresford/</guid>
      <description>PB - Peter Beresford
PB Hello it&amp;rsquo;s good to be here today. My focus today is on effective user involvement to improve practice, support and services.
I bring three affiliations to this discussion, first working as an academic researcher in a university, second, having long term experience of using statutory mental health services and third being actively involved in service user organisations and movements as an activist and service user researcher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovative approaches to creating the learning organisation - Euan Semple</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/innovative-approaches-creating-learning-organisation-euan-semple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/innovative-approaches-creating-learning-organisation-euan-semple/</guid>
      <description>ES - Euan Semple
Using social media
ES I grew up in this part of the world and my father was Head of Computer Systems for Strathclyde region, so for a long time I heard all the moans and groans of working in local authorities and all the sort of stuff he had to deal with in the seventies and eighties, combined with his experiences of computer and delivering computing to people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting It Right for Every Child: promoting effective change</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/getting-it-right-every-child-promoting-effective-change-bill-alexander/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/getting-it-right-every-child-promoting-effective-change-bill-alexander/</guid>
      <description>BA - Bill Alexander
BA We see it everywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s all over this conference. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard it mentioned many times today.
But what is it?
It&amp;rsquo;s simple. &amp;lsquo;Getting it Right for Every Child&amp;rsquo; is transformational change in the assessment, planning and delivery of services to Scotland&amp;rsquo;s children and families, probably unparalleled since the introduction of the Children&amp;rsquo;s Hearings System and care planning processes, thirty years ago.
It&amp;rsquo;s a set of principles &amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten Citizens: today&#39;s forgotten citizens</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-todays-forgotten-citizens-furrah-arshad-tahira-ramzan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-todays-forgotten-citizens-furrah-arshad-tahira-ramzan/</guid>
      <description>TR - Tahira Ramzan
TR Hi my name is Tahira and I&amp;rsquo;m 30 years old. I used to go to Nautical College and I did a development course.
I have 7 sisters, I&amp;rsquo;m the second oldest, I have one brother. I have a learning disability, so does my sister. People don&amp;rsquo;t always understand me, once I was walking down the street and a man started to throw money at me and I got scared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten Citizens: welcome</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-welcome-lisa-curtice-david-kinloch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-welcome-lisa-curtice-david-kinloch/</guid>
      <description>DK - David Kinloch
DK Hi, my name is David. I am from Stirling.
I would like to welcome you to this Conference. I hope that you enjoy the day, and I hope that you get a lot out of all the things that are happening today.
We are here today to talk about Forgotten Citizens. People that were kept out of society and forgotten about. People that had no rights, people who had no voice, and people who had no choices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>