<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alison Petch on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/alison-petch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alison Petch on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/alison-petch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Status change: will the marriage of health and social care lead to better partnership working?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/status-change-will-the-marriage-of-health-and-social-care-lead-to-better-partnership-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/status-change-will-the-marriage-of-health-and-social-care-lead-to-better-partnership-working/</guid>
      <description>AP - Alison Petch
MD The Public Bodies (Joint Working) (Scotland) Bill that has passed through Scottish Parliament is aimed at ensuring closer integration of health and social care services across Scotland. Given a growing older population on the one hand and a past history of sometimes difficult working relationship between health and social work services on the other, any measure which will result in more joined-up services with less people falling through the gaps is to be welcomed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of ethics in social care research and six principles for ethical research</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/importance-of-ethics-in-social-care-research-and-six-principles-for-ethical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/importance-of-ethics-in-social-care-research-and-six-principles-for-ethical-research/</guid>
      <description>AP - Alison Petch
An event entitled &amp;lsquo;Navigating ethical approval and access in social care research&amp;rsquo;, was held on the 28th of January 2014. It provided an opportunity to discuss the routes for gaining ethical approval for social care research and to provide a platform for the launch of the guidance document developed by a working group led by Scottish Government. In this episode, Alison Petch, Director at Iriss, speaks about the importance of ethics in social care research and the six key principles for ethical research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
