<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welfare reform on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/welfare-reform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welfare reform on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/welfare-reform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welfare advisers in health and social care services</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-advisers-in-health-and-social-care-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-advisers-in-health-and-social-care-services/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KB - Kate Burton
RS - Roddy Samson
KC - Karen Carrick
WA roundtable discussion on the embedding of welfare advisers in health and social care services, as an effective response to the impact of welfare reform. The discussion involved Kate Burton, Public Health Practitioner at Scottish Public Health Network; Roddy Samson, Welfare Advice Service Facilitator at the Improvement Service; and Karen Carrick, Project Manager at the Improvement Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welfare reform. Impact on third sector social and housing care providers in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-reform-impact-on-third-sector-social-and-housing-care-providers-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-reform-impact-on-third-sector-social-and-housing-care-providers-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>GW - Gregory White
SD - Shaheena Din
KM - Kirsty McKechnie
Iriss and CCPS - the Coalition of Care and Support Providers in Scotland, collaborated on an ESRC funded research project to investigate the impact of welfare reform on third sector social and housing care providers in Scotland. The results of this project were shared at a workshop on the 23rd of April 2014. First, Lead Researcher Gregory White, describes the project and its findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Poverty Week: effects of welfare reform on practice and practitioners</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenge-poverty-week-effects-of-welfare-reform-on-practice-and-practitioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenge-poverty-week-effects-of-welfare-reform-on-practice-and-practitioners/</guid>
      <description>FM - Fiona McHardy
JB - Jackie Barton
CW - Chris White
LM - Lorraine McGrath
AM - Andrew MacDonald
LS - Lesley Sharkey
IK - Isobel Kelly
BL - Barry Levine
It&amp;rsquo;s Challenge Poverty Week 2013, and to mark it Iriss recently hosted a round-table discussion on the subject of welfare reform. The topic was &amp;lsquo;The effects of welfare reform on practice and practitioners - how can we continue to deliver positive services?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public debate on welfare reform, Learning Disability Week 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/public-debate-on-welfare-reform-learning-disability-week-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/public-debate-on-welfare-reform-learning-disability-week-2013/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PS - Peter Scott
AJ - Alex Johnston
BS - Bill Scott
AM - Andrew McKie
MM - Michael McEwan
MD An Iriss public debate on the subject of welfare reform to mark Learning Disability Week 2013 was held on the 20th of August in Glasgow. Over 50 people attended on the day. The motion for the debate was: Welfare reform will mean that people with learning disabilities are pushed further into poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bed for the night? Austerity, social work and resistance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-bed-for-the-night-austerity-social-work-and-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-bed-for-the-night-austerity-social-work-and-resistance/</guid>
      <description>IF - Professor Iain Ferguson
On 27th March 2013, Iain Ferguson, Professor of Social Work and Social Policy at the University of the West of Scotland, gave an inaugural lecture entitled &amp;lsquo;A bed for the night? Austerity, social work and resistance&amp;rsquo;, which challenges the myth of welfare dependency used to justify attacks on some of the poorest sections of the community. He examines the impact of cuts on services on people&amp;rsquo;s lives, including the working poor, and argues that the crisis calls for a different kind of social work, drawing on the radical tradition and rooted in the collective experience of service users.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>