<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Don Williamson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/don-williamson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Don Williamson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/don-williamson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: The 10th International Short Break Association conference - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>ED - Ellen Daly
DW - Don Williamson
DW What is ISBA? Right ISBA stands for the International Short Break Association and it&amp;rsquo;s a worldwide initiative made up of a whole variety of different agencies and organisations who are all providing healthcare and respite services for families who are concerned or affected by disability. It began back in 1995 with a Conference in a place called Thunder Bay in Canada and the event was entitled Rendezvous for Respite and then we managed to bring together 300 people from 13 different countries, possibly the very first time that that&amp;rsquo;s ever happened that we&amp;rsquo;ve had such a large gathering of people with that shared sort of common interest in respite and then from there it evolved into a whole series of Conferences which happen every two years and they are hosted by different countries and Scotland this year is hosting the 10th event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: ISBA values and themes - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
DN - Don Williamson
DM Well it&amp;rsquo;s my pleasure to introduce Don Williamson who is the President of the International Short Breaks Association. There must be something about 10. It&amp;rsquo;s the 10th ISBA and I noticed that Don has been the Shared Care of Scotland for 10 years and he&amp;rsquo;s done a fantastic job in spearheading the team and many, many hands have been involved in bringing all this together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>