<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linda Mitchell on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/linda-mitchell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linda Mitchell on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/linda-mitchell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIDD 2019 Conference</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/iassidd-2019-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/iassidd-2019-conference/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM On this podcast we hear about a World Congress coming to Glasgow called the IASSSID Congress, from 6-9 August. So, I went to interview Linda Mitchell, Linda works for the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities and is on the local organising committee for the congress. So, Linda can you give us an overview of the whole event?
LM I can Michael. So, the IASSIDD World Congress happens every 3 years and IASSIDD stands for the International Association for the Scientific Study of Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2018</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2018/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM On this podcast we hear about this year&#39;s Learning Disability week. Learning Disability week takes place between the 14th to the 20th of May and the theme for this years Learning Disability week is My Generation. We went along to the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities to find out more where we spoke to Linda Mitchell. Linda is a partnership and development manager of the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2016</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2016/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we are here at the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability with Linda Mitchell. Linda is the Learning and Development Manager for the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability and we&#39;re here to speak to her about the 2016 Learning Disability Week that&#39;s coming up in May. So first of all, Linda, why do we have Learning Disability Week?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>