<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community development on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/community-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community development on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/community-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Unlocking the potential in our communities - George Thomson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-unlocking-the-potential-in-our-communities-george-thomson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-unlocking-the-potential-in-our-communities-george-thomson/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
GT - George Thomson
DM It is my pleasure to tell you that today is about unlocking the potential in our communities. Are we making the most effective use of all that our communities can offer? How might new partnerships improve the choice and availability of short breaks? Where is the potential for developing new opportunities? Our aim today is to consider opportunities to develop alternative approaches to short break provision but tap into the wider community resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative care and support: Pitlochry</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/creative-care-and-support-pitlochry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/creative-care-and-support-pitlochry/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
FJ - Fiona Johnstone
RI - Rikke Iversholt
MD On the 29th of April, Iriss.fm spoke to Fiona and Rikke, the project leads on the Creative Care and Support project in Pitlochry, which has been underway since the autumn of 2013. They tell us where the idea for the project originated and what it aimed to do.
FJ I am Fiona Johnstone, I am the Community Engagement Worker for Highland and Perthshire and I am funded through the Reshaping Care for Older People in Polgreen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assets-based approaches to intervention</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/assets-based-approaches-to-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/assets-based-approaches-to-intervention/</guid>
      <description>LP - Lisa Pattoni
PM - Paul Morin
FG - Fiona Garven
JM - Jennifer McLean
I&#39;m Lisa Pattoni, a Project Manager with the Iriss Innovation and Improvement Team. In this episode I will be looking at asset based approaches. An asset based approach means shifting the balance away from doing things to people in favour of doing things with people. Assets, or social assets, are things like personal skills, inner strength, knowledge and lived experiences - so things that people already possess that can be harnessed to help them deal with crisis, trauma or problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>