<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ian Watson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/ian-watson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ian Watson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/ian-watson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Sony Playstation Portable (PsP) for context based learning</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/using-the-sony-playstation-portable-psp-for-context-based-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/using-the-sony-playstation-portable-psp-for-context-based-learning/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
AW - Alistair Welsh
SM - Sandy Marshall
IW First of all, Alistair, we had a plan to create some support materials for people who were preparing to go along to committee meetings.
AW ... we have 2 members of TAG who are part of the committee for Key, and as part of assisting the guys in preparing for and contributing to committee meetings, one of the themes that we had looked at the use of the PSP for, was whether that through the short video segment it can offer, might that be a helpful way of the two members preparing for and contributing on the day of the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters beyond early years. SAIA Conference 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-beyond-early-years-saia-conference-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-beyond-early-years-saia-conference-2013/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
TB - Tam Baillie
JF - Judy Furnivall
SW - Sally Wassell
HM - Helen Minnis
ZD - Zachary Duncalf
IR - Ian Reid
IW Scottish Attachment In Action, (SAIA) annual conference was held in Glasgow on 6th December 2013, on the theme of &#39;why attachment matters beyond early years&#39;. Tam Baillie, Scotland&#39;s Commissioner for Children and Young People, opened the conference by setting attachment in the context of the United Nations Convention on the rights of the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential child care in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/residential-child-care-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/residential-child-care-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
TI - Tuhinul Islam
IW Tuhinul Islam is from Bangladesh. Currently he is a Consultant with Action Aid and a part time academic, also working with an NGO for Child Protection. As an under-graduate in Bangladesh studying forestry, he did voluntary work with slum dwellers and street children often using recreational singing and dancing techniques to help inspire the desire to learn. Seeing the harsh world of these children growing up in brothels shocked him and he decided this was where he wanted to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educating looked after young people: Aspire Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/educating-looked-after-young-people-aspire-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/educating-looked-after-young-people-aspire-scotland/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
FS - Francis Scott
PN - Paul Neilson
IW Aspire provides high quality residential care and education for children and young people aged between 8 and 17. Aspire Education is based in Kilbirnie, Ayrshire, in a converted cinema which is also home to a number of community facilities including a cafe, gym and games hall to which the school has access. In fact these facilities play an important part in the education programme - helping the young people integrate with the local community and learning about trust and respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media and the criminal courts in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/media-and-the-criminal-courts-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/media-and-the-criminal-courts-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
JD - James Doleman
James Doleman started blogging during the Tommy Sheridan trial in 2006. At a seminar organised by Strathclyde University&#39;s Centre for Law, Crime and Justice, James talked about why social media and criminal courts should be seen as an opportunity rather than a problem. The vast majority of court proceedings are not reported at all, and a great many are under-reported. Social media offers us a new set of media tools that can open up justice and enable citizens to take an active role in the world, going to court rooms or local Council meetings and telling people what is happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring bipolar disorder through theatre</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/exploring-bipolar-disorder-through-theatre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/exploring-bipolar-disorder-through-theatre/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
VC - Vanessa Coffey
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland&#39;s social services.
Introduction The 2012 Scottish Mental Health Arts &amp;amp; Film Festival is underway and Iriss went along to the Centre for Contemporary Arts in Glasgow to see a performance of &#39;Piece of Mind&#39;, a documentary dance theatre work that brings to live verbatim interviews with 15-25 year olds diagnosed with bipolar. After the performance, Ian Watson talked to Vanessa Coffey who devised the work and is one of the two performers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social media and social work practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-media-and-social-work-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-media-and-social-work-practice/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
DG - Deborah Goodman
KD - Katharine Dill
IW In April 2012 a team from Iriss took part in an international workshop on evidence informed practice in County Cavan, Ireland. Following the workshop I was invited to spend a couple of weeks in Toronto working with PART (Practice and Research Together). PART&#39;s mission is to link research to child welfare practice which they do by promoting practice, organisational and systemic change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotions in social work practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/emotions-in-social-work-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/emotions-in-social-work-practice/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
RI - Richard Ingram
Telephone interview with Ian Watson 11 June 2012
Richard Ingram - a lecturer in Social Work at the University of Dundee - is completing a PhD on &amp;quot;Emotions in Social Work Practice&amp;quot;. He has recently published a paper in the British Journal of Social Work looking at the role of emotional intelligence in social work. Iriss&#39;s Ian Watson talked to Richard, via Skype, about his research and its implications for social work practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self directed support: North Lanarkshire demonstrator project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-north-lanarkshire-demonstrator-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-north-lanarkshire-demonstrator-project/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
CO - Carron O&#39;Byrne
MD - Morag Dendy
GK - Gerry Kelly
Interviewees: Carron O&#39;Byrne and Morag Dendy, North Lanarkshire Council and Gerry Kelly, In Control
MD We&#39;ve really tried to put families at the centre and give people much more choice and control over the lives they want to live and the supports that they put around them, not necessarily traditional services within that, and helping people understand the individual budget that&#39;s available to them makes such a big difference, but we are also clear that what works in adults in working out what budget is right, isn&#39;t necessarily the same as what works for children and families, so the opportunity to test something out specifically around children and families is really exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>