<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Co-production on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/co-production/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Co-production on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/co-production/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>People-led Policy Panel</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-led-policy-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-led-policy-panel/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DH - Deirdre Henderson
DS - Denis Shovlin
You&#39;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&#39;s social services podcast. On 7th February 2019 Deirdre Henderson, People-led Policy Officer at Inclusion Scotland, and Denis Shovlin, a member of the People-led Policy Panel, spoke to Michelle from Iriss about the setup, aims and ambitions of the People-led Policy Panel, a group of people who are working together to reform adult social care in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-production Week 2018</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/co-production-week-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/co-production-week-2018/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SJ - Sam Jordan
K - Kieran
A - Abbie
Co-production Week (#CoProWeekScot) was held from the 19-25 November 2018 and provided an opportunity to learn, discuss and celebrate how co-production puts people and communities at the heart of the support and services they&#39;re part of. Michelle from Iriss.fm spoke to Sam Jordan from the Scottish Community Development Centre (SCDC) about what Co-production Week is and some of the activities that took place over the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geetha Marcus</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/geetha-marcus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/geetha-marcus/</guid>
      <description>GM - Geetha Marcus
GM I&#39;m Geetha Marcus and I did a study around the experiences of Gypsy Traveller girls in Scottish schools some time ago, and before I started I thought - oh, by the way, Isaac, I hope I fulfil your strong women thing because that&#39;s, you know, you can tell me later if I fit the bill! So just a little bit about my journey, who I am and how I ended up here and how I ended up talking about Gypsies and Travellers when I&#39;m not myself a Gypsy or a Traveller, although I think there&#39;s some sort of a connection through the Indian connection, but I thought I&#39;d start with myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective user involvement</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/effective-user-involvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/effective-user-involvement/</guid>
      <description>PB - Peter Beresford
PB Hello it&#39;s good to be here today. My focus today is on effective user involvement to improve practice, support and services.
I bring three affiliations to this discussion, first working as an academic researcher in a university, second, having long term experience of using statutory mental health services and third being actively involved in service user organisations and movements as an activist and service user researcher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>