<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colin Turbett on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/colin-turbett/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colin Turbett on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/colin-turbett/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving community social work upstream</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/moving-community-social-work-upstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/moving-community-social-work-upstream/</guid>
      <description>Michelle: Hello and welcome to the Iriss.fm podcast. I&amp;rsquo;m Michelle, and in this episode we focus on community social work. It was a pleasure to get along to the Community Social Work conference on the 8 November 2022; an opportunity not only to meet people face to face, but also to hear about the new model of community social work in Fife. At the event we spoke to Colin Turbett, social work author and consultant alongside Kathy Henwood, the Chief social work officer of Fife Education and Children&amp;rsquo;s Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural social work: what is it and why is it unique?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rural-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rural-social-work/</guid>
      <description>Video link for the session Slides for the session KM - Kerry Musselbrook
CT - Colin Turbett
JP - Jane Pye
KM Welcome everyone to this, our very first session in our online series about rural social work. Today on Thursday the 10th of December 2020, we start very aptly with the topic; Rural social work: what is it and why is it unique? We&amp;rsquo;re delighted to have so many of you here and I&amp;rsquo;m equally delighted to introduce Colin Turbett and Jane Pye, our two presenters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Social Work: Colin Turbett</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-colin-turbett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-colin-turbett/</guid>
      <description>CT - Colin Turbett
CT Thanks very much folks and it&amp;rsquo;s a privilege to be here at the first of these talking social work sessions and I certainly hope it&amp;rsquo;s something that will continue, it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to see such large numbers interested in something like this. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m here tonight is because a result of a commission from Iriss, I&amp;rsquo;ve written this, now it was a collaborative effort and in a sense the story of this publication which only came off the press yesterday is a bit like the history of community social work which is what I want to talk about tonight and that history over the last fifty years since the 68 Act.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
