<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social work (general) on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/social-work-general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social work (general) on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 05:05:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/social-work-general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Influencing practice: relationships matter</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-practice-relationships-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 05:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-practice-relationships-matter/</guid>
      <description>Shaping our future: relationships matters 31 May 2019.
JI - Jackie Irvine
JI I suppose quickly just to introduce myself, I am actually the past President of SWS as of two weeks ago, so, however, the diary hasn&#39;t freed up much. The role in SWS - just to say a wee bit about that - SWS is a membership organisation that is there to encourage the leadership of sw as a profession, and therefore we do work very closely with Iona and her team and we also host the Chief SW Officers meeting which happens every two months where the 32 Chief Social Work Officers across Scotland come together to discuss, clearly the policy issues that Iona has covered, but also to discuss issues that are happening for us in practice, where the challenges are and where some of the pressures are, the implications of a tightening financial climate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influencing policy: relationships matter</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-policy-relationships-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-policy-relationships-matter/</guid>
      <description>Shaping our future: relationships matters 31 May 2019.
IC - Iona Colvin
IC I am really pleased to be here, and really pleased to see you all, newly-qualified social workers. There&#39;s a few people planted in the audience that I recognise who are certainly not newly-qualified social workers, but we&#39;ll just ignore them and we&#39;ll talk to you!
Ok, so my name is Iona Colvin and I&#39;m the Chief Social Work Adviser for the Government, and I&#39;ve been doing this job for two years now, just over two years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>