<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social work (general) on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/social-work-general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social work (general) on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 13:56:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/social-work-general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Language in social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/language-in-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 13:56:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/language-in-social-work/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SH - Sara Hitchin
MD Is use of language something you carefully consider as a social worker? And is language important to social work practice? Sara Hitchin, Senior Lecturer in Social Work at the University of Stirling certainly thinks so and has written about it for Scottish Organisation for Practice Teaching or ScOPT. Michelle from Iriss went along to University of Stirling to have a conversation with her about the importance of language and its relationship to social work values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influencing practice: relationships matter</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-practice-relationships-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 05:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-practice-relationships-matter/</guid>
      <description>Shaping our future: relationships matters 31 May 2019.
JI - Jackie Irvine
JI I suppose quickly just to introduce myself, I am actually the past President of SWS as of two weeks ago, so, however, the diary hasn&amp;rsquo;t freed up much. The role in SWS - just to say a wee bit about that - SWS is a membership organisation that is there to encourage the leadership of sw as a profession, and therefore we do work very closely with Iona and her team and we also host the Chief SW Officers meeting which happens every two months where the 32 Chief Social Work Officers across Scotland come together to discuss, clearly the policy issues that Iona has covered, but also to discuss issues that are happening for us in practice, where the challenges are and where some of the pressures are, the implications of a tightening financial climate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influencing policy: relationships matter</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-policy-relationships-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 10:17:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-policy-relationships-matter/</guid>
      <description>Shaping our future: relationships matters 31 May 2019.
IC - Iona Colvin
IC I am really pleased to be here, and really pleased to see you all, newly-qualified social workers. There&amp;rsquo;s a few people planted in the audience that I recognise who are certainly not newly-qualified social workers, but we&amp;rsquo;ll just ignore them and we&amp;rsquo;ll talk to you!
Ok, so my name is Iona Colvin and I&amp;rsquo;m the Chief Social Work Adviser for the Government, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this job for two years now, just over two years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Governance in Social Care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/research-governance-in-social-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/research-governance-in-social-care/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IM - Irina McLean
Irina McLean, Project Leader with NHS Research Scotland Management Team, is currently leading the development of a Research Governance Framework (RGF) which will meet the needs of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Care Services employers, staff and service users and their families. The Public Bodies (Joint Working) (Scotland) Act 2014 sets the context for the integration of adult health and social care in Scotland. Underpinning the introduction of the Act was a commitment to ensure the consistent provision of quality, sustainable care services for the increasing numbers of people in Scotland who need joined-up support and care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duty of Candour</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/duty-of-candour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/duty-of-candour/</guid>
      <description>SM - Stuart Muirhead
JW - Jackie Weston
AK - Alison Kirsty
LG - Lisa Greenan
LK - Linda Kemp
SM Hello and welcome to our discussion around the duty of candour, my name is Stuart Muirhead and I&amp;rsquo;m a project manager in Iriss. The thinking for this discussion came from being out about in the social services sector, over the last year and getting the feeling that the duty of candour provisions were something that were either well known, or known of and also something that was possibly causing some anxiety or confusion, either that or they weren&amp;rsquo;t on people&amp;rsquo;s radar at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generations Working Together</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/generations-working-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/generations-working-together/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KS - Kate Samuels
KM - Keith Mitchell
NS - Natalie Stewart
CC - Charlotte Craig
On 8th February 2019 Michelle from Iriss had a conversation with Kate Samuels from Generations Working Together about the work it does to promote and support intergenerational practice. She also chatted to Keith Mitchell and Natalie Stewart from Glasgow&amp;rsquo;s Golden Generation and Charlotte Craig, from Impact Arts, about their intergenerational work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in social work education</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/women-in-social-work-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/women-in-social-work-education/</guid>
      <description>VC - Viv Cree
MM - Mary Mitchell
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On the 24th of October, Iriss attended &amp;lsquo;Navigating Troubled Waters: Women in Social Work Education in Scotland&amp;rsquo; seminar where we heard from Emeritus Professor Viv Cree and Dr Mary Mitchell about a study funded by the Carnegie UK Trust which began with the realisation that women in the Academy fare less well than men across all disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social pedagogy in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MS - Mark Smith
LH - Lotte Harbo
GE - Gabriel Eichsteller
GC - Gemma Campbell
GM - Graham McPheat
MD You&amp;rsquo;re professor of Social Work isn&amp;rsquo;t it up at University of Dundee?
MS Yeah.
MD And from a social work perspective then, what is the significance of social pedagogy really?
MS For me some of the significance is it&amp;rsquo;s link back to some of the earlier ideas of Scottish social work, in particular Kilbrandon&amp;rsquo;s idea of social education and Cole Brandon thought of social education as education in it&amp;rsquo;s widest sense to work with individuals families and communities and if you think of the idea of social pedagogy then that is described as education in it&amp;rsquo;s broadest sense as well so, there are obvious sort of linkages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Social Work: Claire Ferrier</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-claire-ferrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-claire-ferrier/</guid>
      <description>CF - Claire Ferrier
Talking Social Work was an event held on the 13th September 2018 to mark the 50th Anniversary of the Social Work Scotland Act 1968, to celebrate, reflect on the journey so far and look to the future. There were a number of guest speakers. Claire Ferrier newly qualified social worker graduated from the University of Dundee with an MSc in Social Work and has just started her first post as a registered social worker with Perth and Kinross Council working within an adult care team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Social Work: Colin Turbett</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-colin-turbett/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-colin-turbett/</guid>
      <description>CT - Colin Turbett
CT Thanks very much folks and it&amp;rsquo;s a privilege to be here at the first of these talking social work sessions and I certainly hope it&amp;rsquo;s something that will continue, it&amp;rsquo;s fantastic to see such large numbers interested in something like this. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m here tonight is because a result of a commission from Iriss, I&amp;rsquo;ve written this, now it was a collaborative effort and in a sense the story of this publication which only came off the press yesterday is a bit like the history of community social work which is what I want to talk about tonight and that history over the last fifty years since the 68 Act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Social Work: Jane Martin</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-jane-martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-social-work-jane-martin/</guid>
      <description>JM - Jane Martin
Jane So it&amp;rsquo;s really good to be here and excellent turn out I think we are going to rival the opening for the V &amp;amp; A and I actually didn&amp;rsquo;t realise there was quite so many social workers. It&amp;rsquo;s fair to say that in Dundee we have a very strong belief in the value of practitioner forum, that&amp;rsquo;s particularly important given the disperse nature of our workforce and when Alan was here as Director of social work, he worked hard to introduce support and embed the approach, but in truth I think like other areas we have struggled to retain the concept, we&amp;rsquo;ve found that our meetings were becoming poorly attended and actually there was a bit of a sense that they were turning into a meeting and greeting session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building the future; shaping our social work identity</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/building-the-future-shaping-our-social-work-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/building-the-future-shaping-our-social-work-identity/</guid>
      <description>MK - Martin Kettle
Building the future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Work, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership and professional identity</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-and-professional-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-and-professional-identity/</guid>
      <description>ST - Susan Taylor
Building the Future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Work, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptions of social work education and practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/perceptions-of-social-work-education-and-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/perceptions-of-social-work-education-and-practice/</guid>
      <description>MK - Martin Kettle
Building the future: shaping our social work identity newly qualified social worker conference was held on 31 May 2018 in Edinburgh. Delivered with the University of Edinburgh (in partnership with the Higher Education Heads of Social Work Group), Iriss, Scottish Social Services Council, the Scottish Association of Social Work, Social Work Scotland and the Scottish Government, it provided an opportunity for newly qualified social workers to come together to connect and reconnect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The grand challenge(s) for social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-grand-challenges-for-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-grand-challenges-for-social-work/</guid>
      <description>JD - John Devaney
At the Social Work Scotland AGM 2018, John Devaney, Centenary Chair of Social Work, spoke about social work in Scotland today. He focused on three key themes:
The nature of modern social work and contribution of social workers to civil society
The role of leadership in social work
How to raise or sustain profile of what social work does and its value to wider society.
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAssport to Independent Living</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passport-to-independent-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passport-to-independent-living/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LS - Lilian Smith
SL - Sharon Ledger
M - Mandy
L - Lizzie
S - Susan
Y - Yvonne
A - Alison
MD 31st of October 2017 marked the launch of PAssport to Independent Living, a published collection of stories written by Personal Assistants about their experiences of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to work as a Personal Assistant in Scotland, and to raise awareness of self-directed support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme (AILIP)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/active-and-independent-living-improvement-programme-ailip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/active-and-independent-living-improvement-programme-ailip/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SM - Sarah Mitchell
SK - Susan Kelso
Sarah Mitchell, programme director for the Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme, and Susan Kelso, AHP Lead for Early Intervention with Scottish Government, spoke to Iriss.fm about the programme and the current Life Curve survey, which they would like AHP&amp;rsquo;s to complete. The Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme, or AILIP, was officially launched on April 26th by Shona Robison, MSP Cabinet Secretary for Health and Sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A watershed for social work in Scotland?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-watershed-for-social-work-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-watershed-for-social-work-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JL - Dr John Lincoln
AB - Audrey Burt
LW - Lynn Williams
SL - Sue Lavery
AB - Alan Baird
On 30th November 2016 the Health and Social Care Alliance, in Partnership with a number of Sector Organisations, including Iriss, posted a seminar entitled A Watershed for Social Work in Scotland. The event brought together people to explore the implications of the Audit Scotland Report on Social Work in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do you find real lack and real passion?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-do-you-find-real-lack-and-real-passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-do-you-find-real-lack-and-real-passion/</guid>
      <description>RF - Dr Robert French
On 24th October 2016 at the University of Strathclyde in Glasgow, Dr Robert French lead an Iriss workshop exploring how to negotiate a way through the complexities of our managed world, in order to do some of the worthwhile things we feel passionate about. In this talk he includes examples from his own experience of the school education system in England, the Poet John Keats and the text &amp;lsquo;Symposium&amp;rsquo; by the Classical Greek philosopher, Plato.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Control Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/in-control-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/in-control-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KE - Keith Etherington
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm we are in the In Control Scotland office and we are speaking to Keith Etherington, who is the director of In Control Scotland. So, first of all Keith, can you tell us more information about what is In Control Scotland?
KE Yeh, In Control Scotland is a small independent charity that&amp;rsquo;s been going, been running as an organisation since 2009, been around since 2009.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Getting there - Roy McConkey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-getting-there-roy-mcconkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-getting-there-roy-mcconkey/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
RM - Roy McConkey
DM Well it is now my pleasure to introduce Professor Roy McConkey, who is the Emeritus Professor from Ulster University in Ireland. Roy is going to provide a personal, retrospective look at the progress of policy and practice around short breaks and respite care. We all know that progress can feel frustratingly slow at times and it&amp;rsquo;s not always even, as Steve was just reminding us, it can be up and down and up and down a bit and sometimes we lose sight of what the long-term pattern has been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: No limits - Jamie Andrew</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-no-limits-jamie-andrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-no-limits-jamie-andrew/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
JA - Jamie Andrew
DM We keep climbing up. So, we&amp;rsquo;re delighted to be able to welcome Jamie Andrew. He&amp;rsquo;s going to inspire us I&amp;rsquo;m sure, and challenge us to look at the barriers that get in the way of progress and to believe in the influence we can exert individually and collectively to achieve our goal. So, as I said earlier, you&amp;rsquo;re joy-givers, you&amp;rsquo;re hope-givers, you&amp;rsquo;re the people who make a huge difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social pedagogy in practice at Camphill Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice-at-camphill-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice-at-camphill-scotland/</guid>
      <description>K - Kirsten
A - Alec
I - Ishtvan
R - Robina
S - Sandra
K Social Pedagogy is an approach to working with people which focusses on relationships. It encourages staff to think about how they can strengthen their relationships through spending quality time with somebody and jointly taking part in activities. It encourages them to reflect on their practise, to acknowledge where things didn&amp;rsquo;t work and to use that information not to blame themselves, but to try something different next time and to focus on how they can use their relationships with someone to help that person to learn and develop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The arts in social care: overview of the evidence base</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-arts-in-social-care-overview-of-the-evidence-base/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-arts-in-social-care-overview-of-the-evidence-base/</guid>
      <description>JT - Jim Thomas
Jim Thomas: Hi, my name is Jim Thomas, and I am the Programme Head for Workforce Innovation at Skills for Care. I am going to talk to you today about the arts in social care and a presentation I made at the end of January, to a workshop for professional artists and people from social care, in partnership with the Institute for Research and Innovation into Social Services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining the Future: public debate part one</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-one/</guid>
      <description>LR - Lesley Riddoch
AM - Alastair McIntosh
GM - Gehan Macleod
As part of the Iriss, Imagining The Future of Social Services project, led by Robert Rae, a series of creative events were held in Govan over May 2014, to explore aspirations for the future from a locality perspective and to think about the changes that need to be made now and in the coming years. One of the events was a public debate on the subject of Social Justice, Chaired by the Journalist, Lesley Riddoch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining the Future: public debate part three</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-three/</guid>
      <description>HB - Harry Burns
LR - Lesley Riddoch
As part of the Iriss, Imagining The Future of Social Services project, led by Robert Rae, a series of creative events were held in Govan over May 2014, to explore aspirations for the future from a locality perspective and to think about the changes that need to be made now and in the coming years. One of the events was a public debate on the subject of Social Justice, Chaired by the Journalist, Lesley Riddoch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagining the Future: public debate part two</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/imagining-the-future-public-debate-part-two/</guid>
      <description>LR - Lesley Riddoch
JM - Jackie McLeod
AU - Alison Urie
BH - Bob Hamilton
As part of the Iriss, Imagining The Future of Social Services project, led by Robert Rae, a series of creative events were held in Govan over May 2014, to explore aspirations for the future from a locality perspective and to think about the changes that need to be made now and in the coming years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Advocacy Project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-advocacy-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-advocacy-project/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CR - Catriona Rowley
MM Now on Iriss.fm we are joined by Catriona Rowley from The Advocacy Project. Can you tell us what is advocacy if people don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is?
CR Yes, so advocacy in one sentence - it&amp;rsquo;s really just about helping people to speak up for themselves and say what they want. We don&amp;rsquo;t tell them what they should say or what they should choose, it&amp;rsquo;s all about helping them to say exactly what they think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Peckham Experiment. Henrietta Trotter in conversation with Lisa Curtice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-peckham-experiment-henrietta-trotter-in-conversation-with-lisa-curtice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-peckham-experiment-henrietta-trotter-in-conversation-with-lisa-curtice/</guid>
      <description>LC - Dr Lisa Curtice
HT - Henrietta Trotter
Henrietta Trotter was closely involved with the Pioneer Health Centre, popularly known as the Peckham Experiment. The centre was set up in 1926 as a public health research study and become something of an icon for people interested in self-organising communities. Dr Lisa Curtice, has long been interested in the Peckham Experiment, collaborating with founder, Dr Alex Scott-Samuel and others, to write its history, and subsequently becoming a trustee of the Pioneer Health Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of ethics in social care research and six principles for ethical research</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/importance-of-ethics-in-social-care-research-and-six-principles-for-ethical-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/importance-of-ethics-in-social-care-research-and-six-principles-for-ethical-research/</guid>
      <description>AP - Alison Petch
An event entitled &amp;lsquo;Navigating ethical approval and access in social care research&amp;rsquo;, was held on the 28th of January 2014. It provided an opportunity to discuss the routes for gaining ethical approval for social care research and to provide a platform for the launch of the guidance document developed by a working group led by Scottish Government. In this episode, Alison Petch, Director at Iriss, speaks about the importance of ethics in social care research and the six key principles for ethical research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting practitioners through the ethical research journey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-practitioners-through-the-ethical-research-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-practitioners-through-the-ethical-research-journey/</guid>
      <description>CR - Catherine-Rose Stocks Rankin
An event entitled &amp;lsquo;Navigating ethical approval and access in social care research&amp;rsquo; was held on the 28th of January 2014. It provided an opportunity to discuss the routes for gaining ethical approval for social care research and to provide a platform for the launch of the guidance document developed by a working group led by Scottish government. In this episode, Catherine-Rose Stocks Ranking, Iriss Associate, speaks about supporting practitioners through the ethical research journey taken on the PROP (Practitioner Research and Older People) project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mindfulness-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mindfulness-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SG - Sandra Gyalsten
JK - Jane Kellock
MD In this episode, Iriss.fm hears from Sandra Gyalsten, Learning and Development officer at Dumfries and Galloway Council and Jane Kellock, Senior Manager of Children and Early Intervention at West Lothian Council on the subject of mindfulness and its application to Social Services practice. Firstly they gave us some background on their interest in the subject and define what mindfulness is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Lives, Real Difference: service user and carer involvement in professional education</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/real-lives-real-difference-service-user-and-carer-involvement-in-professional-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/real-lives-real-difference-service-user-and-carer-involvement-in-professional-education/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PB - Peter Beresford
JM - James McKillop
TF - Tom Friel
SS - Surinder Kaur Saroya
MM - Mo McPhail
MD The Real Lives, Real Difference conference was held at the University of Stirling on the 4th of June 2013. It focused on service user and care involvement in professional education. The keynote speaker, Peter Beresford from Brunel University and Chair of Shaping our Lives, argues that user and care involvement in professional education is of unprecedented importance and makes possible a transformed approach to occupational roles, education and practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Accolades 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2013/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
AB - Alan Baird
AF - Anna Fowlie
SM - Susan McGregor
MR - Margaret Richmond
MM - Marlene Murray
DW - Diane Wright
CT - Caroline Tumath
AW - Alex Wallace
DM - David McKay
DB - David Bleasdale
MD The Care Accolades is a wonderful opportunity to celebrate the achievements of those involved in Social Care Services across Scotland. The 2013 awards was held on a very sunny, 31st of May at Perth Concert Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why volunteer?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-volunteer/</guid>
      <description>CL - Claire Lightowler
CL This recording was made on 8th May 2013 in Stirling. We were joined at Volunteer Development Scotland&amp;rsquo;s office by a number of volunteers to talk about what motivates them to volunteer and what their experience of volunteering has been.
Welcome, I am Claire Lightowler from Iriss. It&amp;rsquo;s 8th May and we are in Volunteer Development Scotland&amp;rsquo;s offices in Stirling, and I am joined today by 9 volunteers who very kindly offered to talk about their experiences of volunteering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The politics of social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-politics-of-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-politics-of-social-work/</guid>
      <description>IF - Iain Ferguson
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland Social Services. Ian Ferguson is Professor of Social Work and Social Policy at the University of the West of Scotland. He&amp;rsquo;s widely published and a founder member of SWAN, Social Work Action Network. In this lecture at Glasgow School of Social Work on 18th April 2013 he argues that an understanding of Social Work&amp;rsquo;s political dimension is essential and that failure to recognise this has been harmful both to the Social Work profession and to service users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping an eye on the child</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/keeping-an-eye-on-the-child/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/keeping-an-eye-on-the-child/</guid>
      <description>BD - Brigid Daniel
It is really nice to see so many familiar faces, to see colleagues, people who work with us on the courses, previous students, and obviously this is a really rich group of folk and you really enjoy getting together. I did say at one point - why bring people in from the foyer, you are obviously having such a good time just talking to each other. So, but anyway I am just going to cover just a few small topics - leadership, multidisciplinary practice, practice learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting people through partnerships: WithScotland Conference 2012</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/protecting-people-through-partnerships-withscotland-conference-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/protecting-people-through-partnerships-withscotland-conference-2012/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TW - Tom Wood
BS - Beth Smith
JB - Joy Barlow
BD - Brigid Daniel
Iriss.fm had the pleasure of attending the first WithScotland conference which was held at Stirling Management Centre on 25th October. Formerly the Scottish Childcare and Protection Network and the Multi-Agency Resource Service, respectively known as SCCPN and MARS - both organisations joined forces to become WithScotland in the summer of 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the Choose Life North Lanarkshire awareness programme</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/evaluating-the-choose-life-north-lanarkshire-awareness-programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/evaluating-the-choose-life-north-lanarkshire-awareness-programme/</guid>
      <description>GB - Greg Burgess
MR - Dr Mark Robinson
GB I am Greg Burgess, I am the Choose Life Coordinator for North Lanarkshire which means I am the suicide prevention guy for North Lanarkshire Council. Choose Life started in 2002, it&amp;rsquo;s the national strategy to reduce suicide in Scotland by 20% before 2013, so a 10 year plan. Each local authority was given a pot of money to spend on suicide prevention activity, that was the decision back then, so every local authority would receive a pot of money, pro rata looking at their general budgets and population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Accolades 2012</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2012/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GC - Gary Coutts
LC - Lisa Curtis
TL - Trisha Lowe
DF - Doug Fairweather
MO - Maureen O&amp;rsquo;Neill
MM - Maria McKay
MB - Mhairi Buttle
AR - Ashleigh Ryan
KM - Kenneth McGowan
KMA - Karen Maley
KS - Kirsty Soutar
GM - Grace McVeigh
H - Heather
DJ - David Jarrold
NH - Nigel Henderson
JC - Jane Cumming
LF - Leah Ford</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotions in social work practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/emotions-in-social-work-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/emotions-in-social-work-practice/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
RI - Richard Ingram
Telephone interview with Ian Watson 11 June 2012
Richard Ingram - a lecturer in Social Work at the University of Dundee - is completing a PhD on &amp;ldquo;Emotions in Social Work Practice&amp;rdquo;. He has recently published a paper in the British Journal of Social Work looking at the role of emotional intelligence in social work. Iriss&amp;rsquo;s Ian Watson talked to Richard, via Skype, about his research and its implications for social work practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed methods research and design: their development and use</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mixed-methods-research-and-design-their-development-and-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mixed-methods-research-and-design-their-development-and-use/</guid>
      <description>JB - Julia Brannen
Introduction: Julia Brannen, Professor of the Sociology of the Family at the University of London, Institute of Education, is a leading international scholar in the fields of family life, work life and intergenerational issues. In this lecture at the Glasgow School of Social Work on 7th June 2012, Professor Brannen explores what we mean by mixed methods - that is mixed qualitative and quantitative research methodologies. She outlines the history of this approach to research and describes some recent examples of its use, in particular in studies of food practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Worker of the Year, Sandy Watt</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-worker-of-the-year-sandy-watt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-worker-of-the-year-sandy-watt/</guid>
      <description>RI - Rikke Iversholt
SW - Sandy Watt
RI Thank you Sandy for talking to me today and congratulation on being Social Worker of the Year in Scotland.
SW Thanks very much.
RI What does it mean for you to receive this award?
SW Well I suppose I am still probably trying to come to terms with it - it was a bit of a shock at the time, but as I say, I feel quite comfortable with it now, I feel quite happy because I realise it&amp;rsquo;s more than just a personal award, it is a reflection on social work in general and my colleagues and everybody I have had contact with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to encourage innovation in the regulated environment</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-to-encourage-innovation-in-the-regulated-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-to-encourage-innovation-in-the-regulated-environment/</guid>
      <description>CW - Carole Wilkinson
CW Good morning everybody. It&amp;rsquo;s very nice to see some familiar faces and some old friends here this morning. I was reflecting as I was coming here that this is probably quite a good piece of timing in terms of thinking about risk and regulation in the light of what has been happening in the airline and aviation industry in the last few days (Icelandic volcano eruption) and we might want to see what we can learn from that as we go through this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does the concept of Next Practice offer to people using social services?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-the-concept-of-next-practice-offer-to-people-using-social-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-the-concept-of-next-practice-offer-to-people-using-social-services/</guid>
      <description>GM - Geoff Mulgan
GM What I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about two things which I suspect are, if they&amp;rsquo;re not already, will be quite live in your sort of day jobs. One is about productivity and how do you cope with pressures on money and outputs and outcomes and so on, and the other is tools of innovation to help you get to better productivity.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to take you through some methods and frameworks and then apply it to one or two specific topics that at least some of you will have far more knowledge than me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting It Right for Every Child: promoting effective change</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/getting-it-right-for-every-child-promoting-effective-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/getting-it-right-for-every-child-promoting-effective-change/</guid>
      <description>BA - Bill Alexander
BA We see it everywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s all over this conference. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard it mentioned many times today.
But what is it?
It&amp;rsquo;s simple. &amp;lsquo;Getting it Right for Every Child&amp;rsquo; is transformational change in the assessment, planning and delivery of services to Scotland&amp;rsquo;s children and families, probably unparalleled since the introduction of the Children&amp;rsquo;s Hearings System and care planning processes, thirty years ago.
It&amp;rsquo;s a set of principles &amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>