<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coronavirus / Covid-19 on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/coronavirus-/-covid-19/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coronavirus / Covid-19 on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/coronavirus-/-covid-19/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership in a crisis</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-in-a-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 15:11:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-in-a-crisis/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KM - Kerry Musselbrook
SS - Sue Stockdale
MD Sue Stockdale works with leaders and organisations to help them achieve exceptional performance. She has an in-depth understanding of motivation and leadership, gleaned from her decades of experience in business, adventure and sport. She offers inspirational presentations, leadership development programmes and coaching. She very kindly gave us her time to talk about leadership during the Covid-19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celia Sweeney: A carer&#39;s story</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/celia-sweeney-a-carers-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/celia-sweeney-a-carers-story/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CS - Celia Sweeney
MD Celia Sweeney cares for her son Paul who has one of the rarest brain diseases in the world. She very kindly gave us her time to tell us about her situation during the Covid-19 pandemic - the challenges of caring, as well as the opportunities and what she believes needs to happen post-Covid. Please note that this episode describes some events which listeners may find distressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiences of unpaid carers during Covid-19</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/experiences-of-unpaid-carers-during-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 10:27:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/experiences-of-unpaid-carers-during-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AD - Alex Davis
FM - Frank McGowan
LC - Liz Carson
MM On this episode of Iriss.fm I took time out to speak to unpaid carers to ask them how are they coping with the whole coronavirus. So first up we&amp;rsquo;re going to hear from Alex Davis. Alex is a full-time carer for her son, and her son&amp;rsquo;s name is Benjamin. So now we&amp;rsquo;re joined by Alex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal stories of coping in lockdown</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/personal-stories-of-coping-in-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 10:22:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/personal-stories-of-coping-in-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CB - Chris Baird
DF - Dr Danielle Farrel
WG - Wesley Grierson
LK - Lindsay Kinloch
MM On this edition of Iriss.fm I went to hear people&amp;rsquo;s views that have a disability, and how it impacts on their lives, in the current crisis that we&amp;rsquo;re facing. First up I spoke to local campaigner and national campaigner, Chris Baird. Chris is from Barrhead and he tells us his views on the coronavirus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunblane Nature Kindergarten: Covid-19 response</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dunblane-nature-kindergarten-covid-19-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 09:38:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dunblane-nature-kindergarten-covid-19-response/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JH - Jenna Henderson
MD Jenna Henderson, an Early Years Educator at Dunblane Nature kindergarten tells us about the impact of lockdown on their services and how they&amp;rsquo;re maintaining relationships with children and families at this time.
MD Can you just tell me a bit about Dunblane Nature Kindergarten and your role there?
JH Yeah, so obviously I&amp;rsquo;m an early years educator at Dunblane Nature Kindergarten. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked there for just over seven and a half years and I started off as a trainee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rashielee Care Home: Covid-19 response</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rashielee-care-home-covid-19-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 10:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rashielee-care-home-covid-19-response/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JC - Jennifer Carruthers
MD On 22 April 2020, Michelle from Iriss spoke to Jennifer Carruthers, Deputy Manager at Rashielee Care Home in Erskine. Jennifer tells us how both staff and residents are managing in the current circumstances and how they&amp;rsquo;ve had to change and adapt services to cope in the crisis.
MD Would you mind just starting off by telling me, Little Inch has a number of care homes with Little Inch Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumbernauld Action for Care of the Elderly: Covid-19 response</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/cumbernauld-action-for-care-of-the-elderly-covid-19-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 08:48:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/cumbernauld-action-for-care-of-the-elderly-covid-19-response/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MR - Margaret Riley
Cumbernauld Action for Care of the Elderly, or CACE, is an organisation that supports improved wellbeing and quality of life for older people in Cumbernauld. We spoke to Margaret Riley, Chief Executive of CACE about how the organisation is managing in the Coronavirus outbreak.
MD Margaret, could you just tell me, how did CACE&amp;hellip;it stands for Cumbernauld Action for Care of the Elderly - how did that come about and what does it do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if my personal assistants need to self-isolate?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-if-all-my-personal-assistants-need-to-self-isolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:04:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-if-all-my-personal-assistants-need-to-self-isolate/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
OS - Ossie Stuart
Dr Ossie Stuart is an academic, researcher and an independent equalities consultant who has written key works on race, disability and social care. He is a wheelchair user and firmly believes that we are all entitled to fully participate in society and have control over our own destinies: these two ideas have heavily influenced everything he has done and will do in his working life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articulate: adapting to the Coronavirus pandemic</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/articulate-adapting-to-the-coronavirus-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:31:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/articulate-adapting-to-the-coronavirus-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
EC - Eona Craig
On the 27th of March 2020 Iriss spoke to Eona Craig, Chief Executive of Articulate Cultural Trust, about its work to support care experienced young people and how they&amp;rsquo;ve managed to continue to deliver services in the midst of the coronavirus pandemic. Articulate works with often socially isolated care experienced young people in Scotland, challenging loneliness, supporting connectivity and promoting physical and mental wellbeing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>