<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Child protection on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/child-protection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Child protection on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/child-protection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Child abuse scandals and online discourse</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-abuse-scandals-and-online-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-abuse-scandals-and-online-discourse/</guid>
      <description>ED - Interviewer
DF - Danielle Farrell
On the 15th November 2016 we recorded a discussion for Iriss.fm with Danielle Farrell about her PHD research. Danielle shared with us an overview of the main points of her thesis which was an examination of the 2012 Child Abuse Scandals in the UK. The research focused on the multi-functional nature of on-line discourse surrounding the issue.
DF I carried out my PHD over 4 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenging child protection: new directions in safeguarding children</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenging-child-protection-new-directions-in-safeguarding-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenging-child-protection-new-directions-in-safeguarding-children/</guid>
      <description>JM - Janice McGhee
JM What I&amp;rsquo;ll be partly doing is drawing on a recently edited book that Lorraine and I have been involved in and are the editors of that is, has this title New Directions in Safeguarding Children and I&amp;rsquo;ll also be drawing on some of my work as the Social Work lead for the Administrative Data Research Centre. It&amp;rsquo;s a Centre that is funded by the ESRC. There is one in each of the four parts of the UK and it&amp;rsquo;s really intended to support and promote the use of data that is already routinely collected by Government, by Public Agencies, by the third sector and use that for research purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social workers&#39; communication with children involved in child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-workers-communication-with-children-involved-in-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-workers-communication-with-children-involved-in-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>Viv - Viv Cree
Fiona - Fiona Morrison
Viv So, hello everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m Viv Cree, I&amp;rsquo;m a Professor of social work studies at the University of Edinburgh. I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to meet with you today and really pleased at the response we&amp;rsquo;ve had to our project. This is the second of three seminars within Scottish Government and in our project, which has a website. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be sharing all the materials that have come from the project we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about today and the project we&amp;rsquo;re involved in now because what we&amp;rsquo;re doing right now is very much what&amp;rsquo;s called an impact project, which is about taking forward the findings from our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reforming child protection insights from Australasia</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-child-protection-insights-from-australasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-child-protection-insights-from-australasia/</guid>
      <description>MC - Professor Marie Connolly
MC (unclear) Greetings to you. Greetings to you and greetings to you all. Thank you for inviting me and thank you to Viv, the University of Edinburgh, for making this possible. I was chief social worker in New Zealand at a time when reform was very much in the mind of the New Zealand Government, and so I&amp;rsquo;m going to share with you today some of the insights from that period of time because we did quite an integrated set of reforms between 2005 and 2010, and then I moved into my current role at the University of Melbourne and since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been a part of a number of ministerial committees that are advancing reform processes in child welfare both in Melbourne and in New South Wales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working together to safeguard and protect children and young people in sport</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/working-together-to-safeguard-and-protect-children-and-young-people-in-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/working-together-to-safeguard-and-protect-children-and-young-people-in-sport/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SR - Shona Robison
BS - Beth Smith
CB - Campbell Bell
DF - Deborah Fry
Working Together to Safeguard and Protect Children and Young People in Sport conference was held on the 29th of October 2013 at Celtic Park. It was a partnership event of WithScotland and Children 1st. Shona Robison, Minister for Commonwealth Games and Sport was keynote speaker. Michelle Drum from Iriss.fm spoke to her before the event began.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New technologies and child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/new-technologies-and-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/new-technologies-and-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CM - Colin McKerracher
BS - Beth Smith
BW - Bill White
KS - Kelly Stone
IW - Ian Watson
PR - Pauline Rattray
KL - Katrina Laing
SK - Stewart Kerr
MD On the 1st of March 2013, Iriss.fm attended the New Technologies and Child Protection Conference, which was held at the Scottish Police College in Tulliallan. It was hosted by WithScotland in partnership with the Criminal Justice Social Work Development Centre and the Youth Justice National Development Team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birth family contact. Continuity or contamination?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/birth-family-contact-continuity-or-contamination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/birth-family-contact-continuity-or-contamination/</guid>
      <description>MM - Mary McKenna
BG - Barbara Godden
Conversation between Mary McKenna and Barbara Godden about contact with birth parents. Recorded at a meeting of Scottish Attachment in Action in March 2012.
MM Barbara has given permission to share some information about her family in relation to contact, so I am going to do a conversation, a Michael Parkinson conversation [laughter]. Barbara, you and your husband adopted 2 girls?
BG That&amp;rsquo;s right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How prevalent is child abuse and neglect?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-prevalent-is-child-abuse-and-neglect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-prevalent-is-child-abuse-and-neglect/</guid>
      <description>LR - Lorraine Radford
Are children&amp;rsquo;s lives getting worse? Is there any evidence that our child protection efforts over the last 30 or 40 years have been making a difference? Lorraine Radford, an independent researcher and former head of research at the National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, reflected on these and other questions about child protection and abuse at a meeting of the Scottish Child Care and Protection Network on 27 April 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safeguarding children of adults in receipt of palliative care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/safeguarding-children-of-adults-in-receipt-of-palliative-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/safeguarding-children-of-adults-in-receipt-of-palliative-care/</guid>
      <description>CC - Carol Comben
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Carol Comben recorded 17 March 2012
My name is Carol Comben. The focus of the study is the role of the palliative care social worker in safeguarding and promoting the welfare of children of adults who are receiving specialist palliative care. The background to this is that whilst there is a stress on the importance of the family in palliative care, reference in the literature generally refers to partners, adult relatives and carers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permanence panel: part one</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-1/</guid>
      <description>C - Chair
D - Dave
M - Margaret
A - Anne
J - Jean
H - Helen
C OK, good morning, everyone. Thanks for attending this meeting of the Permanence Panel. First item on the agenda this morning is Douglas Jones, a nine-month-old child, and we have Jean, Douglas&amp;rsquo;s social worker, attending. I think it might be useful first just to do a quick roundtable of introductions. I think, Jean, you&amp;rsquo;ve been before, but there might be one or two people who weren&amp;rsquo;t on the previous panel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permanence panel: part two</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/permanence-panel-part-two/</guid>
      <description>C - Chair
J - Jean
AB - Anne Brown
DC - Dave Campbell
MF - Margaret Fortes
HG - Helen Green
YS - Yvonne Smith
C Moving on to Mum&amp;rsquo;s view in terms of the permanent plan, Jean. What is Lauren currently saying about the plans for permanence for Douglas?
J Lauren&amp;rsquo;s got a foot in two camps, really, is the only way to say it. She is currently very clear that she would contest adoption for Douglas on one hand, but then on the other, she is supporting and preparing information for his future reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding child trafficking and the challenges for practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/understanding-child-trafficking-and-the-challenges-for-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/understanding-child-trafficking-and-the-challenges-for-practice/</guid>
      <description>PR - Paul Rigby
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Paul Rigby, recorded on 15th January 2012
PR My name is Paul Rigby. I am a researcher in the Child Protection Team at Glasgow Social Work and I am also working presently on a secondment at the Criminal Justice Development Centre at the University of Edinburgh - and I plan to talk today for about 10 minutes about the research we have been doing in Glasgow around the issue of child trafficking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child protection and disabled children: lessons from a scoping study</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-protection-and-disabled-children-lessons-from-a-scoping-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-protection-and-disabled-children-lessons-from-a-scoping-study/</guid>
      <description>KS - Kirsten Stalker
Recorded in February 2012
KS I am very pleased to have a chance to tell you about the scoping study that we did around disabled children and child protection. This was the research that I carried out with Dr Pam Greenlister at Strathclyde University, it was funded by the Sir Harry Stewart Trust and we are really keen that practitioners find out about the research and the findings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>