<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Digital inclusion on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/digital-inclusion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Digital inclusion on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/digital-inclusion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alzheimer Scotland: the place of Near Me in our service</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-the-place-of-near-me-in-our-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-the-place-of-near-me-in-our-service/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GF - Gillian Fyfe
MD Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care Programme over the autumn/winter of 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services. Iriss has supported 5 services to participate in a rapid quality improvement cycle to start using Near ME, provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work and has developed a learning network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrossReach: using Attend Anywhere to provide counselling support</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/crossreach-using-attend-anywhere-to-provide-counselling-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/crossreach-using-attend-anywhere-to-provide-counselling-support/</guid>
      <description>TA - Tanya Anderson
Near Me in social services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish government technology enabled care programme over the autumn winter of 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services. Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid quality improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work; and has developed a learning network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Me in social services: digital inclusion</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-social-services-digital-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-social-services-digital-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>AS - Aaron Slater
Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care Programme over autumn and winter 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services. Iriss has supported 5 services to participate in a rapid quality improvement cycle to start using Near Me, provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work and has also developed a learning network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Me in social services: tools and techniques for remote communication</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-tools-and-techniques-for-remote-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 16:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-tools-and-techniques-for-remote-communication/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JC - Janet Crozier
MD Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care (TEC) Programme over Autumn/Winter 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services.
Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid Quality Improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work, and has developed a Learning Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Me in social services: an introduction</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LD - Louise Bowen
MD Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care (TEC) Programme over Autumn/Winter 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services.
Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid Quality Improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work, and has developed a Learning Network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
