<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yvonne Stewart on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/yvonne-stewart/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yvonne Stewart on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/yvonne-stewart/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>World Dementia Awareness Month 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
YS - Yvonne Stewart
AMMD - Anne Marie MacDonald
AL - Anne Love
RB - Rosalyn Barclay
AMMG - Ann-Marie McGregor
MD September is World Dementia Awareness Month, and to mark it, Iriss.fm met up with the directors of Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training and a group of carers and professionals in the area of dementia care. We firstly spoke to Yvonne Stewart and Anne Marie MacDonald about Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support is just the same as an outcomes focused approach?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-is-just-the-same-as-an-outcomes-focused-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-is-just-the-same-as-an-outcomes-focused-approach/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
NB - Nikki Bruce
AC - Anne Connor
JM - Judith Midgley
YW - Yvonne Stewart
CM - Colin Millar
CS - Caroline Sturgeon
JF - June Findlater
MD The first in a series of planned Iriss discussions took place on 20th June 2013 on the topic self-directed support. We had seven people from various organisations involved including Nikki Bruce, Head of Personalisation at Enable Scotland, Anne Connor, Chief Executive at Outside the Box, Judith Midgley, Iriss Associate on the Pilotlight project, Yvonne Stewart, SDS Project Manager at Alzheimer Scotland, Colin Millar, Chief Executive at Scottish Personal Assistant Employers&#39; Network (SPAEN), Caroline Sturgeon, Workforce Development Advisor at SSSC and finally June Findlater, Fieldwork Manager, Adult and Older People Services at South Lanarkshire Council.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>