<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Viv Cree on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/viv-cree/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Viv Cree on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/viv-cree/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Women in social work education</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/women-in-social-work-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/women-in-social-work-education/</guid>
      <description>VC - Viv Cree
MM - Mary Mitchell
You&#39;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&#39;s social services podcast. On the 24th of October, Iriss attended &#39;Navigating Troubled Waters: Women in Social Work Education in Scotland&#39; seminar where we heard from Emeritus Professor Viv Cree and Dr Mary Mitchell about a study funded by the Carnegie UK Trust which began with the realisation that women in the Academy fare less well than men across all disciplines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Viv Cree</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
VC - Viv Cree
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today, I&#39;m speaking to Viv Cree who is professor of Social work studies at the University of Edinburgh. Viv worked for 16 years as a professional social worker and community worker in both the statutory and voluntary sectors and is an accredited practice teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social workers&#39; communication with children involved in child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-workers-communication-with-children-involved-in-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-workers-communication-with-children-involved-in-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>Viv - Viv Cree
Fiona - Fiona Morrison
Viv So, hello everybody. I&#39;m Viv Cree, I&#39;m a Professor of social work studies at the University of Edinburgh. I&#39;m delighted to meet with you today and really pleased at the response we&#39;ve had to our project. This is the second of three seminars within Scottish Government and in our project, which has a website. We&#39;re going to be sharing all the materials that have come from the project we&#39;re going to talk about today and the project we&#39;re involved in now because what we&#39;re doing right now is very much what&#39;s called an impact project, which is about taking forward the findings from our research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>