<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Young people on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/young-people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Young people on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 16:10:26 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/young-people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Trauma-informed practice at Kibble</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-informed-practice-at-kibble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 16:10:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-informed-practice-at-kibble/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DJ - Dan Johnson
WH - William Howden
MD Kibble is a specialist child and youth care charity and social enterprise that empowers young people through care, education and support. In March of this year we spoke to Dan Johnson, Clinical Director and Forensic Psychologist and William Howden, a children and young people&amp;rsquo;s care worker about the charity&amp;rsquo;s trauma-informed model of care and how it makes a difference to the lives of those they support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble music project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ensemble-music-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 09:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ensemble-music-project/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MT - Michael Timmons
AS - Andrew Sinclair
Ensemble is a Loretto Care project that supports young people out of homelessness through songwriting and music. On the 19th of September Michelle from Iriss travelled to Stirling to speak with Michael Timmons, community engagement lead for the project, and Andrew Sinclair, a participant and volunteer. Ensemble received a different approach award at the Scottish Social Services Awards 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Year of Young People</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/year-of-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/year-of-young-people/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KD - Kevin Ditcham
CS - Cameron Smith
MM On this episode of Iriss.fm we are going to hear about the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo;. 2018 is the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo; here in Scotland, and I went to speak to one of them, but an Ambassador for this campaign this year is Cameron Smith, but first of all I spoke to the Project Manager for the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo;, Kevin Ditcham, and first of all I asked Kevin to tell us why this year is the &amp;lsquo;Year of Young People&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Hope</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-hope/</guid>
      <description>KB - Katherine Baxter
EB - Eileen Bray
LS - Liam Slaven
NC - Natalie Connell
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On the 28th of August 2018 we held a roundtable discussion on &amp;ldquo;Talking Hope&amp;rdquo;, a project exploring to what extent to creating safe conversational spaces amongst diverse stakeholders helps cultivate hope in a context of young people considered to be at high risk. The conversation about Katherine Baxter, Research Associate on the project, Natalie Connell, Unit Manager of the Good Shepherd Centre, Eileen Bray, Mental Health Nurse at CAMHS Ayrshire and Arran, and Liam Slaven, a care-experienced young person and member of Star Board which aims to transform secure care in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Violent and aggressive children: caring for those who care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/violent-and-aggressive-children-caring-for-those-who-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/violent-and-aggressive-children-caring-for-those-who-care/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
CG - Christine Gordon
KW - Karen Wallace
Adoptive or foster parents often believe they have failed and blame themselves for their children&amp;rsquo;s violent or aggressive behaviour. It is important that professionals are &amp;lsquo;trauma aware&amp;rsquo; and dot reinforce these feelings. In this episode, Edwina Grant, Chair of Scottish Attachment in Action talks to Christine Gordon and Karen Wallace of Adapt Scotland about caring for those who care for children who exhibit violent or aggressive behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trauma and looked after children</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-and-looked-after-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-and-looked-after-children/</guid>
      <description>FL - Fiona Lettice
CG - Christine Gordon
KW - Karen Wallace
How do we deal with trauma? Most of us have a reference point for what is &amp;lsquo;safe&amp;rsquo; which allows us to make sense of traumatic events (for example a car crash) and provides a framework to deal with it. Looked after or adoptive children often have no such reference point which makes it difficult for them and their parents to deal with trauma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to be a radical?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-radical/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-it-mean-to-be-a-radical/</guid>
      <description>AM - Angela Morgan
On the 30th of October 2014, Iriss held its annual AGM, which featured guest speaker, Angela Morgan, Chief Executive at Includem. Includem is an organisation that provides intensive support services for Scotland&amp;rsquo;s most vulnerable young people. Her presentation was on the question, &amp;lsquo;what does it mean to be a radical?&amp;rsquo;
AM Good evening everybody, I am very pleased to be here and I appreciate the invitation from Iriss to address you and I would want to say that in terms of our relationship with Iriss, both in terms of the support that Includem receive through Alison being a member of our board and indeed our connection with your projects, we find it incredibly helpful in terms of our commitment to improvement, so you really do play a unique and very important role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships Matter</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/relationships-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/relationships-matter/</guid>
      <description>GR - Gayle Rice
GR Relationships Matter is a project run by Iriss, and we wanted to look specifically at difficulties that workers from a range of different services experience in terms of keeping in contact with young people who are leaving care.
We have read in the literature and we have spoken to workers and young people have brought it up, time and time again, that there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of difficulties maintaining relationships that they would like to continue as they transition and become inter-dependent and are moving in and out of different communities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. Reflections on the project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-reflections-on-the-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-reflections-on-the-project/</guid>
      <description>BD - Professor Bridget Daniel
The Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential child care. Bridget Daniel is Professor of Social Work at the University of Stirling, she pooled together the main messages from the original Food Practices research as well as the Food for Thought project. She highlighted the value in combining practice based evidence with academic research adding a sprinkling of the day to day experiences of children and young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. The experience of partnership and co-production</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-the-experience-of-partnership-and-co-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-the-experience-of-partnership-and-co-production/</guid>
      <description>JA - Jane Alcorn
LS - Laura Steckley
Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling, into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential child care. Jane Alcorn, of Foster Care Associates, explains her experience in being part of the project, in particular working with academics. She mentions the difference between an evidence based practice and practice based evidence. Jane is followed by Laura Steckley of the University of Strathclyde who reflects on the pros and cons of co-production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. The food and care study</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-the-food-and-care-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-the-food-and-care-study/</guid>
      <description>SP - Samantha Punch
Professor Samantha Punch of the University of Stirling summarised the original research project, the use of food and food practices in residential child care in Scotland. This project gave rise to the Food for Thought project. She describes the research questions, the findings and how they set about putting the findings into practice.
SP &amp;hellip; on a very broad thing, we weren&amp;rsquo;t interested in nutrition and healthy eating or eating disorders and whilst these things are important and they may have emerged as important, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t our key focus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought. What it means in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-what-it-means-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-what-it-means-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>RE - Ruth Edmond
RG - Robbie Gilligan
The routines and the rituals that surround food, shopping, preparing, cooking, serving, clearing up, are important parts of our lives, yet often we fail to recognise as symbolic or hidden meanings. The Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential childcare. The project has created a variety of tools and training materials which encourage reflection and strengthen the use of knowledge about food and looked after children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food for Thought: the contexts of care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-the-contexts-of-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-for-thought-the-contexts-of-care/</guid>
      <description>RE - Ruth Edmond
RG - Robbie Gilligan
The routines and the rituals that surround food, shopping, preparing, cooking, serving, clearing up, are important parts of our lives, yet often we fail to recognise as symbolic or hidden meanings. The Food for Thought project grew out of research undertaken by the University of Stirling into the symbolic role of food in foster and residential childcare. The project has created a variety of tools and training materials which encourage reflection and strengthen the use of knowledge about food and looked after children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residential child care in Bangladesh</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/residential-child-care-in-bangladesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/residential-child-care-in-bangladesh/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
TI - Tuhinul Islam
IW Tuhinul Islam is from Bangladesh. Currently he is a Consultant with Action Aid and a part time academic, also working with an NGO for Child Protection. As an under-graduate in Bangladesh studying forestry, he did voluntary work with slum dwellers and street children often using recreational singing and dancing techniques to help inspire the desire to learn. Seeing the harsh world of these children growing up in brothels shocked him and he decided this was where he wanted to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looked after young people and home supervision requirements</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looked-after-young-people-and-home-supervision-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looked-after-young-people-and-home-supervision-requirements/</guid>
      <description>JF - John Paul Fitzpatrick
Young people who are looked after at home or are under a Home Supervision requirement make up the largest proportion of young people who are looked after. They have the poorest educational outcomes compared to other groups, yet have been largely neglected by research. John Paul Fitzpatrick of CELCIS, the Centre for Excellence for Looked After Children in Scotland, has studied this group as part of his PhD research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Widening access to higher education for looked after young people</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/widening-access-to-higher-education-for-looked-after-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/widening-access-to-higher-education-for-looked-after-young-people/</guid>
      <description>NM - Neil Maclennan
JG - Jonathan Gray
SM - Susan Mueller
GC - Graham Connolly
Learning Enhancement and Academic Development in supporting students from a looked after background, hosted by Neil Maclennan, Jonathan Gray, Susan Mueller and Graham Connolly
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland Social Services.
On 25th January 2013, the Centre for Learning Enhancement and Academic Development at Glasgow Caledonian University, and CELCIS, the Centre for Excellent for Looked After Children in Scotland, joined forces to review progress in relation to supporting students from a looked after background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Educating looked after young people: Aspire Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/educating-looked-after-young-people-aspire-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/educating-looked-after-young-people-aspire-scotland/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
FS - Francis Scott
PN - Paul Neilson
IW Aspire provides high quality residential care and education for children and young people aged between 8 and 17. Aspire Education is based in Kilbirnie, Ayrshire, in a converted cinema which is also home to a number of community facilities including a cafe, gym and games hall to which the school has access. In fact these facilities play an important part in the education programme - helping the young people integrate with the local community and learning about trust and respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Involving young people: messages from research</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/involving-young-people-messages-from-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/involving-young-people-messages-from-research/</guid>
      <description>HW - Helen Whincup
Helen Whincup, teaching fellow at the University of Stirling, reflects on a qualitative study entitled &amp;lsquo;Involving Young People Messages from Research&amp;rsquo; which examines how young people feel involved or not in assessment and decision making. It was recorded at a Scottish Childcare Protection meeting on the 30th of April 2012.
HW This morning is thinking about some of the messages from research about what children have said about their feelings about being involved and I will also be drawing on the research that I have been doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care and permanence planning for looked after children in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-and-permanence-planning-for-looked-after-children-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-and-permanence-planning-for-looked-after-children-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GH - Gillian Henderson
MS - Michael Schaffer
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Gillian Henderson and Michael Schaffer, recorded on 16th January 2012.
MS I&amp;rsquo;m Michael Schaffer and I am Head of Practice &amp;amp; Policy within SCRA.
GH I&amp;rsquo;m Gillian Henderson and I am the Information Research Manager within SCRA and I did this research with my colleagues Lucy Hanson and India Whitehead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food and food practices in residential care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-and-food-practices-in-residential-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/food-and-food-practices-in-residential-care/</guid>
      <description>RE - Ruth Emond
SP - Sam Punch
RE My background is as a residential social workers and I had went on to do my PhD looking at young people in residential care and how they formed friends and peer relationships. And as part of that I lived in a residential unit for a year to undertake the research - and one of the things that became very apparent as a kind of pseudo resident was the significance of food and how much of a part food played in the day to day life of both the children and of the adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing up in Scotland (GUS)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/growing-up-in-scotland-gus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/growing-up-in-scotland-gus/</guid>
      <description>PB - Paul Bradshaw
Okay, so the study that I worked on is called &amp;lsquo;Growing Up In Scotland&amp;rsquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s a longitudinal study &amp;hellip; a longitudinal birth and child cohort study. So we are basically covering or tracking several groups of children from their early childhood, into sort of middle childhood, hopefully into adolescence and maybe beyond. It&amp;rsquo;s a study that is funded by Scottish government, funded by the Education Directorate, so a lot of what we do in the study is directed at producing evidence that can be used to inform policy making directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A RIGHT blether with Scotland&#39;s Commissioner for Children and Young People (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-right-blether-with-scotlands-commissioner-for-children-and-young-people-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-right-blether-with-scotlands-commissioner-for-children-and-young-people-part-1/</guid>
      <description>KB - Katie Brown
Part 1 of a talk by Katie Brown, recorded on 6th January 2012.
Welcome to the Iriss podcast. You are listening to a talk as part of the Childcare and Protection Research Collection, a partnership of Iriss and the Scottish Childcare and Protection Network. This talk was recorded on 6th January 2012. Katie Brown speaks about &amp;lsquo;A RIGHT Blether&amp;rsquo;.
KB My name is Katie Brown - I am Head of Participation and Education at the Office of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Commissioner for Children and Young People - the post is currently held by Tam Baillie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A RIGHT blether with Scotland&#39;s Commissioner for Children and Young People (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-right-blether-with-scotlands-commissioner-for-children-and-young-people-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-right-blether-with-scotlands-commissioner-for-children-and-young-people-part-2/</guid>
      <description>KB - Katie Brown
Part 2 of a talk by Katie Brown, recorded on 6th January 2012
KB So we had the &amp;lsquo;Tell Tam Tour&amp;rsquo;. So very exciting, very successful - there&amp;rsquo;s the man himself and there&amp;rsquo;s access to him.
Then we rolled out the next part of the journey which was called &amp;lsquo;Right Brilliant Things&amp;rsquo;, and this was focused on ensuring that we were asking children and young people not only about what they think should improve in the lives of children and young people, but actually what they themselves perceived as really important parts of their lives to celebrate - what they thought was happening really well for children and young people in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
