<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outcomes on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/outcomes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outcomes on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/outcomes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording and measuring outcomes: Carr Gomm</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recording-and-measuring-outcomes-carr-gomm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recording-and-measuring-outcomes-carr-gomm/</guid>
      <description>AT - Andrew Thomson
J - Jill
L - Louise
Recent policy and practice shifts towards personal outcomes present a number of opportunities and challenges for those who provide human services in Scotland. Carr Gomm, which describes itself as a person centred organisation that supports people to lead their lives safely and to do the things they want to do, has developed its own conversation based outcome measurement tool. Their system is designed to capture and track the personal outcomes of the people they support and link these to the wider local and national outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An inspector&#39;s view: quantifying intervention and outcomes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/an-inspectors-view-quantifying-intervention-and-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/an-inspectors-view-quantifying-intervention-and-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>EM - Emma McWilliam
SCCPN Seminar 20th and 21st April 2011. Thursday 21st April, 11.15am - 11.45am
Longitudinal research: measuring child well-being, outcomes and interventions from multi-disciplinary perspectives.
Introduction
EM For the past four and a half years, I have been working as an inspector in the multi-disciplinary Services for Children team based in HMIE which from the 1.4.11 transferred to SCSWIS. The main focus of my work has been joint inspections of services to protect children.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>