<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kerry Musselbrook on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/kerry-musselbrook/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kerry Musselbrook on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:30:32 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/kerry-musselbrook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc in Disaster Interventions and Humanitarian Aid: Lena Dominelli</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/msc-in-disaster-interventions-and-humanitarian-aid-lena-dominelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:30:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/msc-in-disaster-interventions-and-humanitarian-aid-lena-dominelli/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KM - Kerry Musselbrook
LM - Lena Dominelli
MD Lena Dominelli is Professor of Social Work at the University of Stirling and Chair of the International Association of Schools of Social Work (IASSW) Disaster Intervention, Climate Change and Sustainability Committee. Kerry Musselbrook from Iriss had a conversation with her about the new MSc in Disaster Interventions and Humanitarian Aid at University of Stirling, why this matters, and what it means for social work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gypsy, Roma and Traveller history: Davie Donaldson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/gypsy-roma-and-traveller-history-davie-donaldson/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 16:05:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/gypsy-roma-and-traveller-history-davie-donaldson/</guid>
      <description>KM - Kerry Musselbrook
DD - Davie Donaldson
KM Today I have with me Davie Donaldson, who identifies as a Scottish traveller from Perthshire. He&amp;rsquo;s a graduate of Aberdeen University, like myself, and is someone with a keen interest in culture and community relations. Davie is a social justice campaigner and is founder of Progress in Dialogue, a social enterprise that advocates dialogue between communities one conversation at a time. So today is a chance to have another one of those conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership in a crisis</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-in-a-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 15:11:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-in-a-crisis/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KM - Kerry Musselbrook
SS - Sue Stockdale
MD Sue Stockdale works with leaders and organisations to help them achieve exceptional performance. She has an in-depth understanding of motivation and leadership, gleaned from her decades of experience in business, adventure and sport. She offers inspirational presentations, leadership development programmes and coaching. She very kindly gave us her time to talk about leadership during the Covid-19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents with learning disabilities</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/parents-with-learning-disabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/parents-with-learning-disabilities/</guid>
      <description>KM - Kerry Musselbrook
AMi - Andy Miller
AMu - Amanda Muir
BW - Bianca Wood
DB - David Barr
GM - Gillian McIntrye
KM Morning everyone it&amp;rsquo;s Learning Disability Week this week and today we are here to focus ton parents with learning disabilities. Today we are joined by a range of people, so welcome. We have Bianca Wood, People First Scotland, an organisation that works to support people with learning disabilities, to have more choice and control and Bianca is Chairperson of the People First Scotland Parents Group, a self-advocacy group that has been meeting for over ten years now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>