<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lisa Pattoni on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/lisa-pattoni/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lisa Pattoni on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/lisa-pattoni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From strength to strength</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/from-strength-to-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/from-strength-to-strength/</guid>
      <description>LP - Lisa Pattoni
JM - John Moody
DD - David Delaney
DR - Deborah Reid
In 2012, Iriss undertook a project focused on understanding how an assets based approach could improve mental health and wellbeing within East Dunbartonshire, focussing specifically on Kirkintilloch. East Dunbartonshire Association of Mental Health is now in the process of integrating personal asset mapping into WRAP - Wellness Recovery Action Plan. Iriss caught up with the team in East Dunbartonshire to discuss how the idea came about to integrate personal asset mapping into WRAP, what has happened, the feedback, learning outcomes and next steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assets-based approaches to intervention</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/assets-based-approaches-to-intervention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/assets-based-approaches-to-intervention/</guid>
      <description>LP - Lisa Pattoni
PM - Paul Morin
FG - Fiona Garven
JM - Jennifer McLean
I&amp;rsquo;m Lisa Pattoni, a Project Manager with the Iriss Innovation and Improvement Team. In this episode I will be looking at asset based approaches. An asset based approach means shifting the balance away from doing things to people in favour of doing things with people. Assets, or social assets, are things like personal skills, inner strength, knowledge and lived experiences - so things that people already possess that can be harnessed to help them deal with crisis, trauma or problems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
