<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edwina Grant on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/edwina-grant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edwina Grant on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/edwina-grant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Violent and aggressive children: caring for those who care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/violent-and-aggressive-children-caring-for-those-who-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/violent-and-aggressive-children-caring-for-those-who-care/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
CG - Christine Gordon
KW - Karen Wallace
Adoptive or foster parents often believe they have failed and blame themselves for their children&amp;rsquo;s violent or aggressive behaviour. It is important that professionals are &amp;lsquo;trauma aware&amp;rsquo; and dot reinforce these feelings. In this episode, Edwina Grant, Chair of Scottish Attachment in Action talks to Christine Gordon and Karen Wallace of Adapt Scotland about caring for those who care for children who exhibit violent or aggressive behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters: in play, SAIA Conference 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-in-play-saia-conference-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-in-play-saia-conference-2014/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
Theraplay is a child and family therapy aimed at enhancing and building attachment, self-esteem and trust in others. In this keynote address to the Scottish Attachment in Action Conference in December 2014, Edwina Grant explains the importance of play - the building block of human development, and explains the relationship between Dyadic Development Psychotherapy and Theraplay.
EG A little bit about me and Dyadic Developmental Practice, because DDP and Theraplay have a great deal in common I think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attachment focused therapy for children and young people</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/attachment-focused-therapy-for-children-and-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/attachment-focused-therapy-for-children-and-young-people/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
DH - Dan Hughes
Dan Hughes is an specialist in dyadic developmental psychotherapy, an approach that is gaining momentum in Scotland as an effective intervention for children and young people in residential care, as well as children who are adopted or are in foster care and children have experienced abuse, neglect or trauma in their early years.
Dan is a regular visitor to Scotland and we caught up with him in September 2012 in Glasgow during a four day workshop organised by Scottish Attachment in Action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
