<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Donald Macleod on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/donald-macleod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Donald Macleod on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/donald-macleod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Unlocking the potential in our communities - George Thomson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-unlocking-the-potential-in-our-communities-george-thomson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-unlocking-the-potential-in-our-communities-george-thomson/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
GT - George Thomson
DM It is my pleasure to tell you that today is about unlocking the potential in our communities. Are we making the most effective use of all that our communities can offer? How might new partnerships improve the choice and availability of short breaks? Where is the potential for developing new opportunities? Our aim today is to consider opportunities to develop alternative approaches to short break provision but tap into the wider community resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Getting there - Roy McConkey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-getting-there-roy-mcconkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-getting-there-roy-mcconkey/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
RM - Roy McConkey
DM Well it is now my pleasure to introduce Professor Roy McConkey, who is the Emeritus Professor from Ulster University in Ireland. Roy is going to provide a personal, retrospective look at the progress of policy and practice around short breaks and respite care. We all know that progress can feel frustratingly slow at times and it&#39;s not always even, as Steve was just reminding us, it can be up and down and up and down a bit and sometimes we lose sight of what the long-term pattern has been.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: No limits - Jamie Andrew</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-no-limits-jamie-andrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-no-limits-jamie-andrew/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
JA - Jamie Andrew
DM We keep climbing up. So, we&#39;re delighted to be able to welcome Jamie Andrew. He&#39;s going to inspire us I&#39;m sure, and challenge us to look at the barriers that get in the way of progress and to believe in the influence we can exert individually and collectively to achieve our goal. So, as I said earlier, you&#39;re joy-givers, you&#39;re hope-givers, you&#39;re the people who make a huge difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Reframing respite - Maureen Flynn</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-reframing-respite-maureen-flynn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-reframing-respite-maureen-flynn/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
MF - Maureen Flynn
DM It is now my pleasure to introduce Maureen Flynn, who is Project Officer and Transition Support Co-ordinator with Interchange Illawarra Incorporated in New South Wales, Australia. Maureen will talk to us about the transformational changes taking place throughout Australia with a move to individualised funding packages of support for people with disability, their families and carers. It&#39;s known as consumer directed care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: The shifting sector - Amy MacFarlane</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-shifting-sector-amy-macfarlane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-shifting-sector-amy-macfarlane/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
AM - Amy McFarlane
DM My pleasure it is now to introduce Amy MacFarlane, who is the Chief Executive and founder of Recreation Respite Canada. As a provider of creative and flexible respite services, Amy will tell us about the latest developments in policy and practice in Canada and how this is changing people&#39;s expectations of where, when and how respite services are delivered. Amy will share her views on the need for traditional services to become more entrepreneurial and collaborative in their approach to service development and what this means in terms of new business skills and tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Adventures with dementia - Neil Mapes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
NP - Neil Mapes
DM Well it&#39;s now my pleasure to introduce Neil Mapes who&#39;s the Chief Executive of Dementia Adventure. Now Neil is the founder and co-director of Dementia Adventure, which is an awarding winning community interest company and charity, which specialises in supporting people with dementia and their families, to have adventure experiences. Neil will share his own thoughts about how we traditionally respond to those diagnosed with dementia and the barriers we need to overcome if we are to help those with dementia and their family enjoy their lives to the full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Anything to declare? - Jaynie Mitchell</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-anything-to-declare-jaynie-mitchell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-anything-to-declare-jaynie-mitchell/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
JM - Jaynie Mitchell
DM The theme of today is to look at ways in which we can enable people to develop policies and practices to maximise opportunities for people to experience real choice and control over their short breaks. Today we are looking at unlocking the potential of family and friends. What are the different ways we can support people to achieve the breaks they want?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Caring in Scotland - Aileen Campbell</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-caring-in-scotland-aileen-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-caring-in-scotland-aileen-campbell/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
AC - Aileen Campbell
DM Now if we are to make progress then it is absolutely critical that our sector has a positive relationship with our Government. Good legislation and policy is key to creating the conditions that are needed that will help us to develop the best provision that we can. I think in Scotland we are really fortunate in that we have a Government and we have a Parliament that goes to great lengths to be as open and as accessible as it can so that people really feel that they have the opportunity to engage directly with the key decisions that will affect their lives and there is a lot happening in Scotland at the moment concerning new Laws that will help to strengthen the support available to unpaid carers and to people that they care for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: ISBA values and themes - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
DN - Don Williamson
DM Well it&#39;s my pleasure to introduce Don Williamson who is the President of the International Short Breaks Association. There must be something about 10. It&#39;s the 10th ISBA and I noticed that Don has been the Shared Care of Scotland for 10 years and he&#39;s done a fantastic job in spearheading the team and many, many hands have been involved in bringing all this together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Welcome - Donald Macleod</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-welcome-donald-macleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-welcome-donald-macleod/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
DM Ceud Mìle Fàilte, a hundred thousand welcomes as we say in Gaelic. To those of you who have come from 17 other nations. Failte gu na h-Alba, welcome to Scotland and to you all Failte gu Dun Eideann, welcome to Edinburgh. Maidin mhaith, good morning. My name is Domhnall Eoin ma&#39;klaud, Donald Ian Macleod and it&#39;s a pleasure to stand here today to welcome you to the 10th International Short Breaks Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>