<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adult social care on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/adult-social-care/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adult social care on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:31:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/adult-social-care/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kinections: what community means for those in care homes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/kinections-what-community-means-for-care-homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/kinections-what-community-means-for-care-homes/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
ER - Edel Roddy
AJ - Dr Anna Jack-Waugh
MD Kinections was a three-year collaborative research project working with care homes across East Ayrshire to explore what community means for people who live, work and visit care homes with a particular focus on the experiences of people living with dementia. The project was a My Home Life Scotland initiative, lead by a team of researchers at the University of the West of Scotland and was funded by the Life Changes Trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adult social care recruitment campaign</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/adult-social-care-recruitment-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 08:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/adult-social-care-recruitment-campaign/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LG - Lorraine Gray
There&amp;rsquo;s More to Care Than Caring is a Scottish government led adult social care recruitment campaign which was launched in January 2020. It aims to encourage people to take up a career in care. Michelle from Iriss had a conversation with Lorraine Gray, Chief Executive of the Scottish Social Services Council about the purpose of the campaign, the importance of adult social care work and how people can get involved in promoting the campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared Lives</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/shared-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/shared-lives/</guid>
      <description>LS - Lesley Stevenson
SE - Shona Elvin
AK - Asif Khan
BB - Bill Black
ES - Elaine Stockdale
BH - Ben Hall
LS Today&amp;rsquo;s discussion on Shared Lives in Scotland, we have with us Shona Elvin who is family placement assessor for Cornerstone, we have Asif Khan, who is a Shared Life service user with Quarriers, we have Bill Black, who is a Shared Lives carer for Cornerstone, Elaine Stockdale who is a Shared Lives carer with Shared Lives Moray, Ben Hall, who is Scotland Development Manager for Shared Lives Plus and I&amp;rsquo;m Lesley Stevenson, Scotland Development Officer for Shared Lives Plus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit for the Future in Argyll and Bute</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future-in-argyll-and-bute/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future-in-argyll-and-bute/</guid>
      <description>RM - Rhiann McLean
JR - Jim Robb
JC - Jackie Connelly
AA - Ann Austin
RM In 2014, the Fit for the Future project worked with Argyll &amp;amp; Bute Council and local independent sector providers to explore new approaches to the commissioning of care at home. Fit for the Future is a joint Scottish Care and Iriss project which aims to inspire better outcomes for older people by working with independent sector providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover Care Opinion</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discover-care-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discover-care-opinion/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JM - James Munro
IO - Irene Oldfather
GA - Gina Alexander
GD - Grant Douglas
RL - Richard Lyall
On the 13th of November, Iriss.fm attended Discover Care Opinion, an event to launch, as well as discussing explore Care Opinion, the sister site to patient Opinion in Scotland. James Munro, Chief Executive of Patient Opinion, gave us the background on the initiative and its aims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we effectively engage with harder to reach older people?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-effectively-engage-with-harder-to-reach-older-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-effectively-engage-with-harder-to-reach-older-people/</guid>
      <description>VM - Vivien Moffat
SC - Sarah Currie
BM -Betty Milton
AT - Audrey Taylor
GP - Gerry Power
AM - Agnes McGroarty
Plan P: New approaches to prevention with older people is an Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter the advisory group records a group discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the fourth discussion - How can we effectively engage with hard to reach older people?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASSET (Age Specialist Services Emergency Team)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/asset-age-specialist-services-emergency-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/asset-age-specialist-services-emergency-team/</guid>
      <description>TM - Trudi Marshall
ASSET, Age Specialist Services Emergency Team, was set up in February 2012 and is based in Coathill Hospital in Coatbridge. The team is running at Hospital at Home service for people aged over 65. Hospital at Home is for people who require secondary care but who are cared for at their home or the place in which they normally live, rather than having to be admitted to a hospital ward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hospital to Home</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hospital-to-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hospital-to-home/</guid>
      <description>FM - Fiona Munro
PM - Peter McLeod
Hospital to Home is a project to design a pathway to support the transition from hospital to home for older people. Fiona Munro, the project lead, gives us an overview of Hospital to Home, progress to date and the final outcomes of the project.
FM Currently I am leading a 20 month project entitled Hospital to Home which ends in March 2015. The overall aim of this project is to design a pathway to support the transition from hospital to home for older people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What do we mean by prevention?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-do-we-mean-by-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-do-we-mean-by-prevention/</guid>
      <description>VM - Vivien Moffat
GW - Glenda Watt
BM - Betty Milton
IR - Irene Reid
DY - Derek Young
GP - Gerry Power
AM - Agnes McGroarty
Plan P, New Approaches to Prevention with older People, is an Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter, the Advisory Group records a group discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the third discussion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we ensure that older people are equal partners in developing preventative approaches?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-ensure-that-older-people-are-equal-partners-in-developing-preventative-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2014 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-can-we-ensure-that-older-people-are-equal-partners-in-developing-preventative-approaches/</guid>
      <description>VM - Vivien Moffat
IW - Irene Weeden
SC - Sarah Currie
GP - Gerry Power
AM - Agnes McGroarty
GW - Glenda Watt
BM - Betty Milton
VM Plan P - new approaches to prevention with older people is an Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter, the Project Advisory Group records a discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the second discussion and the topic is &amp;ldquo;How can we ensure that older people are equal partners in developing preventative approaches?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit for the Future</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
RM - Rhiann McLean
MD Rhiann McLean, Project Lead on the Fit for the Future project, was happy to speak to Iriss.fm about the project and progress to date. She firstly gives an overview of Fit for the Future and explains the main objectives.
RM Fit for the Future is a partnership project between Iriss and Scottish Care that is aiming to support the independent sector to embrace the challenges and opportunities in transforming support for older people, as laid out by the Reshaping Care for Older People Agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does prevention mean in an ageing population?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-prevention-mean-in-an-ageing-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-does-prevention-mean-in-an-ageing-population/</guid>
      <description>AT - Audrey Taylor
JR - Jackie Reid
JP - Jerry Power
IW - Irene Wheaton
EC - Emma Collins
DY - Derek Young
Plan P: New Approaches to prevention with older people, is a new Iriss project which addresses the issue of social isolation and loneliness amongst older people. Each quarter the project advisory group records a group discussion about a related aspect of prevention. This is the first discussion - &amp;lsquo;What does prevention mean in an ageing population?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
