<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Disability on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/disability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Disability on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/disability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ENABLE Works</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/enable-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/enable-works/</guid>
      <description>Michael: On this podcast I went to find out about ENABLE Works that is part of Scotland so I spoke to the Deputy Director of ENABLE Works, Lianne Williams, and also, I spoke to Mark Cuff who has got a learning disability and he told me more about his job.
Lianne: As an overview for the ENABLE Group, I guess I’ll start by saying that we’re the department ENABLE Works. So, we’re part of the ENABLE Scotland group which was founded in 1954 by five sets of parents of children who had learning disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disability: what’s the learning from Covid-19?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-whats-the-learning-from-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-whats-the-learning-from-covid19/</guid>
      <description>—
Michael: On this podcast I discover the impact on how Covid has affected people within the disability and the social care community. So first up I spoke to Health Journalist, and she specialises in Social Care for many years, Pennie Taylor, and I spoke to her about Covid and what we’ve learned so far.
So, Pennie, we’ve been in this kind of pandemic for coming up to two years now, but can I take you back to the years before this pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate change and disabled people</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/climate-change-and-disabled-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/climate-change-and-disabled-people/</guid>
      <description>Michael: On this podcast I went to find out how the climate change is impacting on people’s lives with a disability. We’re going to hear from Susie Fitton. Susie works for Inclusion Scotland and they were involved in the COP26 and they had a workshop also, at the conference as well. So, I spoke to her about the work that they’re doing from Inclusion Scotland.
So Susie, can you tell us what’s the Inclusion Scotland’s involvement in COP26?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Rights Town</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/human-rights-town/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/human-rights-town/</guid>
      <description>Michael: On this podcast, I went to find out about a new App that has been launched called the Human Rights Town App. It has been designed by the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability and also people with lived experience. So, I went to find out more about this App. I spoke to Oonagh Brown, who is the Human Rights Advisor of the Commission and also, I spoke to Fiona (… unclear) of the App team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus and people with learning disabilities</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/coronavirus-and-people-with-learning-disabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/coronavirus-and-people-with-learning-disabilities/</guid>
      <description>Michael: On this podcast I went to find out about a study that Glasgow University has undertaken. They’re interviewing people with learning disabilities about their Coronavirus. So, I was speaking to one of their researchers at Glasgow University, Roseann Maguire. Also, I spoke to one of their participants of this study, Sandy Stark.
So, Roseanne, tell us what this survey is about please.
Roseann: Well what it is, is, we wanted to provide data about the lives of the people with learning disabilities during the Covid pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adults with learning disabilities: economic outcomes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/adults-with-learning-disabilities-economic-outcomes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/adults-with-learning-disabilities-economic-outcomes/</guid>
      <description>Michael: On this episode, I went to speak to Rob Watts. Rob is one of the Researchers of Fraser of Allander Institute, and they’re carrying out a new project on adults with a learning disability in Scotland. So I was asking Rob about his research and the work that they do.
So Rob, first of all, can you tell us about the Fraser of Allander Institute and what kind of work that you do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stay Up Late</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/stay-up-late/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/stay-up-late/</guid>
      <description>Michael: On this episode with Iriss, I went to find out about a new campaign to Scotland called Stay Up Late Scotland where I spoke to the secretary, Keith Etherington and the Vice Chair, William Rae about their new campaign.
Keith can you tell us a bit about what Stay Up Late is?
Keith: Stay Up Late is a campaign about people with learning disabilities and or any other additional needs, having the right to stay up and get support at the right time of day for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mecoco Meaningful Contribution in your Community</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mecoco-meaningful-contribution-in-your-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mecoco-meaningful-contribution-in-your-community/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JT - Jenny Trott
MM On this podcast, I went to find out about a social enterprise based in Ayrshire called Mecoco. I went to speak to Jenny Trott and found out more about the enterprise.
MM So, what is your social enterprise all about?
JT So, Mecoco stands for meaningful contribution in your community and it’s a social enterprise that I set up a couple of years ago, really because my son who was approaching school leaving age and has complex learning and physical disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The role of sport in communities in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-role-of-sport-in-communities-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-role-of-sport-in-communities-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DF - David Ferguson
On this next podcast for Iriss, I went to speak to David Ferguson. David is one of the executive Directors at The Observatory for Sport in Scotland. They do a lot of research into sport and disability sport in Scotland.
MM So, David can you tell us a bit about your work, just give us an overview of what you do?
DF Yes Michael, The Observatory for Sport in Scotland was started in 2016 in response to the decline in sport participation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sight Scotland Veterans</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sight-scotland-veterans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 16:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sight-scotland-veterans/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AC - Alison Cairns
MM On this podcast you will hear me speaking to Alison Cairns. Alison is from Sight Scotland Veterans and she is a practicing lead for the outreach team and she’s going to tell us more about the service.
MM Okay, so Alison you were called Royal Blind and Scottish War Blinded, so why did you change your name for?
AC Yeah, that’s right Michael, we changed our name from Scottish Way Blinded to Sight Scotland Veterans in October of this year and whilst the charity changed its name, we still continue to support veterans with a sight loss living in Scotland but we hope our new name will allow us to reach even more veterans in the coming months and years indeed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neatebox</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/neatebox/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 16:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/neatebox/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GN - Gavin Neate
MM Now on this podcast I went to find out about a company called Neatebox, where I spoke to the CEO of Neatebox, Gavin Neate. So, Gavin, why did you set up this company in the first place?
GN Hi, Michael. Yeah, so Neatebox was set up in 2011. I was working for Guide Dogs for the Blind at the time. I was a guide dog mobility instructor, so my job was training people how to use guide dogs, and one of the things that I had noticed in the early 2000s was that people were turning up to train with guide dogs and they had mobile phone technology, or they were using email more or they were using online social media, and I just realised that with the mobile phone, technology was going to be something that they were increasingly going to be able to use and it was going to become cheaper and cheaper the more people that have it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Options Understood: Danielle Farrel</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/your-options-understood-danielle-farrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 15:18:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/your-options-understood-danielle-farrel/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DF - Dr Danielle Farrel
MM On this podcast for Iriss I went to interview Dr Danielle Farrel. Danielle Farrel owns her own company called &amp;lsquo;Your Options Understood&amp;rsquo;, so I went to find out more about it. So Danielle, why did you set up your business?
DF I set Your Options Understood up back in 2015 after I&amp;rsquo;d finished my PhD and graduated from university. I guess I set it up for two reasons really.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passion4Social</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passion4social/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 12:41:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passion4social/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
TC - Thiago Carmo
MM On this podcast I went to hear about an organisation called &amp;ldquo;Passion4Social&amp;rdquo;. So I spoke to Thiago Carmo, the marketing manager and senior designer of the organisation. Okay, so &amp;ldquo;Passion4Social&amp;rdquo; is a creative agency with a difference. Can you tell us what the difference is?
TC Sure. Well, &amp;ldquo;Passion4Social&amp;rdquo; is a creative agency that we say is with a difference, because we are a social enterprise and our mission is to create sustainable employment for people with disabilities and the ones that have a long-term health condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting people with disabilities during the Covid-19 crisis</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-people-with-disabilities-during-the-covid-19-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 09:12:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-people-with-disabilities-during-the-covid-19-crisis/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CM - Colin Millar
PR - Pete Richmond
ES - Emma Soanes
MD On this podcast we&amp;rsquo;re going to hear from a number of different disability organisations and we&amp;rsquo;re going to be speaking about how they are coping and dealing with the current crisis. So first up we&amp;rsquo;re going to hear from an organisation called SPAEN. They are the Scottish Personal Employers Network. The network supports people with disabilities and long-term conditions in improving the use of self-directed support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indepen-dance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/indepen-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 14:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/indepen-dance/</guid>
      <description>MM Michael McEwan
KA Karen Anderson
A Adam
MM On this podcast you will hear me speaking to some people from Indepen-dance. Indepen-dance is an award winning, inclusive dance company for disabled and non-disabled people to enjoy and fulfil their prospects through dance. So, I got to meet one of the team members of the company, Adam, who enjoys dancing and also I caught up with the founding member of the company, Karen Anderson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KOR Records</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/kor-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 08:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/kor-records/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GH - Geraldine Heaney
MM On this podcast we will hear from the co-director of KOR Records, Geraldine Heaney. KOR Records is an independent record label that creates music projects for young people with additional support needs. So tell us a bit about KOR Records.
GH So KOR Records is a small record label, community interest company, and we run projects in experimental noise and music for young people with additional support needs, and that might be in schools or in community centres or in an arts venue, anywhere that people want us to come and do it really.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humans of Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/humans-of-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 08:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/humans-of-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AM - Angela Miller
RL - Raven Laine
MB - Michael Byrne
MM On this episode on Iriss.fm I went along to The Alliance Scotland, where The Alliance run a project called the &amp;lsquo;Humans of Scotland&amp;rsquo;, and we&amp;rsquo;re going to be hearing from a couple of people that participated in the &amp;lsquo;Humans of Scotland&amp;rsquo;. Raven Laine, Michael Byrne, and also first off we hear from project manager, Angela Miller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Include Me 2 Club</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/include-me-2-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 09:49:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/include-me-2-club/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
PM - Paul McIlvenny
On this podcast, you will hear me in conversation with Paul McIlvenny. Paul McIlvenny is the chairperson of Include Me 2. Now, Include Me 2 is a small voluntary led charity working with children, young people and adults with additional support needs and disabilities.
MM So, why did you set up Include Me 2 in the first place?
PM Include Me 2 Club kind of came about, Michael, because both my wife and I worked in the social care field and the community development field and Ashley used to come home at night complaining all the time about how there was a lack of opportunities for the people that she supported, that she had to drive from one end of Glasgow to the other end of Glasgow, by the time she got there it was time to get your jacket off, have a quick drink, have a quick dance, get your jacket on and head home due to traffic and stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Life I Want</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-life-i-want/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 08:19:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-life-i-want/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DM - Donna Marie
MM So on this episode of Iriss.fm we are going to hear about a new project called &amp;lsquo;The Life I Want&amp;rsquo;, and where I went to speak to Donna Marie. Donna Marie is the coordinator for &amp;lsquo;The Life I Want&amp;rsquo;. So tell us about &amp;lsquo;The Life I Want&amp;rsquo; and why is it important for people with a learning disability?
DM Well, &amp;lsquo;The Life I Want&amp;rsquo; is a partnership in Greater Glasgow and Clyde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gig Buddies</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/gig-buddies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 08:34:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/gig-buddies/</guid>
      <description>MM Michael McEwan
SM Samuel Magg
KF Kerry Ferguson
On this episode I went to find out about a project in Scotland called, Gig Buddies, Gig Buddies for like music fans who have a learning disability where volunteers who shares a similar interest so, I went to find out about this kind of work and I went to speak to Kerry Ferguson and Samuel Maggs.
MM So, Sam what is Gig Buddies and why is there a need for this project?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People First</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-first/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RS - Rosie Smith
MM On this episode I went to find out about People First. People First works with and supports people with learning disabilities to have more choice and control over their lives. So I went along to the Glasgow office and I spoke to one of the members of People First, Rosie Smith. So Rosie, what is People First?
RS People First is a national independent self-advocacy organisation of people with learning disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IASSIDD 2019 Conference</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/iassidd-2019-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/iassidd-2019-conference/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM On this podcast we hear about a World Congress coming to Glasgow called the IASSSID Congress, from 6-9 August. So, I went to interview Linda Mitchell, Linda works for the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities and is on the local organising committee for the congress. So, Linda can you give us an overview of the whole event?
LM I can Michael. So, the IASSIDD World Congress happens every 3 years and IASSIDD stands for the International Association for the Scientific Study of Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waterbaby Arts</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/waterbaby-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/waterbaby-arts/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RF - Ruth Foster
MG - Maureen Graham
SG - Sandy Graham
MM On this episode on Iriss.fm we hear about an arts organisation called Waterbaby Arts and we&amp;rsquo;re going to be hearing from two of the dancers that take part. It&amp;rsquo;s Maureen Graham and Sandy Graham but first up we&amp;rsquo;re going to speak to Ruth Foster, Ruth Foster is the tutor of (&amp;hellip; unclear) Dance baby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving Miss Daisy</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/driving-miss-daisy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/driving-miss-daisy/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AO - Ann Overdijking
CM - Christine McIntyre
MM On this podcast, we hear about a new service: a service called Driving Miss Daisy. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be hearing from Ann Overdijking and Christine McIntyre, who will tell us more. So, Ann can you tell us about Driving Miss Daisy?
AO Yes, I&amp;rsquo;d love to Michael, thank you. Well Driving Miss Daisy, it&amp;rsquo;s a driving and companion service and we offer a safe, very friendly and reliable driving service and people say, &amp;ldquo;What is it you actually do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Security Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-security-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-security-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RM - Rachael McKechnie
MM On this next podcast, I went to find out more about the all new Social Security Scotland where I was talking to Rachael McKechnie and first off, I asked her: what is Social Security Scotland?
RM Thank you Michael so, Social Security Scotland is the organisation that&amp;rsquo;s been established to deliver a subset of benefits that are being moved from the UK government up to the Scottish government so, those benefits are largely for people with disabilities so, the things like personal independence payment, disability living allowance, the carers, so, carers allowance is coming up and then another smaller number of benefits that are there to support people who are on a low income that need a bit of help to meet additional cost so, that&amp;rsquo;s things like the Sure Start Maternity Grant, DWP&amp;rsquo;s funeral payment and cold weather payments and winter fuel payments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week launch</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-launch/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LC - Libby Clement
MM On this episode of Iriss.fm I went to find out about this year&amp;rsquo;s Learning Disability Week, the launch of Learning Disability Week was held at Project Ability in Glasgow and the National Learning Disability Week takes place from Monday the 13th to Sunday the 19th of May 2019. On this podcast I spoke to the winner of the British Bake Off, James Morton and also one of the award nominees from the learning disability awards last year, Jonathon McKendry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disability Equality Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-equality-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-equality-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
IB - Ian Buchanan
Michael McEwan speaks to Ian Buchanan about Disability Equality Scotland, focusing more specifically on Disability Access Panels. As the umbrella body for Access Panels in Scotland, Disability Equality Scotland offers support and training opportunities to help Access Panels operate efficiently, link together as a network and learn from each other.
MM We are now joined by Ian Buchanan, who is the Access Engagement Officer at Disability Equality Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outspoken Arts</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outspoken-arts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outspoken-arts/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
ST - Steven Thomson
Michael McEwan speaks to Steven Thomson, Creative Director and CEO of Outspoken Arts, a professional and creative organisation interested in work which references cutting edge social issues such as creative learning for young and vulnerable people, stories of migration and asylum, issues affecting LGBT people, disability, ethnicity, creative ageing and social health and well-being. The organisation represents diverse communities and recognises that equality, equal and human rights are now very much the focus of mainstream society, civic and organisational culture and its shifting sense of identity plays an increasingly influential role in this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access to Politics</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-to-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-to-politics/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
EY - Ethan Young
MM On this podcast on Iriss.fm I went to hear about a new project called Access to Politics. It is a fund to help people with a disability into the mainstream politics and on this series I spoke to Ethan Young from Inclusion Scotland. Now Ethan is a Civic Participation Officer and I spoke to him about access to politics. So, what is Access to Politics Ethan?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outside the Box</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outside-the-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/outside-the-box/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JK - Jill Keegan
MM On this episode I went to hear about an organisation called Outside the Box, where I was talking to Jill Keegan, who is the Community Development Adviser. The first question I asked her was, tell us a bit about Outside the Box.
JK Outside the Box is a community development support organisation. So, we are an equalities charity and we are based in Glasgow, but we work right across Scotland and now have also some links with England and Wales, with one of the really big projects we run called Rural Wisdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking Points in East Renfrewshire</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-points-in-east-renfrewshire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/talking-points-in-east-renfrewshire/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GT - Gerry Tougher
MM So, on this next episode for Iriss.fm I went along to East Renfrewshire to hear about a new piece of work called Talking Points and I spoke to Gerry Tougher. Now, Gerry Tougher is a public Engagement Officer of East Renfrewshire. So, can you tell us what is Talking Points?
GT Talking Points really is a new approach that we&amp;rsquo;re taking in East Renfrewshire, essentially Talking Points are places in your community where you can the advice and support you need to help you to do the things you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at Learning Disability Week</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looking-back-at-learning-disability-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/looking-back-at-learning-disability-week/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KM - Katie Morris
PO - Paul O&amp;rsquo;Kane
Michael McEwan, our roving reporter on disability issues attended a number of events over Learning Disability Week 2018 (14-20 May) and spoke to the organisers. We hear about &amp;lsquo;Be the Change&amp;rsquo; campaign created by Enable Scotland, Project Ability and Mind the Gap theatre performance organised by the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability (SCLD).
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Services podcast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2018</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2018/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM On this podcast we hear about this year&amp;rsquo;s Learning Disability week. Learning Disability week takes place between the 14th to the 20th of May and the theme for this years Learning Disability week is My Generation. We went along to the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities to find out more where we spoke to Linda Mitchell. Linda is a partnership and development manager of the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Am Me</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/i-am-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/i-am-me/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DC - Debbie Campbell
Megan - Megan Milligan
MM Now on Iriss.fm I went to I Am Me Scotland to find more about the charity, now I Am Me Scotland is a community partnership charity who is developing in Renfrewshire to raise awareness of a disability hate crime and on this podcast, you&amp;rsquo;ll hear me speaking to Debbie Campbell. Debbie Campbell is the project officer and committee member of I Am Me Scotland, but first up let&amp;rsquo;s hear from Megan Milligan who is the project assistant and she is the secretary from I Am Me Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paisley Disability Resource Centre:2</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre2/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JT - Jim Thompson
DT - Duncan Tomlinson
MM Now on part two of our special series called &amp;ldquo;Inside The Resource Centre&amp;rdquo;, I went along to speak to one of the participants of the group, Duncan Tomlinson, and he takes part in the movie makers group, but first up, we spoke to Jim Thompson. Now Jim Thompson is the co-ordinator for the movie makers and the music group, and he told us more about what happens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paisley Disability Resource Centre:1</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/paisley-disability-resource-centre1/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KC - Kevin Cantwell
BN - Billy Neil
B - Brenda
BW - Billy White
MM Okay, now on Iriss.fm we&amp;rsquo;re going to do a series about &amp;ldquo;Inside The Resource Centre&amp;rdquo;. A lot of people have got a stigma about people with a disability going to the Resource Centre. What can they do? What are they capable of? Well, in this series we&amp;rsquo;ll prove you wrong. This is part one of two of &amp;ldquo;Inside The Resource Centre&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Film Club</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-film-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/access-film-club/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JW - Jodie Wilkinson
MM Now on Iriss.fm we&amp;rsquo;re going to hear about a new project called Access Film Club, and we&amp;rsquo;re joined on Iriss fm by Jodie Wilkinson, the Public Engagement Officer, so thanks for joining us. So, can you tell us a bit about the Access Film Club?
JW Yeah, of course. Access Film Club is a monthly Autism-friendly screening that happens at Glasgow Film Theatre, and we began the journey in November 2014, and at the time we were working with a fantastic organisation called Scottish Autism, who helped us develop the film club into what we see today, and then last year we said goodbye to Scottish Autism and we continued working with the National Autistic Society Scotland, which has enabled us to continue running the monthly screenings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Care Collective</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-care-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-care-collective/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RG - Ruth Gallagher
LW - Lynn Wardle
CW - Colette Walker
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm we are going to hear about a new project called the Care Collective and we are joined by Ruth Gallagher, from Voluntary Action and we are joined by a carer and someone who has a disability as well, Colette Walker, and we are joined by Lynn Wardle from Thrive. So, we are going to hear about this exciting project, but I wanted to ask as well, first of all, if Ruth can give us a wee overview of what Voluntary Action is and what they provide?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden disabilities: Joseph Delaney</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-joseph-delaney/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-joseph-delaney/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JD - Joseph Delaney
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm on this series of Hidden Disabilities, we are going to be talking to Joseph Delaney. Joseph is on the autistic spectrum and Joseph is going to speak about his ups and downs of his journey. So, thanks Joseph for joining us. The first question, when did you become aware that you might be different?
JD Well when I went to mainstream primary school it was discovered I had a moderate learning disability, but even long before that, when I was in nursery school I had a short concentration span so I could only focus on something for a couple of minutes, then I would be away to something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hidden disabilities: Ryan Fleming</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-ryan-fleming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hidden-disabilities-ryan-fleming/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
RF - Ryan Fleming
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm, and this series of hidden disabilities, we are going to speak to Ryan Fleming about the barriers and challenges that he faces day to day. First of all, Ryan, going back to when you were younger, what obstacles did you face?
RF Well I faced quite a number of obstacles when I was young, my big one I would say, was when I actually started nursery school because I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t do it, it was far too much for me, the playing and all that, with other children, just simply did not happen and I don&amp;rsquo;t really think you got much help back then when I started, I mean you are talking the late 1990s here, you didn&amp;rsquo;t really get much support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parents with learning disabilities</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/parents-with-learning-disabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/parents-with-learning-disabilities/</guid>
      <description>KM - Kerry Musselbrook
AMi - Andy Miller
AMu - Amanda Muir
BW - Bianca Wood
DB - David Barr
GM - Gillian McIntrye
KM Morning everyone it&amp;rsquo;s Learning Disability Week this week and today we are here to focus ton parents with learning disabilities. Today we are joined by a range of people, so welcome. We have Bianca Wood, People First Scotland, an organisation that works to support people with learning disabilities, to have more choice and control and Bianca is Chairperson of the People First Scotland Parents Group, a self-advocacy group that has been meeting for over ten years now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2017</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2017/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CC - Chris Creegan (Chief Executive - Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities)
MM We are going by Chris Creegan, now Chris Creegan is the Chief Executive of the Scottish Commission for Learning Disabilities. Thanks for talking to us. First off, what is happening this year? What&amp;rsquo;s the theme?
CC Okay so, just a little bit about the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability, and I&amp;rsquo;ll explain what our role is and then talk to you about the theme for this year, yeah?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/unity-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/unity-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LG - Loretta Galloway
MM Ok, now on Iriss.fm we are joined by Loretta Galloway, the Service Manager for the Learning Disability Service here at Unity Enterprise. Now, she has come to tell us a bit about what her own service does, the Learning Disability Services, but first of all can you tell us an overview of what Unity Enterprise is?
LG Unity Enterprise is a social (&amp;hellip;unclear) Scotland down in Ayrshire and Inverclyde.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glasgow Disability Alliance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/glasgow-disability-alliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/glasgow-disability-alliance/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
BS - Brian Scott
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm, I&amp;rsquo;m here in the Glasgow Disability Alliance office and I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Brian Scott. Now Brian Scott is the Development Manager for the Alliance so thanks Brian&amp;hellip;
BS - Hi.
Male voice - &amp;hellip;for taking the time out to speak to us. So first of all give us a quick over view and a quick insight into what is Glasgow Disability Alliance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limelight Music</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/limelight-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/limelight-music/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GG - Gordon Goodall
MM Okay now at Iriss.fm we&amp;rsquo;re joined by Gordon Goodall the Director of Limelight and Gordon the first question would be what is Limelight?
GG Well basically Limelight&amp;rsquo;s an organisation that supports disabled musicians and provides professional training and employment with the largest employer of disabled musicians in Scotland and within that remit we also roll out a youth&amp;rsquo;s programme to primary schools and to primary schools with Autism units, vision impairment units and hearing impairment units to encourage children to look at ways of developing skills in music and also drama but mainly music, and the reason for this is so that they can get transferrable skills that can lead to employment in other stratospheres of the, of the world basically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Reframing respite - Maureen Flynn</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-reframing-respite-maureen-flynn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-reframing-respite-maureen-flynn/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
MF - Maureen Flynn
DM It is now my pleasure to introduce Maureen Flynn, who is Project Officer and Transition Support Co-ordinator with Interchange Illawarra Incorporated in New South Wales, Australia. Maureen will talk to us about the transformational changes taking place throughout Australia with a move to individualised funding packages of support for people with disability, their families and carers. It&amp;rsquo;s known as consumer directed care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C-Change</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/c-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/c-change/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CW - Cheryl Walker
MM OK and we&amp;rsquo;re at the C-Change office in Glasgow and we&amp;rsquo;re joined by Cheryl Walker. Now Cheryl Walker is a PR in Marketing, Development Officer at C-Change. So Cheryl, can you tell us first of all what is C-Change?
CW C-Change is a supported living organisation. We&amp;rsquo;ve been in existence for about 15 years now. We&amp;rsquo;re actually celebrating our 15 year anniversary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neighbourhood Networks</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/neighbourhood-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/neighbourhood-networks/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Lauren May
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we are in the Neighbourhood Networks office in Glasgow and we&amp;rsquo;re speaking to Lauren May who is the Network Manager for Glasgow. So, first of all, Lauren, can you tell us what is Neighbourhood Networks?
LM So, Neighbourhood Networks facilitates networks of peer support in communities for adults who have a learning disability, mental health problems, people who have physical disabilities as well or just generally anybody who is isolated in their community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2016</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2016/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Linda Mitchell
MM Okay now on Iriss.fm we are here at the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability with Linda Mitchell. Linda is the Learning and Development Manager for the Scottish Commission for Learning Disability and we&amp;rsquo;re here to speak to her about the 2016 Learning Disability Week that&amp;rsquo;s coming up in May. So first of all, Linda, why do we have Learning Disability Week?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Action on Hearing Loss Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/action-on-hearing-loss-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/action-on-hearing-loss-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DH - Delia Henry
This is Iriss.fm Internet radio for Scotland Social Services.
MM Now on Iriss.fm we are here at Action on Hearing Loss Scotland and I&amp;rsquo;m joined by the Director of the Scottish branch, Delia Henry. Delia thanks for giving us your time. First question would be what is Action on Hearing Loss?
DH Action on Hearing Loss is the biggest Charity in the UK who support deaf or hard of hearing people or importantly people with tenasis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disabled Access Day 2016</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disabled-access-day-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disabled-access-day-2016/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
KM - Kiki McDonald
MM Now on Iriss.fm I&amp;rsquo;m joined via Skype by the cofounder of Disabled Access Day Kiki McDonald and she&amp;rsquo;s going to tell us about what is Disability Access Day. So basically, welcome. The first question I would like to ask is, what is Disabled Access Day?
KM So Disabled Access Day is a day where venues are putting on events and incentives to encourage disabled people to come and try them out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Wesley Greer</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-wesley-greer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-wesley-greer/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
WG - Wes Greer
M Wes Greer talks to Michael McEwan about his life, from school through the highs and lows of breaking into the performing arts, currently Wes is working in a voluntary post at Common Knowledge UK, he is also a member of East Kilbride Rec Theatre where he recently played the dormouse in their pantomime adaptation of Alice in Wonderland. Wes has steadfastly refused to let his learning disability limit his ambitions and he explains how his self-confidence increased through attending college and being a host city volunteer at the Common Wealth Games in Glasgow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Lynn Murdoch</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-lynn-murdoch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-lynn-murdoch/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LM - Lynn Murdoch
In our continuing series, My Life My Way, Lynn Murdoch talks candidly to Michael McEwan about life with Cerebral Palsy. Lynn attended mainstream schools and tried office work for a while, now living in her own home and working as an activities co-ordinator in a care home, Lynn offers advice to others with disability.
MM Lynn stays in Nelson and she&amp;rsquo;s got Cerebral Palsy and she works in a care home and she is going to be speaking about her journey from school to working life to getting a house of her own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: George Gordon</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-george-gordon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-george-gordon/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GG - George Gordon
Michael McEwan talks to George Gordon, a part time receptionist with the Scottish Consortium for Learning Disability, who has previously worked with Common Knowledge as an interviewer on the Special Olympics and as a support worker. He has also worked on the SCLD, Citizen Leadership Programme. In this episode, he talks about the challenge of attending college while working as a school traffic patroller and his advice on how to deal with bullying and verbal abuse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bobath Scotland and World Cerebral Palsy Day</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bobath-scotland-and-world-cerebral-palsy-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bobath-scotland-and-world-cerebral-palsy-day/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
SF - Stephanie Fraser
Bobath Scotland is the only charity in Scotland dedicated to helping people with cerebral palsy, the most common cause of physical disability. With Cerebral Palsy Month coming up in October and World Cerebral Palsy Day on 7th October, Bobath Scotland Chief Executive Stephanie Fraser, talks to Michael McEwan about Bobath Therapy, the economics of running a charity, fundraising and training programmes for families, classroom assistants and young people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sense Scotland: supporting disabled people and their families</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sense-scotland-supporting-disabled-people-and-their-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sense-scotland-supporting-disabled-people-and-their-families/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GT - Graeme Thomson
GH - Grant Hendry
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland Social Services. In this episode for Iriss.fm, I went out to Sense Scotland at TouchBase in Glasgow where I interviewed a Grant Hendry, one of the support workers at Sense Scotland, but first up let&amp;rsquo;s hear the interview that I did with their Communications Officer at Sense Scotland, Graeme Thomson.
MM First of all, what is Sense Scotland?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Values into Action Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/values-into-action-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/values-into-action-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DR - David Ross
CH - Catherine Hurrell
Values into Action Scotland promotes rights and equality for people with learning disabilities and individuals on the autistic spectrum. In this episode Michael McEwan first talks to David Ross about how his work as a Quality Checker helps people get more choice and control in their lives. Then Catherine Hurrell talks about a project to develop modern apprenticeships for young people on the autistic spectrum or with learning disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2015</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2015/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
MM Learning Disability Week is running from 15th to 21st June. Now why do we have Learning Disability and why is it important? Well it&amp;rsquo;s important to raise the issues of people with learning disabilities, raise issues and make people aware that there are issues, and give them a stronger voice in their community and society, at the end of the day, and hopefully we will break down barriers and give people an even bigger chance with a learning disability or mental health issues for that matter, to try and get into employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PASDA. Supporting families of adults with autism</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pasda-supporting-families-of-adults-with-autism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pasda-supporting-families-of-adults-with-autism/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
DN - Donna Nelson
CP - Cath Purdie
In Edinburgh and the Lothians there are over 7,000 families supporting adults with an autistic spectrum condition. Pasda is a charity that offers support to parents, partners and siblings of adults with ASC. Executive Manager, Donna Nelson, and Cath Purdie, a carer, join Michael McEwan in a Glasgow cafe to explain how Pasda works in partnership with a whole range of organisations to help improve the health and wellbeing of families affected by ASC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dates-n-Mates</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
LI - Liz Irvine
Dates &amp;lsquo;n Mates is a friendship and dating agency for people with learning disabilities. Michael McEwan talked to PR and Marketing Manager, Liz Irvine, just before Valentines Day 2015.
MM For my latest episode of Iriss.fm, I interviewed PR and Marketing Manager for Dates &amp;lsquo;n Mates, Liz Irvine.
MM First of all, Liz, can you tell us about Dates &amp;lsquo;n Mates?
LI Yes, Dates n Mates has been going 8 years now, it&amp;rsquo;s a friendship and dating agency that covers the whole of Scotland, and it&amp;rsquo;s run by and it&amp;rsquo;s for people with learning disabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Young Scotland&#39;s Got Talent</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/young-scotlands-got-talent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/young-scotlands-got-talent/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
ML - Maura Lynch
Young Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Got Talent is an employment campaign for young people with learning difficulties, as well as young people with autism. Campaign organiser, Maura Lynch, explains to Michael McEwan why the campaign is as much about fun as information.
MM First off Moira, what is Young Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Got Talent?
ML Young Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Got Talent is a campaign that has been set up recognising that the number of young people with a learning disability and autism are not getting jobs and are not getting into the workplace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East Project: supported employment</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-east-project-supported-employment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-east-project-supported-employment/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
EH - Emma Hill
MM We are here in the East Project in East Renfrewshire with the Project Coordinator, Emma Hill. So Emma, first tell us a bit about the project.
EH Yes, absolutely - the project is called the East Project - we have just began in East Renfrewshire in about September of this year. It&amp;rsquo;s a supported employment project, so we help individuals with learning disabilities and learning difficulties between the ages of 18-30 to look for employment opportunities - and that can be work experience, right up to paid employment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go4IT digital inclusion service</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/go4it-digital-inclusion-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/go4it-digital-inclusion-service/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DW - Diane Webb
RM - Ross McNicol
DP - Dee Piggott
PH - Pamela Hewison
MD Iriss.fm visited the Glasgow Centre for Inclusive Living which hosts &amp;lsquo;Go4IT&amp;rsquo;, a digital inclusion service for adults with disabilities who are supported by Quarriers. We spoke to Diane Webb, Digital Inclusion Lead at Quarriers about how the Go4IT programme began and the type of courses it provides. Diane received a TalkTalk Digital Hero Award in 2014 for her work with Go4IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCanDoIT, digital literacy training</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ucandoit-digital-literacy-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ucandoit-digital-literacy-training/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JJ - Joyce Jordan
MM I am joined by Joyce Jordan. Joyce is one of the tutors for UCanDoIT. Now first off Joyce, what is UCanDoIT?
JJ Well UCanDoIT is a charity which provides computer and internet training for people in their own homes, and we teach them on a one to one basis. The charity was founded in 1998 and we have a network of tutors around the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving permanence for disabled children</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/achieving-permanence-for-disabled-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/achieving-permanence-for-disabled-children/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LB - Liz Brabender
TB - Tam Baillie
MD On the 10th of October 2014, Iriss.fm attended an event, &amp;lsquo;Achieving permanence for disabled children&amp;rsquo; which was held at the Teacher Building in Glasgow. The event was held to discuss a new piece of research, - achieving permanence for disabled children and young people in foster care and adoption. The research was produced by Vicki Welch, Senior Research Fellow at CELCIS, Kirsten Stalker, Professor of Disability Studies at the University of Strathclyde and Chris Jones, Lecturer at the Child Protection Centre at the University of Edinburgh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Chris White</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-chris-white/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-chris-white/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CW - Chris White
You are listening to My Life My Way on Iriss.fm and we are joined by Chris White today. Now basically Chris was in his 20s, he was doing okay, he was married, he had a good job and a decent social life. Then he started feeling worried and anxious about most things and quickly developed into feeling as though he couldn&amp;rsquo;t cope. He attended a kind of a day centre from 1995 to 1999, and in about 2002, Chris made the decision not to use the day centre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life My Way: Gordon Roy</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-gordon-roy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-life-my-way-gordon-roy/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GR - Gordon Roy
MM When Gordon Roy left school at 17 in the 1980&amp;rsquo;s, he first attended a day centre. He was told he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to work or have a family. He left the day centre and went to college and has held down a steady job for many years. He also has a family. In the first of our new series, My Life My Way, Gordon talks to Michael McEwan about day centres, college and working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking towards better health</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/walking-towards-better-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/walking-towards-better-health/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
EG - Emma Goodlad
So we are here today with Emma Goodlad from the Walking Towards Better Health project from the ALLIANCE Scotland. Now, Emma, can you first tell us what is this project all about?
EG Well, Walking Towards Better Health was set up to really, it&amp;rsquo;s a partnership programme between Paths For All and Health and Social Care ALLIANCE Scotland, and it&amp;rsquo;s really all about trying to encourage people who are living with long term conditions to become more active through walking, because it&amp;rsquo;s the most accessible form of physical activity and it&amp;rsquo;s got so many benefits come from it, so that was really, the whole premise of it was really just to think of a really simple way to try and encourage people living with any long term condition to become more active.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Disability Week 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/learning-disability-week-2014/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JM - Jan Murdoch
MM You are listening to Iriss.fm and we are here with Jan Murdoch, Head of Corporate Affairs at the Scottish Consortium for Learning Disabilities, and Jan is going to be speaking to us about Learning Disability Week. Now before we speak about Learning Disability Week, can you tell us what is Learning Disability Week all about?
JM It&amp;rsquo;s a week to bring attention to the issues that are facing people with disabilities and their families, so it&amp;rsquo;s a change to think about what is happening locally or nationally and make a bit of a noise about it and to hopefully get some attention from people right across Scotland around the issues that are affecting people and their families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dates-n-Mates nightclub for people with learning disabilities</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates-nightclub-for-people-with-learning-disabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dates-n-mates-nightclub-for-people-with-learning-disabilities/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
JP - John Paul
MM We are at the Arches in Glasgow for the &amp;lsquo;Late&amp;rsquo; event, it&amp;rsquo;s Scotland&amp;rsquo;s first fully inclusive club night for people with learning disabilities and one of the Directors is here from Dates-n-Mates, John Paul. Now, John Paul, before you tell us a bit about the campaign, can you first of all tell us a bit about what is Dates-n-Mates?
JP Yes, no bother, Michael.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disability sports in Scotland and the Commonwealth Games 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-sports-in-scotland-and-the-commonwealth-games-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/disability-sports-in-scotland-and-the-commonwealth-games-2014/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
GM - Gavin MacLeod
MM We are here on Iriss.fm, with the Chief Executive of Scottish Disability Sports, Gavin MacLeod. Gavin, so just tell us a bit about Scottish Disability Sports and the work that you do.
GM Thanks Michael, our job is really to create opportunities for people with a disability to participate in sport and then once we have got them involved in sport, is to develop their performance so that they can meet their full potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trend Spotter network</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trend-spotter-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trend-spotter-network/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
SC - Susan Campbell
MM Today we are joined by Susan Campbell, from the Social Care Ideas Factory. First of all before Susan tells us about the project, she is going to tell us a bit about herself.
SC Hi Michael, yes, my name is Susan Campbell and I am a self employed life coach and community worker, but I have been doing bits and pieces of work for the Social Care Ideas Factory on an off for the last 5 years now and this piece of work I am working on just now is called &amp;lsquo;Trendspotters&amp;rsquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s a really exciting piece of work that I am wanting to tell Michael all about today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Able Radio presents... December 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-december-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-december-2013/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
In this episode, guest presenter, Michael McEwan from Able Radio, gives us the latest roundup of news and events for people with disabilities.
Hello and welcome to another programme on Iriss.fm. My name is Michael McEwan. Coming up this month we will tell you about an international day of persons with a disability. We will also tell you a bit about a new initiative run by the Scottish Government, facilitated by the Social Ideas Factory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Able Radio presents- October 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-october-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-october-2013/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
In this episode, guest presenter, Michael McEwan from Able Radio, gives us the latest roundup of news and events for people with disabilities.
MM Hello, welcome to Iriss.fm and welcome to this podcast. Coming up on this months podcast we will tell you a bit about a few AGM&amp;rsquo;s taking place - Enable Scotland, Downs Syndrome Scotland, and we will tell you a bit about the SCLD, the Scottish Consortium for Learning Disabilities we have news of events taking place later in November.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Able Radio presents - September 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-september-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/able-radio-presents-september-2013/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
In this episode, we are pleased to introduce guest presenter, Michael McEwan, who is a regular broadcaster on Able Radio.
My name is Michael McEwan and you are listening to Iriss.fm. My background is I work on a disability radio station called Able Radio and I do numerous of disability issues in the media. For the next couple of Iriss broadcasts I will be here with news or events coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from a scoping study on disabled children and child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/lessons-from-a-scoping-study-on-disabled-children-and-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/lessons-from-a-scoping-study-on-disabled-children-and-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>KS - Professor Kirsten Stalker
KS I am very pleased to have a chance to tell you about the scoping study that we did around disabled children and child protection. This was the research that I carried out with Dr Pam Green-Lister at Strathclyde University, it was funded by the Sir Harry Stewart Trust and we are really keen that practitioners find out about the research and the findings. The research was an 8 month scoping study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten Citizens: today&#39;s forgotten citizens</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-todays-forgotten-citizens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-todays-forgotten-citizens/</guid>
      <description>TR - Tahira Ramzan
TR Hi my name is Tahira and I&amp;rsquo;m 30 years old. I used to go to Nautical College and I did a development course.
I have 7 sisters, I&amp;rsquo;m the second oldest, I have one brother. I have a learning disability, so does my sister. People don&amp;rsquo;t always understand me, once I was walking down the street and a man started to throw money at me and I got scared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forgotten Citizens: welcome</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/forgotten-citizens-welcome/</guid>
      <description>DK - David Kinloch
DK Hi, my name is David. I am from Stirling.
I would like to welcome you to this Conference. I hope that you enjoy the day, and I hope that you get a lot out of all the things that are happening today.
We are here today to talk about Forgotten Citizens. People that were kept out of society and forgotten about. People that had no rights, people who had no voice, and people who had no choices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
