<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self-directed support on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/self-directed-support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self-directed support on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:01:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/self-directed-support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Support, My Choice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-support-my-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-support-my-choice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DJ - Lucy Mulvagh
DM - Donald McLeod
My Support, My Choice is a research project led jointly by the Health and Social Care Alliance and Self-Directed Support Scotland with the aim of understanding people’s experiences of self-directed support in Scotland. It was funded by the Scottish Government. Between November 2018 and February 2020 over 600 people who received self-directed support or had been assessed in the previous 12 months took part in this research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People&#39;s experiences of self-directed support in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/peoples-experiences-of-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/peoples-experiences-of-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
HT - Hannah Tweed
DT - Dianne Theakstone
Hannah Tweed from the Health and Social Care Alliance, and Dianne Theakstone from Self Directed Support Scotland, spoke to Iriss about the joint research they are undertaking on user experiences of Self-directed Support in Scotland. This Scottish Government funded research intends to encourage and develop policy and best practice across the social care landscape.
MD Thanks so much Hannah and Dianne for coming in to speak to us today about user experiences of Self-directed Support in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support: a radical policy?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-a-radical-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-a-radical-policy/</guid>
      <description>SM - Stuart Muirhead
CP - Charlotte Pearson
NW - Nick Watson
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On the 21st of February 2019 Dr Charlotte Pearson and Professor Nick Watson spoke to Stuart Muirhead from Iriss about their research on Self-Directed Support in Scotland and whether it&amp;rsquo;s brought about the transformational change it set out to achieve.
SM Hello and welcome to our latest Iriss fm episode. My name is Stuart Muirhead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support survey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-survey/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CM - Cathy McGregor
LG - Lorraine Gillies
On the 21st of February 2017, Iriss.fm spoke to Cathy McGregor and Lorraine Gillies from Audit Scotland about the National Self-Directed Support survey that has recently been circulated. Audit Scotland are keen to get as many responses as possible before the 27th of February; stories positive or negative of people&amp;rsquo;s experiences of Self-Directed Support or experiences of supporting someone to use Self-Directed Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Chose to Climb!</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/we-chose-to-climb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/we-chose-to-climb/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CB - Charlie Barker
MD We Chose to Climb was a three-day event or &amp;lsquo;climb&amp;rsquo; that was held over 16-18th March at the Arches in Glasgow. It was an event that brought together those interested in discussing and exploring the principles of self-directed support. Iriss.fm spoke to Charlie Barker of Social Care Ideas Factory - she tells us more about it.
MD Charlie, just tell me, you are the brain behind this event - what&amp;rsquo;s it all about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPAEN and self directed support</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/spaen-and-self-directed-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/spaen-and-self-directed-support/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
CM - Colin Millar
MM We are joined by Colin Millar, now Colin Millar is the Chief Executive of the Scottish Personal Assistant Employment Network, wow, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a mouthful. Colin and his team deal with Self Directed Support. So first off, can you tell us a bit about Self Directed Support?
CM Sure, Self Directed Support is the name that&amp;rsquo;s been given to a national strategy, so in November 2010, the Scottish Government started talking about folk having more choice and control and freedom over how their support needs are met, and the Self Directed Support strategy, aims to encourage folk to take a lot more control and have a lot more say over how they meet those needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilotlight: self-directed support for those with mental health problems</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pilotlight-self-directed-support-for-those-with-mental-health-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pilotlight-self-directed-support-for-those-with-mental-health-problems/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KD - Kate Dowling
JM - Judith Midgeley
JL - Joyce Lorimer
AI - Ailsa Innes
CW - Catriona Watson
TG - Tracey Grant
MD In this episode we hear more about the first Pilotlight Pathway in Moray Council. Kate Dowling and Judith Midgeley, Iriss associates in Pilotlight, give us an overview of the Pilotlight project and the first Pilotlight Pathway in Moray.
KD Social Care Self Directed Support Scotland Act 2013 will be enacted on the 1st of April 2014 and preparations for implementation are well underway across Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support is just the same as an outcomes focused approach?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-is-just-the-same-as-an-outcomes-focused-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-is-just-the-same-as-an-outcomes-focused-approach/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
NB - Nikki Bruce
AC - Anne Connor
JM - Judith Midgley
YW - Yvonne Stewart
CM - Colin Millar
CS - Caroline Sturgeon
JF - June Findlater
MD The first in a series of planned Iriss discussions took place on 20th June 2013 on the topic self-directed support. We had seven people from various organisations involved including Nikki Bruce, Head of Personalisation at Enable Scotland, Anne Connor, Chief Executive at Outside the Box, Judith Midgley, Iriss Associate on the Pilotlight project, Yvonne Stewart, SDS Project Manager at Alzheimer Scotland, Colin Millar, Chief Executive at Scottish Personal Assistant Employers&#39; Network (SPAEN), Caroline Sturgeon, Workforce Development Advisor at SSSC and finally June Findlater, Fieldwork Manager, Adult and Older People Services at South Lanarkshire Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A collaborative consultation on the draft statutory guidance for self-directed support in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-collaborative-consultation-on-the-draft-statutory-guidance-for-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-collaborative-consultation-on-the-draft-statutory-guidance-for-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KF - Kate Fearnley
DM - Donald Macaskill
RC - Roy Campbell
SR - Scott Reid
DMD - Donna McDowell
MH - Mark Paul Howard
KD - Kate Dowling
YM - Yvonne McLees
LM - Lesley McLaren
MD A consultation event on the draft statutory guidance for Self-Directed Support in Scotland was held on 6th June 2013 at the Carnegie Conference Centre in Dunfermline. It brought together providers of services and users and carers to discuss the various parts of the guidance and give their views on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the first steps with self-directed support</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/taking-the-first-steps-wth-self-directed-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/taking-the-first-steps-wth-self-directed-support/</guid>
      <description>KE - Keith Etherington
BA - Bill Alexander
KE Taking The First Steps started from the idea that there had been relatively little work done in Scotland with children, young people and families, as well as with local authorities and provider organisations, so we were trying to work out ways that people could be involved in directing their own support. And Taking the First Steps was designed to help people go through the process of Self Direct Support in a way that was safe and not risky for anyone, for people themselves, for families and for local authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self directed support: North Lanarkshire demonstrator project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-north-lanarkshire-demonstrator-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-north-lanarkshire-demonstrator-project/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
CO - Carron O&amp;rsquo;Byrne
MD - Morag Dendy
GK - Gerry Kelly
Interviewees: Carron O&amp;rsquo;Byrne and Morag Dendy, North Lanarkshire Council and Gerry Kelly, In Control
MD We&amp;rsquo;ve really tried to put families at the centre and give people much more choice and control over the lives they want to live and the supports that they put around them, not necessarily traditional services within that, and helping people understand the individual budget that&amp;rsquo;s available to them makes such a big difference, but we are also clear that what works in adults in working out what budget is right, isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily the same as what works for children and families, so the opportunity to test something out specifically around children and families is really exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
