<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Criminal justice on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/criminal-justice/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Criminal justice on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 04:28:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/criminal-justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth justice through the ages</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/youth-justice-through-the-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 04:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/youth-justice-through-the-ages/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
FD - Fiona Dyer, Interim Director at CYCJ
BA - Bruce Adamson, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Commissioner for Children and Young People
LD - The Right Honourable Lady Dorrian, Lord Justice Clerk
TB - Doctor Tim Bateman, University of Bedfordshire
RM - Rosie Moore, Independent Care Review and co-chair of conference
JF - James Frame, co-chair of the conference
The Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice, CYCJ&amp;rsquo;s, annual conference was held on the 19th and 20th of June 2019 in Stirling, with the theme &amp;lsquo;Youth Justice through the Ages&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restorative justice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/restorative-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/restorative-justice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CW - Ciara Webb
MD Restorative justice is a process of dialogue between two parties. In the context of criminal justice social work this will be a victim or person harmed and an offender, one who has caused harm. Statutory criminal justice social work in Edinburgh is a service aimed to reducing reoffending and protecting the public through evidence based interventions. The development of a restorative justice service for those on statutory orders is a new and progressive approach to tackling reoffending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Between a rock and a hard place</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</guid>
      <description>KM - Kristina Moodie
DN - Debbie Nolan
DA - David
S - Sheila
DU - Duncan
KM Welcome to this special podcast, the Centre for Youth &amp;amp; Criminal Justice are hosting to celebrate the CELCIS 2017 Festival of Residential Childcare. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about how residential childcare workers respond to offending in children&amp;rsquo;s houses. Everyone here, aside from myself and Debbie, works with young people who are looked after, so we really appreciate you all travelling and giving your time to meet with us for this conversation in Glasgow today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secure care in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/secure-care-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/secure-care-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>DN - Debbie Nolan
AG - Alison Gough
S - Sharon
D - Deborah
L - Lesley
DN Thanks a lot to everyone for joining us today. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the perceptions and experiences of secure care with myself. My name is Debbie Nolan, I&amp;rsquo;m Practice Development Advisor at the Centre for Youth &amp;amp; Criminal Justice.
AG Alison Gough, I&amp;rsquo;m the Secure Care National Advisor and I&amp;rsquo;m also based at CYCJ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hate crime: causes, motivations and effective interventions</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hate-crime-causes-motivations-and-effective-interventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hate-crime-causes-motivations-and-effective-interventions/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
RH - Rania Hamad - City of Edinburgh Council
RH First of all, the Scottish Government allotted money for Criminal Justice Social Work to sort of strengthen their community interventions, and Criminal Justice Social Work in Edinburgh decided to use that funding to undertake research into hate crime and the Criminal Justice Social Work response to that and how do we strengthen our interventions when working with offenders and perpetrators - I&amp;rsquo;ll use those terms, they are sometimes a bit value laden but just for ease of reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reforming narratives: is there life after punishment?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-narratives-is-there-life-after-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/reforming-narratives-is-there-life-after-punishment/</guid>
      <description>FM - Fergus McNeill
LA - Louis Abbott
This episode features a recording of a Sutherland Trust Lecture, Reforming Narratives, is there Life after Punishment? Presented by Fergus McNeill, professor of Criminology and Social Work at the University of Glasgow. It was held on the 29th of October 2014, and features songs created by Vox Luminous, which are sung by Louis Abbott.
FM So tonight&amp;rsquo;s lecture is a little bit different, the middle is fairly conventional, in that I will talk to you for about 35 minutes about the subject of Reforming Narratives or Narratives of Reform, I suppose we could call them the narrative reconstruction that people experience as they move away from offending and into different kinds of life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk assessment and risk management in youth justice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/risk-assessment-and-risk-management-in-youth-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/risk-assessment-and-risk-management-in-youth-justice/</guid>
      <description>LJ - Lorraine Johnstone
DO - David Orr
SA - Stuart Allardyce
NV - Nina Vaswan
MM - Mark McSherry
On 9th December 2013, Mark McSherry, Head of Development with the Risk Management Authority, hosted a discussion at the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice about risk assessment and risk management in Youth Justice. Taking part, Lorraine Johnstone, Consultant, Clinical and Forensic Psychologist, David Orr, a Social Worker with Edinburgh Youth Offending Service, currently seconded to the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice, Stuart Allardyce, also a Social Worker and seconded from Barnardo&amp;rsquo;s to the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice, and Nina Vaswani, Research Fellow at the Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media and the criminal courts in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/media-and-the-criminal-courts-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/media-and-the-criminal-courts-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
JD - James Doleman
James Doleman started blogging during the Tommy Sheridan trial in 2006. At a seminar organised by Strathclyde University&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Law, Crime and Justice, James talked about why social media and criminal courts should be seen as an opportunity rather than a problem. The vast majority of court proceedings are not reported at all, and a great many are under-reported. Social media offers us a new set of media tools that can open up justice and enable citizens to take an active role in the world, going to court rooms or local Council meetings and telling people what is happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering desistance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discovering-desistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discovering-desistance/</guid>
      <description>CL - Claire Lightowler
EW - Ewan
B - Beth
A - Archie
EL - Elizabeth
Claire Lightowler (Iriss) hosts a discussion at the second of two workshops held in Glasgow on 16 May 2012 as part of the Desistance Knowledge Exchange
CL Shall we start just going around the table and introduce yourselves a little bit?
EW I am Ewan
B I am Beth
A I am Archie
EL I am Elizabeth</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The rights and status of children of prisoners in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-rights-and-status-of-children-of-prisoners-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-rights-and-status-of-children-of-prisoners-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>NJ - Nico Juetten
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Nico Juetten, recorded 6th January 2012
NJ The role of the (&amp;hellip; unclear) Office is to promote and safeguard the rights of children and young people, with particular regard to the United Nation&amp;rsquo;s Convention on Rights of the Child or UNCRC for short. The UK ratified the UNCRC in 1991 and so committed itself to bring in all laws, policies and practices in line with the Convention, and the Office&amp;rsquo;s remit covers children up to the age of 18 or 21 if they have been in the care system at any point.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>