<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jane Pye on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/jane-pye/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jane Pye on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/jane-pye/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The role of technology in rural social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/role-of-technology-in-rural-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/role-of-technology-in-rural-social-work/</guid>
      <description>Kerry: Welcome to everyone, we are looking at exploring the role of technology in rural social work. So, I’m Kerry Musselbrook; I’m from Iriss and I’m going to be your chair for the session. I’m now delighted to introduce our speaker, Jane Pye. Jane is the senior teaching associate in social work in the department of sociology at Lancaster University. Prior to this role, Jane worked for 12 years in statutory social work and then spent a short period working in a children’s charity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rural social work: what is it and why is it unique?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rural-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 16:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rural-social-work/</guid>
      <description>Video link for the session Slides for the session KM - Kerry Musselbrook
CT - Colin Turbett
JP - Jane Pye
KM Welcome everyone to this, our very first session in our online series about rural social work. Today on Thursday the 10th of December 2020, we start very aptly with the topic; Rural social work: what is it and why is it unique? We&amp;rsquo;re delighted to have so many of you here and I&amp;rsquo;m equally delighted to introduce Colin Turbett and Jane Pye, our two presenters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
