<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Attachment on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/attachment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Attachment on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/attachment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters/</guid>
      <description>HM - Helen Minnis
DW - David Woodier
In the following interview between Professor Helen Minnis, from University of Glasgow, and David Woodier, a teacher, adoptive parent and blogger for Scottish Attachment in Action, Helen speaks about why attachment matters to her. Themes emerging from the interview may well resonate with those living and working with children and young people who have had an adverse start in life.
DW My name is David Woodier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters: in play, SAIA Conference 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-in-play-saia-conference-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-in-play-saia-conference-2014/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
Theraplay is a child and family therapy aimed at enhancing and building attachment, self-esteem and trust in others. In this keynote address to the Scottish Attachment in Action Conference in December 2014, Edwina Grant explains the importance of play - the building block of human development, and explains the relationship between Dyadic Development Psychotherapy and Theraplay.
EG A little bit about me and Dyadic Developmental Practice, because DDP and Theraplay have a great deal in common I think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting the baby IN the bathwater, why attachment matters for all</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/putting-the-baby-in-the-bathwater-why-attachment-matters-for-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/putting-the-baby-in-the-bathwater-why-attachment-matters-for-all/</guid>
      <description>JS - Jonathan Sher
JS I came here from the States, specifically from North Carolina, and I can talk like this all the live long day if it would amuse and please you, but it&amp;rsquo;s not actually how I talk, so I will just sort of go with what I know and lapse into it every once in a while if it would please you. But in North Carolina, I had the pleasure of being Chief Executive of an organisation which was called the North Carolina Child Advocacy Institute, and part of what we did was to create a coalition of organisations called, &amp;lsquo;the Covenant with North Carolina&amp;rsquo;s Children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why attachment matters beyond early years. SAIA Conference 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-beyond-early-years-saia-conference-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/why-attachment-matters-beyond-early-years-saia-conference-2013/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
TB - Tam Baillie
JF - Judy Furnivall
SW - Sally Wassell
HM - Helen Minnis
ZD - Zachary Duncalf
IR - Ian Reid
IW Scottish Attachment In Action, (SAIA) annual conference was held in Glasgow on 6th December 2013, on the theme of &amp;lsquo;why attachment matters beyond early years&amp;rsquo;. Tam Baillie, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Commissioner for Children and Young People, opened the conference by setting attachment in the context of the United Nations Convention on the rights of the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attachment focused therapy for children and young people</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/attachment-focused-therapy-for-children-and-young-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/attachment-focused-therapy-for-children-and-young-people/</guid>
      <description>EG - Edwina Grant
DH - Dan Hughes
Dan Hughes is an specialist in dyadic developmental psychotherapy, an approach that is gaining momentum in Scotland as an effective intervention for children and young people in residential care, as well as children who are adopted or are in foster care and children have experienced abuse, neglect or trauma in their early years.
Dan is a regular visitor to Scotland and we caught up with him in September 2012 in Glasgow during a four day workshop organised by Scottish Attachment in Action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy and emotional intelligence</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/empathy-and-emotional-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/empathy-and-emotional-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>DH - David Howe
David Howe - Emeritus Professor in the school of Social Work and Psychology at the University of East Anglia - one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading social work academics specialising in adoption, emotional intelligence, empathy attachment theory and child abuse and neglect. On 10th May 2012, he addressed a packed audience of academics, students and practitioners at a meeting of the resiliency, risk and vulnerability research network in the school of education, social work and community education at the University of Dundee.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
