<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ellen Daly on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/ellen-daly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ellen Daly on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/ellen-daly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dundee Early Intervention Team</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-dundee-early-intervention-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-dundee-early-intervention-team/</guid>
      <description>ED - Ellen Daly
F - Natalie, Harriet, Jade, Bianca
M - Brian
The Dundee Early Intervention Team (DEIT) provides early intervention support to families.
The team is a partnership of the four leading children&#39;s charities in Dundee - Aberlour, Children 1st, Action for Children and Barnardo&#39;s Scotland - the team works together with Dundee City Council, NHS Tayside and Dundee Voluntary Action.
Practicing a social pedagogy model, the team work alongside families to build their capacity to tackle challenges and make sustainable change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Child abuse scandals and online discourse</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-abuse-scandals-and-online-discourse/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/child-abuse-scandals-and-online-discourse/</guid>
      <description>ED - Interviewer
DF - Danielle Farrell
On the 15th November 2016 we recorded a discussion for Iriss.fm with Danielle Farrell about her PHD research. Danielle shared with us an overview of the main points of her thesis which was an examination of the 2012 Child Abuse Scandals in the UK. The research focused on the multi-functional nature of on-line discourse surrounding the issue.
DF I carried out my PHD over 4 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: The 10th International Short Break Association conference - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>ED - Ellen Daly
DW - Don Williamson
DW What is ISBA? Right ISBA stands for the International Short Break Association and it&#39;s a worldwide initiative made up of a whole variety of different agencies and organisations who are all providing healthcare and respite services for families who are concerned or affected by disability. It began back in 1995 with a Conference in a place called Thunder Bay in Canada and the event was entitled Rendezvous for Respite and then we managed to bring together 300 people from 13 different countries, possibly the very first time that that&#39;s ever happened that we&#39;ve had such a large gathering of people with that shared sort of common interest in respite and then from there it evolved into a whole series of Conferences which happen every two years and they are hosted by different countries and Scotland this year is hosting the 10th event.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>