<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Carers on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/carers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Carers on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 09:25:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/carers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Foster carer recruitment</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/foster-carer-recruitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 09:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/foster-carer-recruitment/</guid>
      <description>MD Michelle Drumm
DN Dorothy Neriah
Dorothy Neriah is a PhD student at the University of Edinburgh who is conducting research on rethinking how we understand, evaluate and undertake foster carer recruitment. Michelle from Iriss had a conversation with her about how she came to focus on this topic, current practice in foster care recruitment and the benefits of rethinking the approach.
MD I&#39;m here with Dorothy Neriah, who is a PhD student here at the University of Edinburgh, and your focus is foster care and kinship care and at the moment you&#39;re doing a bit of research around rethinking how we understand, evaluate and undertake foster carer recruitment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: The 10th International Short Break Association conference - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-10th-international-short-break-association-conference-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>ED - Ellen Daly
DW - Don Williamson
DW What is ISBA? Right ISBA stands for the International Short Break Association and it&#39;s a worldwide initiative made up of a whole variety of different agencies and organisations who are all providing healthcare and respite services for families who are concerned or affected by disability. It began back in 1995 with a Conference in a place called Thunder Bay in Canada and the event was entitled Rendezvous for Respite and then we managed to bring together 300 people from 13 different countries, possibly the very first time that that&#39;s ever happened that we&#39;ve had such a large gathering of people with that shared sort of common interest in respite and then from there it evolved into a whole series of Conferences which happen every two years and they are hosted by different countries and Scotland this year is hosting the 10th event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: The shifting sector - Amy MacFarlane</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-shifting-sector-amy-macfarlane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-the-shifting-sector-amy-macfarlane/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
AM - Amy McFarlane
DM My pleasure it is now to introduce Amy MacFarlane, who is the Chief Executive and founder of Recreation Respite Canada. As a provider of creative and flexible respite services, Amy will tell us about the latest developments in policy and practice in Canada and how this is changing people&#39;s expectations of where, when and how respite services are delivered. Amy will share her views on the need for traditional services to become more entrepreneurial and collaborative in their approach to service development and what this means in terms of new business skills and tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Anything to declare? - Jaynie Mitchell</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-anything-to-declare-jaynie-mitchell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-anything-to-declare-jaynie-mitchell/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
JM - Jaynie Mitchell
DM The theme of today is to look at ways in which we can enable people to develop policies and practices to maximise opportunities for people to experience real choice and control over their short breaks. Today we are looking at unlocking the potential of family and friends. What are the different ways we can support people to achieve the breaks they want?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Caring in Scotland - Aileen Campbell</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-caring-in-scotland-aileen-campbell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-caring-in-scotland-aileen-campbell/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
AC - Aileen Campbell
DM Now if we are to make progress then it is absolutely critical that our sector has a positive relationship with our Government. Good legislation and policy is key to creating the conditions that are needed that will help us to develop the best provision that we can. I think in Scotland we are really fortunate in that we have a Government and we have a Parliament that goes to great lengths to be as open and as accessible as it can so that people really feel that they have the opportunity to engage directly with the key decisions that will affect their lives and there is a lot happening in Scotland at the moment concerning new Laws that will help to strengthen the support available to unpaid carers and to people that they care for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: ISBA values and themes - Don Williamson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-isba-values-and-themes-don-williamson/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
DN - Don Williamson
DM Well it&#39;s my pleasure to introduce Don Williamson who is the President of the International Short Breaks Association. There must be something about 10. It&#39;s the 10th ISBA and I noticed that Don has been the Shared Care of Scotland for 10 years and he&#39;s done a fantastic job in spearheading the team and many, many hands have been involved in bringing all this together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Welcome - Donald Macleod</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-welcome-donald-macleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-welcome-donald-macleod/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
DM Ceud Mìle Fàilte, a hundred thousand welcomes as we say in Gaelic. To those of you who have come from 17 other nations. Failte gu na h-Alba, welcome to Scotland and to you all Failte gu Dun Eideann, welcome to Edinburgh. Maidin mhaith, good morning. My name is Domhnall Eoin ma&#39;klaud, Donald Ian Macleod and it&#39;s a pleasure to stand here today to welcome you to the 10th International Short Breaks Conference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>