<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning and development on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/learning-and-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning and development on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/learning-and-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge into practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-into-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-into-practice/</guid>
      <description>MM - Michael McEwan
AW - Dr Ann Wales
In this episode, Michael McEwan talks to Dr Ann Wales about translating knowledge into practice. Ann is Programme Director for Knowledge Management with NHS Education Scotland. She explains the relationship between Social Services Knowledge Scotland, known as SSKS, and the Knowledge Network, going on to talk about the Strategy and Action Plan for embedding Knowledge in Practice in Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Services. She highlights three strands of knowledge management: skills for sourcing and sharing evidence, producing actionable knowledge, such as decision aids, and the social use of knowledge, that is tools and techniques for connecting people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Sony Playstation Portable (PsP) for context based learning</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/using-the-sony-playstation-portable-psp-for-context-based-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/using-the-sony-playstation-portable-psp-for-context-based-learning/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
AW - Alistair Welsh
SM - Sandy Marshall
IW First of all, Alistair, we had a plan to create some support materials for people who were preparing to go along to committee meetings.
AW &amp;hellip; we have 2 members of TAG who are part of the committee for Key, and as part of assisting the guys in preparing for and contributing to committee meetings, one of the themes that we had looked at the use of the PSP for, was whether that through the short video segment it can offer, might that be a helpful way of the two members preparing for and contributing on the day of the meeting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little engine that could - ideas into practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-little-engine-that-could-ideas-into-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-little-engine-that-could-ideas-into-practice/</guid>
      <description>KD - Katharine Dill
Dr Katharine Dill, lecturer at Queens University Belfast and founding executive director of PART (Practice and Research Together), spoke at Iriss&amp;rsquo;s 6th annual AGM on the 27th of November 2013. Her presentation was entitled &amp;lsquo;The Little Engine That Could&amp;rsquo;, creating, building and sustaining a Canadian based knowledge exchange programme. In this programme, Dr Katharine Dill speaks about putting ideas into practice and gives an example of implementing system-wide change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little engine that could - implementation science and art</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-little-engine-that-could-implementation-science-and-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-little-engine-that-could-implementation-science-and-art/</guid>
      <description>KD - Katharine Dill
Dr Katharine Dill, lecturer at Queens University Belfast and founding executive director of PART (Practice and Research Together), spoke at Iriss&amp;rsquo;s 6th annual AGM on the 27th of November 2013. Her presentation was entitled &amp;lsquo;The Little Engine That Could&amp;rsquo;, creating, building and sustaining a Canadian based knowledge exchange programme. In this programme, Dr Katharine Dill, talks about the science and the art of implementing evidence informed practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The little engine that could - introduction</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-little-engine-that-could-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-little-engine-that-could-introduction/</guid>
      <description>KD - Katharine Dill
Dr Katharine Dill, Lecturer at Queen&amp;rsquo;s University Belfast and founding Executive Director of PART, (Practice and Research Together) spoke at Iriss&amp;rsquo;s sixth annual AGM on the 27th of November 2013. Her presentation was entitled, &amp;lsquo;The Little Engine That Could&amp;rsquo;, creating, building and sustaining a Canadian based knowledge exchange programme. This programme is known as PART (Practice and Research together). In this introductory episode, she tells us how PART came about, grew and made an impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video enhanced reflective practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/video-enhanced-reflective-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/video-enhanced-reflective-practice/</guid>
      <description>RS - Robin Sen
RS - What we did was Video Enhanced Reflective Practice and I just want to kind of locate that within the wider method of Video Interaction Guidance, which is a method used with parents to improve interaction with children, particularly young children. I want to focus on the process of what we did and how we set up the training and what we did in the training and give you a few examples of what we did, and then we are going to come onto the evaluation of the training and how effective it was, which is my shakiest point - still looking at the data at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social media and social work practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-media-and-social-work-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-media-and-social-work-practice/</guid>
      <description>IW - Ian Watson
DG - Deborah Goodman
KD - Katharine Dill
IW In April 2012 a team from Iriss took part in an international workshop on evidence informed practice in County Cavan, Ireland. Following the workshop I was invited to spend a couple of weeks in Toronto working with PART (Practice and Research Together). PART&amp;rsquo;s mission is to link research to child welfare practice which they do by promoting practice, organisational and systemic change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Café</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-caf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/knowledge-caf/</guid>
      <description>DG - David Gurteen
DG Good morning. We&amp;rsquo;re not only going to talk about Knowledge Cafe, we are actually going to run one and get some experience of what it is all about. But let me start by telling you the story of how I started to run Knowledge Cafes, because Knowledge Cafes have been around for quite a while, probably since back to the early 90&amp;rsquo;s and have taken various sorts of forms and formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovative approaches to creating the learning organisation - Euan Semple</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/innovative-approaches-to-creating-the-learning-organisation-euan-semple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/innovative-approaches-to-creating-the-learning-organisation-euan-semple/</guid>
      <description>ES - Euan Semple
Using social media
ES I grew up in this part of the world and my father was Head of Computer Systems for Strathclyde region, so for a long time I heard all the moans and groans of working in local authorities and all the sort of stuff he had to deal with in the seventies and eighties, combined with his experiences of computer and delivering computing to people.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
