<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neil Mapes on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/neil-mapes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neil Mapes on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/neil-mapes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Adventures with dementia - Neil Mapes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-adventures-with-dementia-neil-mapes/</guid>
      <description>DM - Donald Macleod
NP - Neil Mapes
DM Well it&amp;rsquo;s now my pleasure to introduce Neil Mapes who&amp;rsquo;s the Chief Executive of Dementia Adventure. Now Neil is the founder and co-director of Dementia Adventure, which is an awarding winning community interest company and charity, which specialises in supporting people with dementia and their families, to have adventure experiences. Neil will share his own thoughts about how we traditionally respond to those diagnosed with dementia and the barriers we need to overcome if we are to help those with dementia and their family enjoy their lives to the full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISBA 2016: Back in the driving seat - James McKillop</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-back-in-the-driving-seat-james-mckillop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/isba-2016-back-in-the-driving-seat-james-mckillop/</guid>
      <description>NM - Neil Mapes
JM - James McKillop
NM So we have got the great pleasure in introducing Dr James McKillop MBE. We have had the great pleasure in supporting James for the last 5 years or so and James is a man who likes photography and outdoor activities and is a strong family man as I&amp;rsquo;m sure you will hear but he is also a founding member of the Scottish Dementia Working Group and former Chair and since 1999 has had vascular dementia and has been part of an amazing array of initiatives and projects both Nationally and Internationally.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>