<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jackie Irvine on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/jackie-irvine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jackie Irvine on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 05:05:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/jackie-irvine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Influencing practice: relationships matter</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-practice-relationships-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 05:05:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/influencing-practice-relationships-matter/</guid>
      <description>Shaping our future: relationships matters 31 May 2019.
JI - Jackie Irvine
JI I suppose quickly just to introduce myself, I am actually the past President of SWS as of two weeks ago, so, however, the diary hasn&amp;rsquo;t freed up much. The role in SWS - just to say a wee bit about that - SWS is a membership organisation that is there to encourage the leadership of sw as a profession, and therefore we do work very closely with Iona and her team and we also host the Chief SW Officers meeting which happens every two months where the 32 Chief Social Work Officers across Scotland come together to discuss, clearly the policy issues that Iona has covered, but also to discuss issues that are happening for us in practice, where the challenges are and where some of the pressures are, the implications of a tightening financial climate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed Jackie Irvine</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JI - Jackie Irvine
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Jackie Irvine. Jackie is currently Chief Social Work Officer and Head of Safer and Stronger Communities in the City of Edinburgh Council. Jackie was appointed as the president of Social Work Scotland in May of 2018 and her tenure as President comes to an end in May 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
