<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freshly Squeezed on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/freshly-squeezed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freshly Squeezed on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 08:28:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/freshly-squeezed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Alistair Brown</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-alistair-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 08:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-alistair-brown/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
AB - Alistair Brown
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Alistair Brown, national director of the Scottish Association of Social Work. Alistair grew up in Falkirk and has been practicing in Scotland in statutory roles and as a mental health officer and independent social worker over the last ten years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Peter Macleod</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-peter-macleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 08:48:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-peter-macleod/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PM - Peter MacLeod
Michelle Drumm speaks to Peter MacLeod, Peter is Chief Executive of the Care Inspectorate as of 2018 and has spent over thirty years working in the public sector. He graduated from Robert Gordon University with a degree in Social Sciences and a qualification in Social Work and began a career as a social worker in Glasgow in 1987. In 1996 he joined Renfrewshire Council as an Area Manager responsible for adult, children&#39;s and criminal justice social work and in early 2007 was appointed Head of Children&#39;s Services and Criminal Justice for Social Work and the Community Health Partnership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Viv Clelland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-clelland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-clelland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
VC - Viv Clelland
You&#39;re listening to Iriss.fm Scotland&#39;s Social Services podcast.
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &#39;squeeze&#39; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland, today I&#39;m speaking to Viv Clelland. Viv is a support worker for looked after young people and families in East Ayrshire. She received the untold story award at the Scottish Social Services Awards 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Kathryn Lindsay</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-kathryn-lindsay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 09:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-kathryn-lindsay/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KL - Kathryn Lindsay
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Kathryn Lindsay. Kathryn is the Director of Children, Families &amp;amp; Justice, and Chief Social Work Officer for Angus Council. She is also the President of Social Work Scotland. Since qualifying as a social worker in 2000, Kathryn worked as a practitioner across Angus and Dundee City Council justice services, and in residential services at Rossie Young People&#39;s Trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Lorraine Ward</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lorraine-ward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 04:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lorraine-ward/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LW - Lorraine Ward
An interview with Lorraine Ward, a social worker awarded for Best Practice in Equality &amp;amp; Diversity at the SASW Awards 2019.
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Lorraine Ward. Lorraine is a social worker who has worked with Children and Families social work department in Glasgow for over 25 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed Calum Glasgow</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-calum-glasgow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 07:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-calum-glasgow/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CG - Calum Glasgow
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Calum Glasgow. Calum is currently studying social work at the University of Strathclyde, and received an award for student social worker of the year at the SASW Social Work Awards 2019. His previous social care experience involves working with children and young adults with additional support needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed Jackie Irvine</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JI - Jackie Irvine
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Jackie Irvine. Jackie is currently Chief Social Work Officer and Head of Safer and Stronger Communities in the City of Edinburgh Council. Jackie was appointed as the president of Social Work Scotland in May of 2018 and her tenure as President comes to an end in May 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: David Williams</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-david-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 12:00:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-david-williams/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DW - David Williams
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to David Williams. David qualified as a social worker in 1988 and worked for 2 years in Easterhouse and then for 7 years in Drumchapel as a social worker and senior social worker. He moved to the children&#39;s charity NCH in 1997 as Service Manager to set up and bring in a range of integrated children and family services in the Moray Council area until 2004.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Ben Farrugia</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ben-farrugia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ben-farrugia/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
BF - Ben Farrugia
Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Ben Farrugia, Director of Social Work Scotland. Ben grew up in London and Dorset and studied modern history and political science in Birmingham followed by a Masters in Political Sociology at the London School of Economics and Political Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Lynn Williams</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lynn-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lynn-williams/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LW - Lynn Williams
MD Hello welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influences in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Lynn Williams, an unpaid carer providing practical care and support to her husband Derek. Derek has a high-level spinal injury and other linked complex needs. Lynn is on the board of Engender a National Women&#39;s organisation and on the board of her local carers centre, she also works on a part time basis in Health and Social Care policy with Glasgow Centre for Voluntary services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Jennifer Davidson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jennifer-davidson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jennifer-davidson/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JD - Jennifer Davidson
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &#39;squeeze&#39; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Michelle Drumm interviews Professor Jennifer Davidson, Executive Director of Inspiring Children&#39;s Futures at the University of Strathclyde, which incorporates the Centre for Excellence for Looked After Children in Scotland (CELCIS). Inspiring children&#39;s futures has a vision of ensuring that children and young people facing aversity have what they need to reach their full potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Mairi O&#39;Keefe</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-mairi-okeefe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-mairi-okeefe/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MO - Mairi O&#39;Keefe
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in Social Services in Scotland, today I&#39;m speaking to Mairi O&#39;Keefe. Mairi has been the Chief Executive of Leuchie House, national respite centre, based near North Berwick since 2003. The only facility of its kind in Scotland, Leuchie has specialised in providing short respite breaks for people and their families living with MS, Parkinson&#39;s and other long-term conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Emma Scott</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-emma-scott/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-emma-scott/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
ES - Emma Scott
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I am speaking to Emma Scott. In June of this year Emma won the Bright Spark award at the Scottish Social Services Awards. This award aims to recognise a young person who is excelling in the work they do in the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Ian Welsh</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ian-welsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ian-welsh/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IW - Ian Welsh
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;quot;Freshly Squeezed&amp;quot;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to professor Ian Welsh OBE. Ian was previously Director of UK Services for the Rehab Group, leading charities working in care, supported employment, rehabilitation and training. In his time as Chief Executive and Board Member of Kilmarnock Football Club he led the club through business and footballing success building a number of innovative community programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Trisha Hall</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-trisha-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-trisha-hall/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TH - Trisha Hall
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencer in social services in Scotland. Today, I&#39;m speaking to Trisha Hall, Trisha was born in the Netherlands and has worked with and for Children and Families for over 40 years. Since coming to Britain from the Netherlands in 1987, Trisha has worked in residential child care in West Yorkshire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Donald Macaskill</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-donald-macaskill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-donald-macaskill/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DM - Dr Donald Macaskill
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss Podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Dr Donald Macaskill, Donald has worked for many years in the health and social care sectors across the UK specialising in learning disability and older people&#39;s work. A particular professional focus has been issues related to bereavement, palliative care and individual rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Viv Cree</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
VC - Viv Cree
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today, I&#39;m speaking to Viv Cree who is professor of Social work studies at the University of Edinburgh. Viv worked for 16 years as a professional social worker and community worker in both the statutory and voluntary sectors and is an accredited practice teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Tommy Whitelaw</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-tommy-whitelaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-tommy-whitelaw/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TW - Tommy Whitelaw
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &#39;squeeze&#39; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland.
You&#39;re listening to Iriss.fm Scotland&#39;s Social Services podcast.
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed and Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social service in Scotland, today I&#39;m speaking to Tommy Whitelaw. For 5 years Tommy was a full-time carer for his late mother Joan who had vascular dementia, in 2011 he embarked on a walk around Scotland&#39;s towns and cities to collect hundreds of life story letters detailing the experiences of individuals caring for a loved one living with dementia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Iona Colvin</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-iona-colvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-iona-colvin/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IC - Iona Colvin
Welcome to the first episode in a new series, Freshly Squeezed, which aims to &#39;squeeze&#39; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. We hear how and why they are working in social services, what motivates them, and the people, books and music that inspire them. They also offer some golden nuggets of advice. To kick the series off, Michelle Drumm spoke to Iona Colvin, Chief Social Work Adviser for Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>