<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iain Ferguson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/iain-ferguson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iain Ferguson on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/iain-ferguson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The politics of social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-politics-of-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/the-politics-of-social-work/</guid>
      <description>IF - Iain Ferguson
This is Iriss.fm, internet radio for Scotland Social Services. Ian Ferguson is Professor of Social Work and Social Policy at the University of the West of Scotland. He&amp;rsquo;s widely published and a founder member of SWAN, Social Work Action Network. In this lecture at Glasgow School of Social Work on 18th April 2013 he argues that an understanding of Social Work&amp;rsquo;s political dimension is essential and that failure to recognise this has been harmful both to the Social Work profession and to service users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A bed for the night? Austerity, social work and resistance</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-bed-for-the-night-austerity-social-work-and-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-bed-for-the-night-austerity-social-work-and-resistance/</guid>
      <description>IF - Professor Iain Ferguson
On 27th March 2013, Iain Ferguson, Professor of Social Work and Social Policy at the University of the West of Scotland, gave an inaugural lecture entitled &amp;lsquo;A bed for the night? Austerity, social work and resistance&amp;rsquo;, which challenges the myth of welfare dependency used to justify attacks on some of the poorest sections of the community. He examines the impact of cuts on services on people&amp;rsquo;s lives, including the working poor, and argues that the crisis calls for a different kind of social work, drawing on the radical tradition and rooted in the collective experience of service users.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
