<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michelle Drumm on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/michelle-drumm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michelle Drumm on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 04:41:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/michelle-drumm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Lorraine Ward</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lorraine-ward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 04:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lorraine-ward/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LW - Lorraine Ward
An interview with Lorraine Ward, a social worker awarded for Best Practice in Equality &amp;amp; Diversity at the SASW Awards 2019.
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Lorraine Ward. Lorraine is a social worker who has worked with Children and Families social work department in Glasgow for over 25 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth justice through the ages</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/youth-justice-through-the-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 04:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/youth-justice-through-the-ages/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
FD - Fiona Dyer, Interim Director at CYCJ
BA - Bruce Adamson, Scotland&#39;s Commissioner for Children and Young People
LD - The Right Honourable Lady Dorrian, Lord Justice Clerk
TB - Doctor Tim Bateman, University of Bedfordshire
RM - Rosie Moore, Independent Care Review and co-chair of conference
JF - James Frame, co-chair of the conference
The Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice, CYCJ&#39;s, annual conference was held on the 19th and 20th of June 2019 in Stirling, with the theme &#39;Youth Justice through the Ages&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed Calum Glasgow</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-calum-glasgow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 07:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-calum-glasgow/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CG - Calum Glasgow
MD Hello and welcome to &#39;Freshly Squeezed&#39;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&#39;m speaking to Calum Glasgow. Calum is currently studying social work at the University of Strathclyde, and received an award for student social worker of the year at the SASW Social Work Awards 2019. His previous social care experience involves working with children and young adults with additional support needs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>