<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michelle Drumm on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/michelle-drumm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michelle Drumm on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/hosts/michelle-drumm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alzheimer Scotland: the place of Near Me in our service</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-the-place-of-near-me-in-our-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-the-place-of-near-me-in-our-service/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GF - Gillian Fyfe
MD Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care Programme over the autumn/winter of 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services. Iriss has supported 5 services to participate in a rapid quality improvement cycle to start using Near ME, provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work and has developed a learning network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How care home staff and family carers responded to visiting restrictions</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-care-home-staff-and-family-carers-responded-to-visiting-restrictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-care-home-staff-and-family-carers-responded-to-visiting-restrictions/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JH - Jo Hockley
A study to gauge how lockdown restrictions have affected the families of care home residents, have been published. The research, titled Creative Covid Care, highlights the relationship-based and creative practices used to support communication and connection while visiting restrictions have been in place.
This rapid research project, funded by the Chief Scientists Office at Scottish Government, has been led by the University of Edinburgh with partners from University of Strathclyde, The University of the West of Scotland and Iriss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Support, My Choice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-support-my-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/my-support-my-choice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DJ - Lucy Mulvagh
DM - Donald McLeod
My Support, My Choice is a research project led jointly by the Health and Social Care Alliance and Self-Directed Support Scotland with the aim of understanding people’s experiences of self-directed support in Scotland. It was funded by the Scottish Government. Between November 2018 and February 2020 over 600 people who received self-directed support or had been assessed in the previous 12 months took part in this research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Me in social services: tools and techniques for remote communication</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-tools-and-techniques-for-remote-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 16:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-tools-and-techniques-for-remote-communication/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JC - Janet Crozier
MD Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care (TEC) Programme over Autumn/Winter 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services.
Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid Quality Improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work, and has developed a Learning Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Near Me in social services: an introduction</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 16:01:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/near-me-in-social-services-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LD - Louise Bowen
MD Near Me in Social Services is a project Iriss has been leading in partnership with the NHS Near Me team and the Scottish Government Technology Enabled Care (TEC) Programme over Autumn/Winter 2020/21. The project is producing new evidence around the priorities, enablers and challenges of using video consulting in social services.
Iriss has supported five services to participate in a rapid Quality Improvement cycle to start using Near Me; provided light touch improvement support to organisations that are setting up Near Me independently within their work, and has developed a Learning Network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinections: what community means for those in care homes</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/kinections-what-community-means-for-care-homes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 14:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/kinections-what-community-means-for-care-homes/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
ER - Edel Roddy
AJ - Dr Anna Jack-Waugh
MD Kinections was a three-year collaborative research project working with care homes across East Ayrshire to explore what community means for people who live, work and visit care homes with a particular focus on the experiences of people living with dementia. The project was a My Home Life Scotland initiative, lead by a team of researchers at the University of the West of Scotland and was funded by the Life Changes Trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How &#39;essential visitor&#39; status can support families</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-essential-visitor-status-can-support-families/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 17:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/how-essential-visitor-status-can-support-families/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
Nancy
Margaret
Natasha
JP - Jim Pearson
MD The first findings of a study to gauge how lockdown restrictions have affected the families of care home residents, have been published. The research, titled Creative Covid Care, highlights the relationship-based and creative practices used to support communication and connection while visiting restrictions have been in place. This rapid research project, funded by the Chief Scientists Office at Scottish Government, has been led by the University of Edinburgh with partners from University of Strathclyde, The University of the West of Scotland and Iriss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of lockdown on care home relatives</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/impact-of-lockdown-on-care-home-relatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 17:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/impact-of-lockdown-on-care-home-relatives/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LJ - Lynn Jamieson
SS - Sarah Swift
MD In this episode of Iriss.fm, the first findings of a study to gauge how lockdown restrictions have affected the families of care home residents, are presented. The research, titled, Creative Covid Care, highlights the relationship-based and creative practices used to support communication and connection while visiting restrictions have been in place. This rapid research project, funded by the Chief Scientists Office at Scottish Government, has been led by the University of Edinburgh with partners from University of Strathclyde, The University of the West of Scotland and Iriss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care experience and mental health</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-experience-and-mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 16:30:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-experience-and-mental-health/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TB - Thomas Bartlett
CA - Casey Armstrong
MD The following conversation was recorded by Thomas Bartlett and Casey Armstrong, two care experienced young people who talk openly about the subject of mental health as part of a project titled, &amp;lsquo;Mental health and care experienced children and young people: a partnership for change&amp;rsquo;.
The project seeks to improve understanding and practice in relation to care experienced young people&amp;rsquo;s mental health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Poverty Week 2020</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenge-poverty-week-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 15:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/challenge-poverty-week-2020/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SM - Suzi Murning
MD Challenge Poverty Week was held between 5-11 October this year. The week aims to raise a unified voice against poverty and calls for a more just and equal Scotland. We spoke to Suzi Murning, Campaigns Officer at The Poverty Alliance to find out about the history of Challenge Poverty Week, its purpose and the activities and impact of the campaign for this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MSc in Disaster Interventions and Humanitarian Aid: Lena Dominelli</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/msc-in-disaster-interventions-and-humanitarian-aid-lena-dominelli/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 17:30:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/msc-in-disaster-interventions-and-humanitarian-aid-lena-dominelli/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KM - Kerry Musselbrook
LM - Lena Dominelli
MD Lena Dominelli is Professor of Social Work at the University of Stirling and Chair of the International Association of Schools of Social Work (IASSW) Disaster Intervention, Climate Change and Sustainability Committee. Kerry Musselbrook from Iriss had a conversation with her about the new MSc in Disaster Interventions and Humanitarian Aid at University of Stirling, why this matters, and what it means for social work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trauma-informed practice at Kibble</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-informed-practice-at-kibble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 16:10:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/trauma-informed-practice-at-kibble/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DJ - Dan Johnson
WH - William Howden
MD Kibble is a specialist child and youth care charity and social enterprise that empowers young people through care, education and support. In March of this year we spoke to Dan Johnson, Clinical Director and Forensic Psychologist and William Howden, a children and young people&amp;rsquo;s care worker about the charity&amp;rsquo;s trauma-informed model of care and how it makes a difference to the lives of those they support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clackmannanshire and Stirling HSCP: Covid-19 response</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/clackmannanshire-and-stirling-hscp-covid-19-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 15:14:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/clackmannanshire-and-stirling-hscp-covid-19-response/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CW - Carolyn Wyllie
MD Carolyn Wyllie is Head of Community Health and Care at Clackmannan and Stirling Health and Social Care Partnership. On 18 June, we had a conversation with Carolyn about the partnerships&#39; response to Covid-19 and the interventions put in place to continue care and support in the crisis. This includes detail on the Forth Valley model.
MD So thanks a million for taking the time out to speak to me &amp;lsquo;cause I know you&amp;rsquo;ve got a busy schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Scott: The impact of Covid-19 on disabled people</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bill-scott-the-impact-of-covid-19-on-disabled-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 15:44:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/bill-scott-the-impact-of-covid-19-on-disabled-people/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MM - Michael McEwan
BS - Bill Scott
MD Bill Scott is Director of Policy at Inclusion Scotland, an organisation that works to achieve positive changes to policy and practice, so that we disabled people are fully included throughout all Scottish society as equal citizens. Michael McEwan, spoke to Bill about the results of their Covid-19 evidence survey which reveals the impact of Covid-19 on disabled people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership in a crisis</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-in-a-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 15:11:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/leadership-in-a-crisis/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KM - Kerry Musselbrook
SS - Sue Stockdale
MD Sue Stockdale works with leaders and organisations to help them achieve exceptional performance. She has an in-depth understanding of motivation and leadership, gleaned from her decades of experience in business, adventure and sport. She offers inspirational presentations, leadership development programmes and coaching. She very kindly gave us her time to talk about leadership during the Covid-19 crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celia Sweeney: A carer&#39;s story</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/celia-sweeney-a-carers-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 11:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/celia-sweeney-a-carers-story/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CS - Celia Sweeney
MD Celia Sweeney cares for her son Paul who has one of the rarest brain diseases in the world. She very kindly gave us her time to tell us about her situation during the Covid-19 pandemic - the challenges of caring, as well as the opportunities and what she believes needs to happen post-Covid. Please note that this episode describes some events which listeners may find distressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dunblane Nature Kindergarten: Covid-19 response</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dunblane-nature-kindergarten-covid-19-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 09:38:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/dunblane-nature-kindergarten-covid-19-response/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JH - Jenna Henderson
MD Jenna Henderson, an Early Years Educator at Dunblane Nature kindergarten tells us about the impact of lockdown on their services and how they&amp;rsquo;re maintaining relationships with children and families at this time.
MD Can you just tell me a bit about Dunblane Nature Kindergarten and your role there?
JH Yeah, so obviously I&amp;rsquo;m an early years educator at Dunblane Nature Kindergarten. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked there for just over seven and a half years and I started off as a trainee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting people with disabilities during the Covid-19 crisis</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-people-with-disabilities-during-the-covid-19-crisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 09:12:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/supporting-people-with-disabilities-during-the-covid-19-crisis/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CM - Colin Millar
PR - Pete Richmond
ES - Emma Soanes
MD On this podcast we&amp;rsquo;re going to hear from a number of different disability organisations and we&amp;rsquo;re going to be speaking about how they are coping and dealing with the current crisis. So first up we&amp;rsquo;re going to hear from an organisation called SPAEN. They are the Scottish Personal Employers Network. The network supports people with disabilities and long-term conditions in improving the use of self-directed support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rashielee Care Home: Covid-19 response</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rashielee-care-home-covid-19-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 10:58:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/rashielee-care-home-covid-19-response/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JC - Jennifer Carruthers
MD On 22 April 2020, Michelle from Iriss spoke to Jennifer Carruthers, Deputy Manager at Rashielee Care Home in Erskine. Jennifer tells us how both staff and residents are managing in the current circumstances and how they&amp;rsquo;ve had to change and adapt services to cope in the crisis.
MD Would you mind just starting off by telling me, Little Inch has a number of care homes with Little Inch Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving justice in child contact</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/improving-justice-in-child-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 10:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/improving-justice-in-child-contact/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KT - Kay Tisdall
MS - Marsha Scott
MD Improving justice in child contact is a project funded by the European Union&amp;rsquo;s Rights, Equality and Citizenship Programme (2014-2020) that is exploring child contact decisions in families affected by domestic abuse. Child contact is understood to be the systems and court processes which decide whether and how a child sees a parent that they are not living with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cumbernauld Action for Care of the Elderly: Covid-19 response</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/cumbernauld-action-for-care-of-the-elderly-covid-19-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 08:48:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/cumbernauld-action-for-care-of-the-elderly-covid-19-response/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MR - Margaret Riley
Cumbernauld Action for Care of the Elderly, or CACE, is an organisation that supports improved wellbeing and quality of life for older people in Cumbernauld. We spoke to Margaret Riley, Chief Executive of CACE about how the organisation is managing in the Coronavirus outbreak.
MD Margaret, could you just tell me, how did CACE&amp;hellip;it stands for Cumbernauld Action for Care of the Elderly - how did that come about and what does it do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if my personal assistants need to self-isolate?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-if-all-my-personal-assistants-need-to-self-isolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 16:04:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/what-if-all-my-personal-assistants-need-to-self-isolate/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
OS - Ossie Stuart
Dr Ossie Stuart is an academic, researcher and an independent equalities consultant who has written key works on race, disability and social care. He is a wheelchair user and firmly believes that we are all entitled to fully participate in society and have control over our own destinies: these two ideas have heavily influenced everything he has done and will do in his working life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articulate: adapting to the Coronavirus pandemic</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/articulate-adapting-to-the-coronavirus-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:31:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/articulate-adapting-to-the-coronavirus-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
EC - Eona Craig
On the 27th of March 2020 Iriss spoke to Eona Craig, Chief Executive of Articulate Cultural Trust, about its work to support care experienced young people and how they&amp;rsquo;ve managed to continue to deliver services in the midst of the coronavirus pandemic. Articulate works with often socially isolated care experienced young people in Scotland, challenging loneliness, supporting connectivity and promoting physical and mental wellbeing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language in social work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/language-in-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 13:56:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/language-in-social-work/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SH - Sara Hitchin
MD Is use of language something you carefully consider as a social worker? And is language important to social work practice? Sara Hitchin, Senior Lecturer in Social Work at the University of Stirling certainly thinks so and has written about it for Scottish Organisation for Practice Teaching or ScOPT. Michelle from Iriss went along to University of Stirling to have a conversation with her about the importance of language and its relationship to social work values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adult social care recruitment campaign</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/adult-social-care-recruitment-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 08:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/adult-social-care-recruitment-campaign/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LG - Lorraine Gray
There&amp;rsquo;s More to Care Than Caring is a Scottish government led adult social care recruitment campaign which was launched in January 2020. It aims to encourage people to take up a career in care. Michelle from Iriss had a conversation with Lorraine Gray, Chief Executive of the Scottish Social Services Council about the purpose of the campaign, the importance of adult social care work and how people can get involved in promoting the campaign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Alistair Brown</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-alistair-brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 08:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-alistair-brown/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
AB - Alistair Brown
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Alistair Brown, national director of the Scottish Association of Social Work. Alistair grew up in Falkirk and has been practicing in Scotland in statutory roles and as a mental health officer and independent social worker over the last ten years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get into Care campaign</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/get-into-care-campaign/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 10:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/get-into-care-campaign/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CMG - Corinne Morrison-Gillies
C - Charlene
&amp;lsquo;Get into Care&amp;rsquo; is a recruitment campaign that supports less advantaged young people to work in the care sector. Corinne Morrison-Gillies, Head of HR Operations and People Development at CrossReach, spoke to Iriss about this award-winning programme.
MD Thank you for speaking to us today about the &amp;lsquo;Get into Care&amp;rsquo; campaign. Could you tell me just first off, what is &amp;lsquo;Get into Care&amp;rsquo;?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foster carer recruitment</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/foster-carer-recruitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 09:25:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/foster-carer-recruitment/</guid>
      <description>MD Michelle Drumm
DN Dorothy Neriah
Dorothy Neriah is a PhD student at the University of Edinburgh who is conducting research on rethinking how we understand, evaluate and undertake foster carer recruitment. Michelle from Iriss had a conversation with her about how she came to focus on this topic, current practice in foster care recruitment and the benefits of rethinking the approach.
MD I&amp;rsquo;m here with Dorothy Neriah, who is a PhD student here at the University of Edinburgh, and your focus is foster care and kinship care and at the moment you&amp;rsquo;re doing a bit of research around rethinking how we understand, evaluate and undertake foster carer recruitment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People&#39;s experiences of self-directed support in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/peoples-experiences-of-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/peoples-experiences-of-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
HT - Hannah Tweed
DT - Dianne Theakstone
Hannah Tweed from the Health and Social Care Alliance, and Dianne Theakstone from Self Directed Support Scotland, spoke to Iriss about the joint research they are undertaking on user experiences of Self-directed Support in Scotland. This Scottish Government funded research intends to encourage and develop policy and best practice across the social care landscape.
MD Thanks so much Hannah and Dianne for coming in to speak to us today about user experiences of Self-directed Support in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensemble music project</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ensemble-music-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 09:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/ensemble-music-project/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MT - Michael Timmons
AS - Andrew Sinclair
Ensemble is a Loretto Care project that supports young people out of homelessness through songwriting and music. On the 19th of September Michelle from Iriss travelled to Stirling to speak with Michael Timmons, community engagement lead for the project, and Andrew Sinclair, a participant and volunteer. Ensemble received a different approach award at the Scottish Social Services Awards 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Careers in Care: Social Work</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/careers-in-care-social-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 08:17:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/careers-in-care-social-work/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
RM - Rowena McIntosh
JM - John McVey
JS - John Stewart
On the 16th of September 2019, Iriss attended the launch of the SSSC&amp;rsquo;s Careers in Care website which was created to highlight the wide variety of career opportunities available in the sector. The resource demonstrates how people can build a career working with children and young people in social services and health care settings or as a social worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Careers in Care: Adult social care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/careers-in-care-adult-social-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 08:25:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/careers-in-care-adult-social-care/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
S - Sarah
G - Gillian
D - Deborah
On the 16th of September 2019, Iriss attended the launch of the SSSC&amp;rsquo;s Careers and Care Website which was created to highlight the wide variety of career opportunities available in the sector. The resource demonstrates how people can build a career working with children and young people in social services and health care settings or as a social worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Careers in Care: Residential care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/careers-in-care-residential-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 08:20:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/careers-in-care-residential-care/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
E - Elaine
G - Greg
C - Charlotte
T - Tasha
On 16th September 2019, Iriss attended the launch of the SSSC&amp;rsquo;s Careers in Care website, which was created to highlight the wide variety of career opportunities available in the sector. The resource demonstrates how people can build a career working with children and young people in social services and healthcare settings, or as a social worker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Peter Macleod</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-peter-macleod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 08:48:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-peter-macleod/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PM - Peter MacLeod
Michelle Drumm speaks to Peter MacLeod, Peter is Chief Executive of the Care Inspectorate as of 2018 and has spent over thirty years working in the public sector. He graduated from Robert Gordon University with a degree in Social Sciences and a qualification in Social Work and began a career as a social worker in Glasgow in 1987. In 1996 he joined Renfrewshire Council as an Area Manager responsible for adult, children&amp;rsquo;s and criminal justice social work and in early 2007 was appointed Head of Children&amp;rsquo;s Services and Criminal Justice for Social Work and the Community Health Partnership.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Viv Clelland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-clelland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-clelland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
VC - Viv Clelland
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Services podcast.
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &amp;lsquo;squeeze&amp;rsquo; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland, today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Viv Clelland. Viv is a support worker for looked after young people and families in East Ayrshire. She received the untold story award at the Scottish Social Services Awards 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Kathryn Lindsay</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-kathryn-lindsay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 09:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-kathryn-lindsay/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KL - Kathryn Lindsay
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Kathryn Lindsay. Kathryn is the Director of Children, Families &amp;amp; Justice, and Chief Social Work Officer for Angus Council. She is also the President of Social Work Scotland. Since qualifying as a social worker in 2000, Kathryn worked as a practitioner across Angus and Dundee City Council justice services, and in residential services at Rossie Young People&amp;rsquo;s Trust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Lorraine Ward</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lorraine-ward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 04:41:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lorraine-ward/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LW - Lorraine Ward
An interview with Lorraine Ward, a social worker awarded for Best Practice in Equality &amp;amp; Diversity at the SASW Awards 2019.
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Lorraine Ward. Lorraine is a social worker who has worked with Children and Families social work department in Glasgow for over 25 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youth justice through the ages</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/youth-justice-through-the-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 04:28:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/youth-justice-through-the-ages/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
FD - Fiona Dyer, Interim Director at CYCJ
BA - Bruce Adamson, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Commissioner for Children and Young People
LD - The Right Honourable Lady Dorrian, Lord Justice Clerk
TB - Doctor Tim Bateman, University of Bedfordshire
RM - Rosie Moore, Independent Care Review and co-chair of conference
JF - James Frame, co-chair of the conference
The Centre for Youth and Criminal Justice, CYCJ&amp;rsquo;s, annual conference was held on the 19th and 20th of June 2019 in Stirling, with the theme &amp;lsquo;Youth Justice through the Ages&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed Calum Glasgow</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-calum-glasgow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 07:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-calum-glasgow/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CG - Calum Glasgow
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Calum Glasgow. Calum is currently studying social work at the University of Strathclyde, and received an award for student social worker of the year at the SASW Social Work Awards 2019. His previous social care experience involves working with children and young adults with additional support needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Governance in Social Care</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/research-governance-in-social-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/research-governance-in-social-care/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IM - Irina McLean
Irina McLean, Project Leader with NHS Research Scotland Management Team, is currently leading the development of a Research Governance Framework (RGF) which will meet the needs of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Care Services employers, staff and service users and their families. The Public Bodies (Joint Working) (Scotland) Act 2014 sets the context for the integration of adult health and social care in Scotland. Underpinning the introduction of the Act was a commitment to ensure the consistent provision of quality, sustainable care services for the increasing numbers of people in Scotland who need joined-up support and care.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed Jackie Irvine</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jackie-irvine/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JI - Jackie Irvine
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Jackie Irvine. Jackie is currently Chief Social Work Officer and Head of Safer and Stronger Communities in the City of Edinburgh Council. Jackie was appointed as the president of Social Work Scotland in May of 2018 and her tenure as President comes to an end in May 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: David Williams</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-david-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 12:00:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-david-williams/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DW - David Williams
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;lsquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rsquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to David Williams. David qualified as a social worker in 1988 and worked for 2 years in Easterhouse and then for 7 years in Drumchapel as a social worker and senior social worker. He moved to the children&amp;rsquo;s charity NCH in 1997 as Service Manager to set up and bring in a range of integrated children and family services in the Moray Council area until 2004.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Ben Farrugia</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ben-farrugia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ben-farrugia/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
BF - Ben Farrugia
Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Ben Farrugia, Director of Social Work Scotland. Ben grew up in London and Dorset and studied modern history and political science in Birmingham followed by a Masters in Political Sociology at the London School of Economics and Political Science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generations Working Together</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/generations-working-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/generations-working-together/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KS - Kate Samuels
KM - Keith Mitchell
NS - Natalie Stewart
CC - Charlotte Craig
On 8th February 2019 Michelle from Iriss had a conversation with Kate Samuels from Generations Working Together about the work it does to promote and support intergenerational practice. She also chatted to Keith Mitchell and Natalie Stewart from Glasgow&amp;rsquo;s Golden Generation and Charlotte Craig, from Impact Arts, about their intergenerational work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People-led Policy Panel</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-led-policy-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/people-led-policy-panel/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DH - Deirdre Henderson
DS - Denis Shovlin
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. On 7th February 2019 Deirdre Henderson, People-led Policy Officer at Inclusion Scotland, and Denis Shovlin, a member of the People-led Policy Panel, spoke to Michelle from Iriss about the setup, aims and ambitions of the People-led Policy Panel, a group of people who are working together to reform adult social care in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-production Week 2018</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/co-production-week-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/co-production-week-2018/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SJ - Sam Jordan
K - Kieran
A - Abbie
Co-production Week (#CoProWeekScot) was held from the 19-25 November 2018 and provided an opportunity to learn, discuss and celebrate how co-production puts people and communities at the heart of the support and services they&amp;rsquo;re part of. Michelle from Iriss.fm spoke to Sam Jordan from the Scottish Community Development Centre (SCDC) about what Co-production Week is and some of the activities that took place over the week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Lynn Williams</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lynn-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-lynn-williams/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LW - Lynn Williams
MD Hello welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influences in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Lynn Williams, an unpaid carer providing practical care and support to her husband Derek. Derek has a high-level spinal injury and other linked complex needs. Lynn is on the board of Engender a National Women&amp;rsquo;s organisation and on the board of her local carers centre, she also works on a part time basis in Health and Social Care policy with Glasgow Centre for Voluntary services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Jennifer Davidson</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jennifer-davidson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-jennifer-davidson/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JD - Jennifer Davidson
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &amp;lsquo;squeeze&amp;rsquo; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Michelle Drumm interviews Professor Jennifer Davidson, Executive Director of Inspiring Children&amp;rsquo;s Futures at the University of Strathclyde, which incorporates the Centre for Excellence for Looked After Children in Scotland (CELCIS). Inspiring children&amp;rsquo;s futures has a vision of ensuring that children and young people facing aversity have what they need to reach their full potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Mairi O&#39;Keefe</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-mairi-okeefe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-mairi-okeefe/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MO - Mairi O&amp;rsquo;Keefe
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in Social Services in Scotland, today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Mairi O&amp;rsquo;Keefe. Mairi has been the Chief Executive of Leuchie House, national respite centre, based near North Berwick since 2003. The only facility of its kind in Scotland, Leuchie has specialised in providing short respite breaks for people and their families living with MS, Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s and other long-term conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social pedagogy in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/social-pedagogy-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
MS - Mark Smith
LH - Lotte Harbo
GE - Gabriel Eichsteller
GC - Gemma Campbell
GM - Graham McPheat
MD You&amp;rsquo;re professor of Social Work isn&amp;rsquo;t it up at University of Dundee?
MS Yeah.
MD And from a social work perspective then, what is the significance of social pedagogy really?
MS For me some of the significance is it&amp;rsquo;s link back to some of the earlier ideas of Scottish social work, in particular Kilbrandon&amp;rsquo;s idea of social education and Cole Brandon thought of social education as education in it&amp;rsquo;s widest sense to work with individuals families and communities and if you think of the idea of social pedagogy then that is described as education in it&amp;rsquo;s broadest sense as well so, there are obvious sort of linkages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Emma Scott</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-emma-scott/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-emma-scott/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
ES - Emma Scott
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I am speaking to Emma Scott. In June of this year Emma won the Bright Spark award at the Scottish Social Services Awards. This award aims to recognise a young person who is excelling in the work they do in the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write to Recovery - four years on</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery-four-years-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery-four-years-on/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
EC - Erin Crombie
JM - John McCormack
A - Audrey
D - Dorothea
MD - You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm, Scotland&amp;rsquo;s social services podcast. &amp;ldquo;Write to Recovery&amp;rdquo; is celebrating four years this year. Erin Crombie, Group Work Facilitator, and John McCormack, Project Manager, from the Scottish Recovery Network give an update on the project four years on.
EC The project originally started out as a story-sharing tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Ian Welsh</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ian-welsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-ian-welsh/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IW - Ian Welsh
MD Hello and welcome to &amp;ldquo;Freshly Squeezed&amp;rdquo;, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to professor Ian Welsh OBE. Ian was previously Director of UK Services for the Rehab Group, leading charities working in care, supported employment, rehabilitation and training. In his time as Chief Executive and Board Member of Kilmarnock Football Club he led the club through business and footballing success building a number of innovative community programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Trisha Hall</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-trisha-hall/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-trisha-hall/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TH - Trisha Hall
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencer in social services in Scotland. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Trisha Hall, Trisha was born in the Netherlands and has worked with and for Children and Families for over 40 years. Since coming to Britain from the Netherlands in 1987, Trisha has worked in residential child care in West Yorkshire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Donald Macaskill</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-donald-macaskill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-donald-macaskill/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DM - Dr Donald Macaskill
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss Podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Dr Donald Macaskill, Donald has worked for many years in the health and social care sectors across the UK specialising in learning disability and older people&amp;rsquo;s work. A particular professional focus has been issues related to bereavement, palliative care and individual rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Viv Cree</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-viv-cree/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
VC - Viv Cree
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed, an Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Viv Cree who is professor of Social work studies at the University of Edinburgh. Viv worked for 16 years as a professional social worker and community worker in both the statutory and voluntary sectors and is an accredited practice teacher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welfare advisers in health and social care services</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-advisers-in-health-and-social-care-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/welfare-advisers-in-health-and-social-care-services/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KB - Kate Burton
RS - Roddy Samson
KC - Karen Carrick
WA roundtable discussion on the embedding of welfare advisers in health and social care services, as an effective response to the impact of welfare reform. The discussion involved Kate Burton, Public Health Practitioner at Scottish Public Health Network; Roddy Samson, Welfare Advice Service Facilitator at the Improvement Service; and Karen Carrick, Project Manager at the Improvement Service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Tommy Whitelaw</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-tommy-whitelaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-tommy-whitelaw/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TW - Tommy Whitelaw
Freshly Squeezed is an Iriss podcast which aims to &amp;lsquo;squeeze&amp;rsquo; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland.
You&amp;rsquo;re listening to Iriss.fm Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Social Services podcast.
MD Hello and welcome to Freshly Squeezed and Iriss podcast which aims to squeeze information and inspiration from key influencers in social service in Scotland, today I&amp;rsquo;m speaking to Tommy Whitelaw. For 5 years Tommy was a full-time carer for his late mother Joan who had vascular dementia, in 2011 he embarked on a walk around Scotland&amp;rsquo;s towns and cities to collect hundreds of life story letters detailing the experiences of individuals caring for a loved one living with dementia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshly Squeezed: Iona Colvin</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-iona-colvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jun 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/freshly-squeezed-iona-colvin/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
IC - Iona Colvin
Welcome to the first episode in a new series, Freshly Squeezed, which aims to &amp;lsquo;squeeze&amp;rsquo; information and inspiration from key influencers in social services in Scotland. We hear how and why they are working in social services, what motivates them, and the people, books and music that inspire them. They also offer some golden nuggets of advice. To kick the series off, Michelle Drumm spoke to Iona Colvin, Chief Social Work Adviser for Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PAssport to Independent Living</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passport-to-independent-living/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/passport-to-independent-living/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LS - Lilian Smith
SL - Sharon Ledger
M - Mandy
L - Lizzie
S - Susan
Y - Yvonne
A - Alison
MD 31st of October 2017 marked the launch of PAssport to Independent Living, a published collection of stories written by Personal Assistants about their experiences of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to work as a Personal Assistant in Scotland, and to raise awareness of self-directed support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restorative justice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/restorative-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/restorative-justice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CW - Ciara Webb
MD Restorative justice is a process of dialogue between two parties. In the context of criminal justice social work this will be a victim or person harmed and an offender, one who has caused harm. Statutory criminal justice social work in Edinburgh is a service aimed to reducing reoffending and protecting the public through evidence based interventions. The development of a restorative justice service for those on statutory orders is a new and progressive approach to tackling reoffending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme (AILIP)</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/active-and-independent-living-improvement-programme-ailip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/active-and-independent-living-improvement-programme-ailip/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SM - Sarah Mitchell
SK - Susan Kelso
Sarah Mitchell, programme director for the Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme, and Susan Kelso, AHP Lead for Early Intervention with Scottish Government, spoke to Iriss.fm about the programme and the current Life Curve survey, which they would like AHP&amp;rsquo;s to complete. The Active and Independent Living Improvement Programme, or AILIP, was officially launched on April 26th by Shona Robison, MSP Cabinet Secretary for Health and Sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hate crime: causes, motivations and effective interventions</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hate-crime-causes-motivations-and-effective-interventions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/hate-crime-causes-motivations-and-effective-interventions/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
RH - Rania Hamad - City of Edinburgh Council
RH First of all, the Scottish Government allotted money for Criminal Justice Social Work to sort of strengthen their community interventions, and Criminal Justice Social Work in Edinburgh decided to use that funding to undertake research into hate crime and the Criminal Justice Social Work response to that and how do we strengthen our interventions when working with offenders and perpetrators - I&amp;rsquo;ll use those terms, they are sometimes a bit value laden but just for ease of reference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alzheimer Scotland: Annual Conference and Dementia Awards</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-annual-conference-and-dementia-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/alzheimer-scotland-annual-conference-and-dementia-awards/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KW - Kirsty Wilson
Iriss.fm recently spoke to Kirsty Wilson from Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland about two upcoming events in 2017. Their annual conference and the Dementia awards. She also tells us about some of the exciting work being undertaken by Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland this year.
KW Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Scotland&amp;rsquo;s main aim is to make sure that no one goes through dementia on their own, so that&amp;rsquo;s our main aim in everything that we do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support survey</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-survey/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CM - Cathy McGregor
LG - Lorraine Gillies
On the 21st of February 2017, Iriss.fm spoke to Cathy McGregor and Lorraine Gillies from Audit Scotland about the National Self-Directed Support survey that has recently been circulated. Audit Scotland are keen to get as many responses as possible before the 27th of February; stories positive or negative of people&amp;rsquo;s experiences of Self-Directed Support or experiences of supporting someone to use Self-Directed Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A watershed for social work in Scotland?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-watershed-for-social-work-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-watershed-for-social-work-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JL - Dr John Lincoln
AB - Audrey Burt
LW - Lynn Williams
SL - Sue Lavery
AB - Alan Baird
On 30th November 2016 the Health and Social Care Alliance, in Partnership with a number of Sector Organisations, including Iriss, posted a seminar entitled A Watershed for Social Work in Scotland. The event brought together people to explore the implications of the Audit Scotland Report on Social Work in Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Chose to Climb!</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/we-chose-to-climb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/we-chose-to-climb/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CB - Charlie Barker
MD We Chose to Climb was a three-day event or &amp;lsquo;climb&amp;rsquo; that was held over 16-18th March at the Arches in Glasgow. It was an event that brought together those interested in discussing and exploring the principles of self-directed support. Iriss.fm spoke to Charlie Barker of Social Care Ideas Factory - she tells us more about it.
MD Charlie, just tell me, you are the brain behind this event - what&amp;rsquo;s it all about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go4IT digital inclusion service</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/go4it-digital-inclusion-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/go4it-digital-inclusion-service/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DW - Diane Webb
RM - Ross McNicol
DP - Dee Piggott
PH - Pamela Hewison
MD Iriss.fm visited the Glasgow Centre for Inclusive Living which hosts &amp;lsquo;Go4IT&amp;rsquo;, a digital inclusion service for adults with disabilities who are supported by Quarriers. We spoke to Diane Webb, Digital Inclusion Lead at Quarriers about how the Go4IT programme began and the type of courses it provides. Diane received a TalkTalk Digital Hero Award in 2014 for her work with Go4IT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whose Shoes?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/whose-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/whose-shoes/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GP - Gill Phillips
KH - Ken Howard
DH - Dorothy Hall
MB - Marion Brown
MD In this episode, Michelle Drumm from Iriss has a conversation with Gill Phillips, the creator of Whose Shoes? And Ken Howard, a media ambassador for people with dementia, who were up in Scotland from the 20th to the 24th of October to attend the European Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Conference and to also run Whose Shoes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discover Care Opinion</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discover-care-opinion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/discover-care-opinion/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
JM - James Munro
IO - Irene Oldfather
GA - Gina Alexander
GD - Grant Douglas
RL - Richard Lyall
On the 13th of November, Iriss.fm attended Discover Care Opinion, an event to launch, as well as discussing explore Care Opinion, the sister site to patient Opinion in Scotland. James Munro, Chief Executive of Patient Opinion, gave us the background on the initiative and its aims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving permanence for disabled children</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/achieving-permanence-for-disabled-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/achieving-permanence-for-disabled-children/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LB - Liz Brabender
TB - Tam Baillie
MD On the 10th of October 2014, Iriss.fm attended an event, &amp;lsquo;Achieving permanence for disabled children&amp;rsquo; which was held at the Teacher Building in Glasgow. The event was held to discuss a new piece of research, - achieving permanence for disabled children and young people in foster care and adoption. The research was produced by Vicki Welch, Senior Research Fellow at CELCIS, Kirsten Stalker, Professor of Disability Studies at the University of Strathclyde and Chris Jones, Lecturer at the Child Protection Centre at the University of Edinburgh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Dementia Awareness Month 2014</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/world-dementia-awareness-month-2014/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
YS - Yvonne Stewart
AMMD - Anne Marie MacDonald
AL - Anne Love
RB - Rosalyn Barclay
AMMG - Ann-Marie McGregor
MD September is World Dementia Awareness Month, and to mark it, Iriss.fm met up with the directors of Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training and a group of carers and professionals in the area of dementia care. We firstly spoke to Yvonne Stewart and Anne Marie MacDonald about Dementia Scotland Consultancy and Training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write to recovery</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/write-to-recovery/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LG - Linda Gillard
RR - Robin Ross
AC - Ashley Campbell
JC - Jim Campbell
SN - Sandy Nisbet
SB - Simon Bradstreet
JM - John McCormack
MD Write to Recovery, a website designed to support people affected by mental health problems on their journeys of recovery, was launched on the 11th of June 2014 at the Scottish Storytelling Centre in Edinburgh. The launch forms part of the Scottish Recovery Networks 10-year anniversary celebrations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative care and support: Pitlochry</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/creative-care-and-support-pitlochry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/creative-care-and-support-pitlochry/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
FJ - Fiona Johnstone
RI - Rikke Iversholt
MD On the 29th of April, Iriss.fm spoke to Fiona and Rikke, the project leads on the Creative Care and Support project in Pitlochry, which has been underway since the autumn of 2013. They tell us where the idea for the project originated and what it aimed to do.
FJ I am Fiona Johnstone, I am the Community Engagement Worker for Highland and Perthshire and I am funded through the Reshaping Care for Older People in Polgreen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fit for the Future</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/fit-for-the-future/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
RM - Rhiann McLean
MD Rhiann McLean, Project Lead on the Fit for the Future project, was happy to speak to Iriss.fm about the project and progress to date. She firstly gives an overview of Fit for the Future and explains the main objectives.
RM Fit for the Future is a partnership project between Iriss and Scottish Care that is aiming to support the independent sector to embrace the challenges and opportunities in transforming support for older people, as laid out by the Reshaping Care for Older People Agenda.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mindfulness in practice</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mindfulness-in-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/mindfulness-in-practice/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SG - Sandra Gyalsten
JK - Jane Kellock
MD In this episode, Iriss.fm hears from Sandra Gyalsten, Learning and Development officer at Dumfries and Galloway Council and Jane Kellock, Senior Manager of Children and Early Intervention at West Lothian Council on the subject of mindfulness and its application to Social Services practice. Firstly they gave us some background on their interest in the subject and define what mindfulness is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilotlight: self-directed support for those with mental health problems</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pilotlight-self-directed-support-for-those-with-mental-health-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/pilotlight-self-directed-support-for-those-with-mental-health-problems/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KD - Kate Dowling
JM - Judith Midgeley
JL - Joyce Lorimer
AI - Ailsa Innes
CW - Catriona Watson
TG - Tracey Grant
MD In this episode we hear more about the first Pilotlight Pathway in Moray Council. Kate Dowling and Judith Midgeley, Iriss associates in Pilotlight, give us an overview of the Pilotlight project and the first Pilotlight Pathway in Moray.
KD Social Care Self Directed Support Scotland Act 2013 will be enacted on the 1st of April 2014 and preparations for implementation are well underway across Scotland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working together to safeguard and protect children and young people in sport</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/working-together-to-safeguard-and-protect-children-and-young-people-in-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/working-together-to-safeguard-and-protect-children-and-young-people-in-sport/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SR - Shona Robison
BS - Beth Smith
CB - Campbell Bell
DF - Deborah Fry
Working Together to Safeguard and Protect Children and Young People in Sport conference was held on the 29th of October 2013 at Celtic Park. It was a partnership event of WithScotland and Children 1st. Shona Robison, Minister for Commonwealth Games and Sport was keynote speaker. Michelle Drum from Iriss.fm spoke to her before the event began.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Excellence in Dementia Education Conference</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/promoting-excellence-dementia-education-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/promoting-excellence-dementia-education-conference/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
HS - Henry Simmons
PM - Peter McLaughlin
MR - Mairead Rae
PM - Pamela Mackay
MD The Promoting Excellence in Dementia Education conference was held on the 18th of September 2013 at the Stirling Management Centre. Iriss.fm attended to capture some of the presentations and to get a flavour of the workshops. Henry Simmons, Chief Executive of Alzheimer Scotland, opened the conference and was subject to the Second Dementia Strategy for Scotland, he speaks about achievements in dementia care to date and some of the challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public debate on welfare reform, Learning Disability Week 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/public-debate-on-welfare-reform-learning-disability-week-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/public-debate-on-welfare-reform-learning-disability-week-2013/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PS - Peter Scott
AJ - Alex Johnston
BS - Bill Scott
AM - Andrew McKie
MM - Michael McEwan
MD An Iriss public debate on the subject of welfare reform to mark Learning Disability Week 2013 was held on the 20th of August in Glasgow. Over 50 people attended on the day. The motion for the debate was: Welfare reform will mean that people with learning disabilities are pushed further into poverty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-directed support is just the same as an outcomes focused approach?</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-is-just-the-same-as-an-outcomes-focused-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/self-directed-support-is-just-the-same-as-an-outcomes-focused-approach/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
NB - Nikki Bruce
AC - Anne Connor
JM - Judith Midgley
YW - Yvonne Stewart
CM - Colin Millar
CS - Caroline Sturgeon
JF - June Findlater
MD The first in a series of planned Iriss discussions took place on 20th June 2013 on the topic self-directed support. We had seven people from various organisations involved including Nikki Bruce, Head of Personalisation at Enable Scotland, Anne Connor, Chief Executive at Outside the Box, Judith Midgley, Iriss Associate on the Pilotlight project, Yvonne Stewart, SDS Project Manager at Alzheimer Scotland, Colin Millar, Chief Executive at Scottish Personal Assistant Employers&#39; Network (SPAEN), Caroline Sturgeon, Workforce Development Advisor at SSSC and finally June Findlater, Fieldwork Manager, Adult and Older People Services at South Lanarkshire Council.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A collaborative consultation on the draft statutory guidance for self-directed support in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-collaborative-consultation-on-the-draft-statutory-guidance-for-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/a-collaborative-consultation-on-the-draft-statutory-guidance-for-self-directed-support-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
KF - Kate Fearnley
DM - Donald Macaskill
RC - Roy Campbell
SR - Scott Reid
DMD - Donna McDowell
MH - Mark Paul Howard
KD - Kate Dowling
YM - Yvonne McLees
LM - Lesley McLaren
MD A consultation event on the draft statutory guidance for Self-Directed Support in Scotland was held on 6th June 2013 at the Carnegie Conference Centre in Dunfermline. It brought together providers of services and users and carers to discuss the various parts of the guidance and give their views on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Lives, Real Difference: service user and carer involvement in professional education</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/real-lives-real-difference-service-user-and-carer-involvement-in-professional-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/real-lives-real-difference-service-user-and-carer-involvement-in-professional-education/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
PB - Peter Beresford
JM - James McKillop
TF - Tom Friel
SS - Surinder Kaur Saroya
MM - Mo McPhail
MD The Real Lives, Real Difference conference was held at the University of Stirling on the 4th of June 2013. It focused on service user and care involvement in professional education. The keynote speaker, Peter Beresford from Brunel University and Chair of Shaping our Lives, argues that user and care involvement in professional education is of unprecedented importance and makes possible a transformed approach to occupational roles, education and practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Accolades 2013</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2013/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
AB - Alan Baird
AF - Anna Fowlie
SM - Susan McGregor
MR - Margaret Richmond
MM - Marlene Murray
DW - Diane Wright
CT - Caroline Tumath
AW - Alex Wallace
DM - David McKay
DB - David Bleasdale
MD The Care Accolades is a wonderful opportunity to celebrate the achievements of those involved in Social Care Services across Scotland. The 2013 awards was held on a very sunny, 31st of May at Perth Concert Hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovery 2020: A vision achieved? SRN 5th national gathering</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-2020-a-vision-achieved-srn-5th-national-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/recovery-2020-a-vision-achieved-srn-5th-national-gathering/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
SB - Simon Bradstreet
RP - Rachel Perkins
JM - John McCormack
LC - Louise Christie
JG - Jenny Graydon
ED - Elinor Dowson
SS - Susan Scott
MD On 18th March 2013, Iriss.fm attended the 5th Scottish Recovery Network Gathering on the theme of &amp;lsquo;Recovery 2020: A Vision Achieved?&amp;rsquo; It featured a number of speakers from various mental health disciplines, each of who presented using the very upbeat and visual Pecha Kucha format comprising 20 images and 20 seconds per image to get the point across.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New technologies and child protection</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/new-technologies-and-child-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/new-technologies-and-child-protection/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
CM - Colin McKerracher
BS - Beth Smith
BW - Bill White
KS - Kelly Stone
IW - Ian Watson
PR - Pauline Rattray
KL - Katrina Laing
SK - Stewart Kerr
MD On the 1st of March 2013, Iriss.fm attended the New Technologies and Child Protection Conference, which was held at the Scottish Police College in Tulliallan. It was hosted by WithScotland in partnership with the Criminal Justice Social Work Development Centre and the Youth Justice National Development Team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At Home Abroad exhibition</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/at-home-abroad-exhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/at-home-abroad-exhibition/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
DS - Daniele Sime
DS This exhibition is one of a series of events that we are organising for practitioners and general public policymakers, through a knowledge exchange programme of activities funded by the Economic and Social Research Council. The exhibition is an interactive, very visual child centred model of thinking about a topic which is often quite controversial and a lot of people will have different opinions on, bringing together people who are migrants, non-migrants, people who have positive or less positive views on migration, perhaps challenging stereo types that people might have about what migrants are like and what experiences of migration are, what are peoples reasons for migrating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SASW MHO of the Year Award: Liz Snodgrass</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sasw-mho-of-the-year-award-liz-snodgrass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sasw-mho-of-the-year-award-liz-snodgrass/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
LS - Liz Snodgrass
MD Liz Snodgrass from Renfrewshire Council became the first winner of the Scottish Association of Social Works&#39; Mental Health Officer of the Year Award in memory of Wilma MacDonald, a highly respected Mental Health Officer from the east end of Glasgow who died in 2009.
On 2nd November 2012, Liz agreed to speak to Iriss.fm about the significance of winning the award and was also willing to answer some other questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting people through partnerships: WithScotland Conference 2012</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/protecting-people-through-partnerships-withscotland-conference-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/protecting-people-through-partnerships-withscotland-conference-2012/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
TW - Tom Wood
BS - Beth Smith
JB - Joy Barlow
BD - Brigid Daniel
Iriss.fm had the pleasure of attending the first WithScotland conference which was held at Stirling Management Centre on 25th October. Formerly the Scottish Childcare and Protection Network and the Multi-Agency Resource Service, respectively known as SCCPN and MARS - both organisations joined forces to become WithScotland in the summer of 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care Accolades 2012</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-accolades-2012/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GC - Gary Coutts
LC - Lisa Curtis
TL - Trisha Lowe
DF - Doug Fairweather
MO - Maureen O&amp;rsquo;Neill
MM - Maria McKay
MB - Mhairi Buttle
AR - Ashleigh Ryan
KM - Kenneth McGowan
KMA - Karen Maley
KS - Kirsty Soutar
GM - Grace McVeigh
H - Heather
DJ - David Jarrold
NH - Nigel Henderson
JC - Jane Cumming
LF - Leah Ford</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Care and permanence planning for looked after children in Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-and-permanence-planning-for-looked-after-children-in-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/care-and-permanence-planning-for-looked-after-children-in-scotland/</guid>
      <description>MD - Michelle Drumm
GH - Gillian Henderson
MS - Michael Schaffer
Child care and protection research collection. Talk by Gillian Henderson and Michael Schaffer, recorded on 16th January 2012.
MS I&amp;rsquo;m Michael Schaffer and I am Head of Practice &amp;amp; Policy within SCRA.
GH I&amp;rsquo;m Gillian Henderson and I am the Information Research Manager within SCRA and I did this research with my colleagues Lucy Hanson and India Whitehead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
