<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bill Alexander on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/bill-alexander/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bill Alexander on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/speakers/bill-alexander/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the first steps with self-directed support</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/taking-the-first-steps-wth-self-directed-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/taking-the-first-steps-wth-self-directed-support/</guid>
      <description>KE - Keith Etherington
BA - Bill Alexander
KE Taking The First Steps started from the idea that there had been relatively little work done in Scotland with children, young people and families, as well as with local authorities and provider organisations, so we were trying to work out ways that people could be involved in directing their own support. And Taking the First Steps was designed to help people go through the process of Self Direct Support in a way that was safe and not risky for anyone, for people themselves, for families and for local authorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting It Right for Every Child: promoting effective change</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/getting-it-right-for-every-child-promoting-effective-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2008 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/getting-it-right-for-every-child-promoting-effective-change/</guid>
      <description>BA - Bill Alexander
BA We see it everywhere. It&#39;s all over this conference. I&#39;ve heard it mentioned many times today.
But what is it?
It&#39;s simple. &#39;Getting it Right for Every Child&#39; is transformational change in the assessment, planning and delivery of services to Scotland&#39;s children and families, probably unparalleled since the introduction of the Children&#39;s Hearings System and care planning processes, thirty years ago.
It&#39;s a set of principles .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>