<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Careers in social services on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</title>
    <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/careers-in-social-services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Careers in social services on Transcripts of Iriss.fm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/categories/careers-in-social-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Careers in social services: the role of Disclosure Scotland</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/role-of-disclosure-scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/role-of-disclosure-scotland/</guid>
      <description>Michelle: Today I am speaking to Andrew Morrall, Customer Engagement Manager in the Customer Engagement team at Disclosure Scotland and the subject of today’s discussion is careers and social services.
Welcome Andrew.
Andrew: Hi, good afternoon lovely to be here.
Michelle: Firstly, can I just ask you what the role of Disclosure Scotland is, and how does it relate to careers in social services?
Andrew: Disclosure Scotland was established in 2002 and the role of Disclosure Scotland is to provide criminal history information to employers to help them make recruitment decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Careers in social services: opportunities and employability</title>
      <link>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sssc-careers-opportunities-and-emplyability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://transcripts.podcast.iriss.org.uk/transcript/sssc-careers-opportunities-and-emplyability/</guid>
      <description>INT: The social services sector is growing and this means there are opportunities for people looking for a new career. Whether that’s changing jobs, or people who are just starting out. So what are these opportunities and what role can employment support workers have in helping this important workforce to grow sustainably?
We speak to Kerry Cannon, learning and development adviser at the Scottish Social Services Council and Susie Ferguson, partnership manager at the Department of Work and Pensions, about current recruitment opportunities and the important role employability organisations can have in supporting these.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
